<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="783" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">LAWS <lb/>OF <lb/>THE THIRD LEGISLATURE <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS</head>
<byline>VOLUME III.&#8212;PART III.</byline>
<byline>PUBLISHED BY AUTHORITY.</byline>
<byline>AUSTIN. 1850</byline>
<pb n="784" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" />
<byline>*<sub>*</sub>* For more convenient reference, the laws contained herein are severally designated by chapters and numbers in regular series. The laws of the first Legislature are considered as being embraced in volume I, those of the second in volume II, and those of the present in volume III&#8212;part III.</byline>
<byline>*<sub>*</sub>* The laws of the regular session of the third Legislature, heretofore published, are divided into two parts&#8212;the first em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bracing the general and the second the special laws. Those of the extra or second session contained herein, are therefore published as Part III of volume III.</byline>
<byline>*<sub>*</sub>* Those laws signed by the Governor, are designated by the word Approved&#8212;and those not signed by him, are said to be Passed.</byline>
<pb n="785" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" /><fw type="header" place="top">Lows, Orders and Coutracts</fw>
<head type="sub">VOLUME III&#8212;PART III. GENERAL AND SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the second Section of an Act to define the Time of holding the Courts in the several Judicial Districts, approved February 29th, 1848.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the second section of said act shall be and is hereby so amended that it shall hereafter read as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>That the district courts in the third judicial district, shall com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mence and be holden as follows:</p>
<p>In the county of Washington, on the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session three weeks;</p>
<p>In the county of Burleson, on the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week;</p>
<p>In the county of Milam, on the first Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week;</p>
<p>In the county of Bell, on the second Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week;</p>
<p>In the county of McLellan, on the third Mondays after the <pb n="786" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Falls, on the fourth Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week;</p>
<p>In the county of Limestone, on the fifth Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Le&#243;n, on the sixth Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week;</p>
<p>In the county of Robertson, on the seventh Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week;</p>
<p>In the county of Brazos, on the eighth Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That all laws and parts of laws contrary to the provisions of this act be, and the same are hereby, repealed; and that this act take effect and be in force from and after the 25th day of November, A. D. 1850.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 23, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>vhbh vjb</salute>
</opener>
<p>An Act making an Appropriation for the Payment of outstand<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing Liabilities of the Mission of Maj. R. S. Neighbors, to organ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ize the Counties of Presidio, El Paso, Worth and Santa Fe.</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of twelve hundred and fifty-six fifty-one hundredths dollars, be, and the same is hereby appropriated, to reimburse Maj. R. S. Neighbors, for expenditures of mission to organize the counties of Presidio, El Paso, Worth and Santa Fe; and the Comptroller is hereby authorized and required to draw his warrant on the Treasury in favor of Maj. Neighbors for the above amount.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 28, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="787" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation of Money to build a Fire-proof Land Office.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of ten thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated out of any money which may come into the Treasury, by the sale of the lots belonging to the State in the City of Austin, to pay for build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing a Fire-proof Land Office, at the seat of government in this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the amount hereby appropriated, shall be under the control of the Commissioner of the General Land Office, who shall contract for the erection of said building, and see that his said contract is fully complied with, the same being made with a view to convenience, durability and safety. The said building shall be constructed in accordance with such plan as the Commissioner may adopt, and the Commissioner shall be held responsible for the proper application and disbursement of the money appropriated by this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the said building contemplated by this act shall be of durable stone, with a fire-proof roof, and shall in every re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spect be made secure from destruction by fire, as far as practicable.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That before letting out the said contract, the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner shall advertise for proposals, at least sixty days; and shall on a given day examine said bids, and let the contract out to the lowest responsible bidder; and he shall require said contractor to enter into bond with three or more responsible securities, in dou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ble the amount of the whole cost of the building, for the faithful performance of said contract.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the Commissioner of the Land Office, be and he is hereby authorized to use any note, or notes that may be hereafter given, for the purchase of public lots in the City of Austin, in pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing for the building herein contemplated; provided said notes can be used at par.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the ground whereon the said building shall be erected, shall be selected on any of the public lot, or lots of the State, that may be selected by the Commissioner of the Land Office, Governor and Secretary of State; or any two of them may select; and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="788" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to define the Time of holding the Courts in the Third Ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicial District, for the Fall Term, 1850.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That a district court shall be held in each county in the third judicial district of the State of Texas, hereafter named, and such courts shall commence on the days and may continue for the time herein specified.</p>
<p>In the county of Brazos, on the first Monday in September, A. D. 1850, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Leon, on the second Monday in September, A. D. 1850, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Limestone, on the third Holiday in September, A. D. 1850, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Robertson, on the fourth Monday in September, A. D. 1850, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Milam, on the fifth Monday in September, A. D. 1850, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Burleson, on the first Monday in October, A. D. 1850, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Washington, on the sixth Monday after the fourth Monday in September, A. D. 1850, and may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all writs and process of every kind that have been, or may hereafter be issued from any of the district courts of the third judicial district, shall be considered as returnable, and shall be returned to the terms as established by this act; and all such writs and process shall have the same force and effect, as if they had originally been issued so returnable.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all acts and parts of acts conflicting herewith, so far as the same respects holding the fall term, 1850, of the courts of the third judicial district, be, and the same are hereby repealed; and that this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its prssage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="789" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the Relief of the Heirs of Louis P. Cooke.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the provisions of the second section of an act approved 4th of May, 1846, entitled an act for the relief of any person who may have purchased lots in the City of Austin, and out lots upon the tract adjoining, be, and the same are hereby extended to the heirs of Louis P. Cooke, so that any money he may have paid upon lots heretofore forfeited, may be transferred to the payment of any money now due, or to become due, the State of Texas, by the legal representative of said Cooke, as payment on any Austin City lot or lots.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this resolution take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 3, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an Appropriation for the per diem Pay and Mile<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age of the Members and Officers of the Legislature, at the extra Session, convened the 12th of August, 1850.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of fifteen thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated for the per diem pay and mileage of the members, and per diem pay of the officers of the two Houses, it the same per diem pay as the officers and members received at the first session of the third Legislature, for this extra session of the Legislature, convened by proclamation of the Governor, at the City of Austin on the 12th day of August, 1850; and that the cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate of the Secretary of the Senate and of the Chief Clerk of the House, shall be authority for the Comptroller to draw on the Treasury, for the several amounts that the officers and members are respectively entitled to; and that this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 3, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="790" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorise the Sale of Austin City Lots and reserved Tract adjoining.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller of Public Accounts be and he is hereby authorized and required to cause the reserved tract of land adjoining the City of Austin, and belonging to the State, to be laid off in lots of convenient size, and after giving at least ninety days previous notice of the time, place and terms of sale, by weekly advertisements until the day of sale, in the newspapers published in said city, and in three other newspapers published in the State, to offer for sale at public auction, to the highest bidder, at the Comptroller&#8217;s office in Austin, said lots so laid off, together with the unsold forfeited lots in said city, except lot No. 4, in block 98, belonging to James O. Rice, and such of the reserved lots therein, as he may think it expedient to sell, not exceeding half of said lots and tract adjoining, upon the following terms, to wit: one-third of the purchase money to be paid in cash, at the time of sale, and the balance in two equal semi-annual instalments; the first to be paid in six months, and the second in twelve months from the day of sale; the postponed payments to be Secured by bonds with approved security, made payable to the Comptroller, whose duty it shall be to pay into the Treasury of the State all the money arising from such sales, after deducting enough to defray the necessary ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penses thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The Comptroller may adjourn the sale from clay to day for six days, or discontinue the sale, when he shall believe the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terest of the State may require it; provided that no other post<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ponement shall be made for a shorter time than sixty days; and the Comtproller shall cause weekly notice to be given in the news<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />papers printed at Austin during the time of such postponement, of the time, place and terms of the resumed sale.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The Comptroller shall deliver to the purchaser a cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate describing the property by him purchased, and setting forth the price for which such purchase was made, which certificate shall be sufficient authority for the purchaser to enter upon, hold and occupy the property by him purchased, unless the same shall become forfeited by the non-payment of any of the instal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments as herein provided. Upon the presentment of any certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate with the Comptroller&#8217;s receipt in full thereon, the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner of the General Land Office shall issue a patent to the <pb n="791" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>owners for the lot or tract therein described; provided, that in no case shall a patent issue until full payment is made.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That citizens who have erected houses upon, or fences around the reserved lots, in the City of Austin, shall be and are hereby authorized to remove the same therefrom.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That in the event any purchaser or owner of any lot or tract of land shall fail to pay any of the instalments as the same shall become due, it shall be the duty of the Comptroller to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed forthwith to sell, after giving thirty days notice in some news<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />paper published in the City of Austin, such forfeited lot or tract of land; which sale shall be made on the same terms, and the patent shall issue under the same restrictions, as herein provided in the first instance.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That it any person or persons shall fail to make payment of the several instalments in conformity with this act, as they become due, he or they shall forfeit all such sums as may have been previously paid, and the ground and im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />provements situated thereon shall by such default revert to the State, and the Comptroller shall immediately thereupon proceed to resell said property, as though no such forfeiture had taken place, according to the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The purchaser or owner of lots No. 10, in Division B, and Nos. 23 and 23&#189; in Division A, of the Government tract ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />joining the City of Austin, shall have power to close up the street between the two said divisions, to the extent of said lots lying on both sides of said street; and that this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 3, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to repeal in Part the third and fourth Sections of an Act to incorporate the Town of Jefferson, approved March 20th, 1848.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the third section of the above recited act, be so amended, that if from any cause the election of town officers is not held as provided for in said section, it shall be the duty of the Chief Justice upon the petition of any five persons of said town, <pb n="792" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>to order the said election by giving ten days notice thereof, as pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided in said section, and the officers so elected shall hold their offices twelve months from the date of their election; and should a vacancy occur in said board, by death, resignation or otherwise, such vacancy shall be filled by election ordered by said board, notice being given of said election as before provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the fourth section of the above recited act, be amended and construed as follows: That as soon as the first mayor and aldermen are qualified under the provisions of this act, they shall proceed to lay off the corporate limits of said town, viz: Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mencing at the point where the east boundary line of Allen Ur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quhart&#8217;s survey leaves the Big Cypress Bayou, and running from thence in a north-west course one mile, and from thence on a south-west line to a point where said line may strike the Big Cy<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />press Bayou, thence down said bayou with its meanders to the place of beginning.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. There shall be one mayor, five aldermen, and other offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers chosen by the qualified voters living within the foregoing<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />limits, a majority of whom shall constitute a quorum to do busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness; and in case of the absence of the presiding officers of said board, it shall be the duty of said board to elect one of their num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber to fill said office pro tem.; and should said board from any cause be broken up, so that a quorum could not be had for the transac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of business, then it shall be the duty of the Chief Justice to order an election to fill vacancies in said board.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. All laws and parts of laws conflicting with the provisions of this act, are hereby repealed; and that this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 4, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Sulphur Fork Navigation Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That James W. Jackson, and Such other persons as he may associate with him, and their successors, are hereby consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tuted and incorporated a body corporate and politic, under the name and style of the sulphur Pork Navigation Company; and under that name, shall be capable to contract, to buy, receive, <pb n="793" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and hold all property, real, personal or mixed; may have a com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mon seal, and alter the same at pleasure; may sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, in any court of this State; may pass all needful rules and regulations for the government of said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, not in conflict with the constitution or laws of this State, for the purpose of removing the obstructions in the Sulphur Fork of Red River, and preparing the same for navigation, either by keel or steamboats.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said company when they shall have cleared out and rendered navigable said river, shall have the exclusive priv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ilege of navigating the same for the space of ten years; provided that the exclusive privilege herein granted, shall not extend to that portion of the Sulphur Fork of Red River at present, or which has heretofore, been navigated by steam or keel-boats.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That if said company shall fail, or neglect to make said river navigable, within three years from the passage of this act, for a distance of one hundred miles above the highest point at which it is now, or has heretofore been navigated by steam or keel boats, then the privilege granted in this charter, shall cease and determine.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 4, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act defining the Time for holding an Election for the County Seat of the County of Tarrant, and appointing a Place for hold<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the Courts for said County, until the County Seat is located.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the people of said county open and hold an election for the county seat of said county of Tarrant, on the first Monday in August, 1851, according to the provisions of an act creating the county of Tarrant, approved 20th December, A. D. 1849.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the several courts for said county shall be held at the store house of E. M. Daggete, in the vicinity of Fort Worth, until the election provided for in the <pb n="794" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>first section of this till shall have been holden, and the county seat permanently located.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the territory and citizens west of said county of Tarrant, and east of the Brazos river, be under the jurisdiction and entitled to privileges and immunities of other citizens, until otherwise provided by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 4, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to an Act to perfect the Land Titles in Castro&#8217;s Colony, approved January 22, 1850.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the twelfth section of the above recited act, be so amended as to read as follows, to wit: That the description of the north-eastern and north-western boundary of the colony of H. Castro, shall be the dividing ridge between the waters of the Rio Frio and Medina rivers, and to continue with the ridge to a point bearing North 42 deg. east for a point three miles north from the centre of Dhanis village. Thence south 42 deg. west to said point three miles north from said village. Thence in a direct line to the point of confluence of the Arroyo de Uvalde with the Rio Frio; provided that nothing in this act contained shall affect any location or survey of land heretofore made.</p>
<p>Sec. 2d. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 4, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to repeal an Act to incorporate Rio Grande City, approved January 10th, 1850.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That an act entitled an act to incorporate Rio Grande City be, and the same is hereby, repealed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 4, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="795" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to change the name of certain Persons therein mentioned.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the name of Antoniett D. Scott be, and the same is hereby changed to Antoniett D. Devereux, and that the name of Sidney Way, be changed to Sidney Devereux.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 4, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the qualified Electors of the Town of San Augustine to elect Corporation Officers for the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the qualified electors of the town of San Augustine be and they are hereby authorized to elect, under the regulations prescribed by law, all the corporation officers for said town, on the fourth Saturday in October next, and annually thereafter, accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing to the provisions of the third section of the act to incorporate the town of San Augustine; and, in case no election shall be had<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />at the time specified, then at as early a period thereafter as prac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticable; and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 4, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act legalizing the Organization of the Buffalo Bayou, Brazos and Colorado Rail Road Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the commissioners of said company were under the ne<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessity of using the power of attorney of two of the absent com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners, for the purpose of calling a meeting, of the same, in order to organize said company: and</p>
<p>Whereas, there is a doubt as to the right of said commissioners <pb n="796" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>to act by virtue of a power of attorney under the charter granted to said company, in calling said meeting: therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the organization of the Buffalo Bayou, Brazos and Colorado Rail Road Company, which took place in the city of Boston, in the State of Massachusetts, on the first day of June, 1850, be and is hereby declared legal, and shall have the same force and effect as if organized strictly in conformity with said charter.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 4, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate Central Male and Female Institute in the County of Cass.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Robert Graham, Henry Story, Ebenezer Traylor, James Campbell and Charles Graham be, and they are hereby incorporated a body politic, under the name and style of the Trustees of the Male and Female Institute; capable of suing and being sued, of pleading and being impleaded; of holding property, either real, personal or mixed, of selling and conveying the same at pleasure; of bearing [having] a common seal, and of changing the same at pleasure; and of doing and performing whatever else that may be proper and necessary to be done for the advancement of said institution, not contrary to the constitution and laws of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this charter and privilege shall extend to the said trustees and their successors in office, as long as they confine the benefit of the same to the advancement of the sciences, and the promotion of useful knowledge to [the] rising generation; which institution shall be accessible alike to all, without regard to opinions of religion or politics.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the trustees shall have full power to enact by-laws, rules and regulations for the govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of said academy, as may seem to them necessary for that object.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 4, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="797" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an Act entitled an Act defining the Times of holding the Courts in the Eighth Judicial District of this State, approved February 11, 1850.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the act defining the times of holding the courts in the eighth judicial district of this State, be so amended as to read as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Bowie, on the first Mondays in March and Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember, and may continue one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Titus, on the second Mondays in March and Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember, and may continue one week.</p>
<p>In the, county of Hopkins, on the third Mondays in March and September, and may continue one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Hunt, on the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Collin, on the first Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and continue one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Denton, on the second Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and continue one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Cooke, on the third Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and continue one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Grayson, on the fourth Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and continue one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Fannin, on the fifth Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and continue one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Lamar, on the sixth Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Red River, on the seventh Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue two weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That so much of the act to which this is an amendment be, and the same is hereby repealed; and this act take effect from and after the first day of January, 1851.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 4, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="798" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to confirm certain Land Titles therein named, and to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quire the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue Pat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ents on the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the land titles which have been investigated by the commissioner and recommended favorably, under an act entitled an act to investigate land titles in certain counties therein named, approved February 10th, 1850, be and the same are hereby con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />firmed to the claimants thereof, as set forth in the report of Wil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liam H. Bourland, one of the commissioners, on the 26th day of August, A. D. 1850.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That it shall be lawful for the county surveyor of Webb county, immediately to survey and plat the lands designated in each of said applications, and upon the return of such field notes and plat to the General Land Office, it shall be the duty of the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue patents thereon to the respective claimants.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 4, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an Appropriation for the Construction of the Penitentiary.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That an appropriation of two thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby, appropriated out of any moneys in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the erection and support of the Peni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tentiary; which amount may be drawn on the order of the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners, and applied to the suport of convicts, and furnishing materials for the Penitentiary; and that this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 4, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="799" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the People of Falls County to locate the County Site of said County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall be the duty of the Chief Justice of Falls county, and he is hereby required, to order an election to be held at each of the several precincts in said county, on the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />day in November next, by the qualified electors of said county, for the purpose of selecting a seat of justice for said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That it shall be the duty of said Chief Justice to ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vertise the said election in each election precinct of said county, for ten days next preceding the day thereon fixed for holding such election, specifying, distinctly, in said advertisement or notice, the purpose for which said election is to be held.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the place receiving a majority of all the votes polled, shall be the site of justice for said county of Falls, and shall be called Marlin, until otherwise provided by law; and that all laws and parts of laws conflicting with the terms of this act be and the same are hereby repealed; and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>September 4, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Trinity Plank Road Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Isaac Tousey, Frederick Pomrey and such persons as they may associate with them, are hereby incorporated under the name and style of the Trinity Plank Road Company, and under such name may sue and be sued, and have succession for and dur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the term of twenty years from and after the passage of this act, they may also have a corporate seal, which they may alter at pleasure, and also the right of holding such real and personal property as may be necessary for carrying out the objects of this incorporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of said company within two years after the passage of this act, to erect a suitable plank road from the east-branch of the Trinity <pb n="800" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>river opposite the town of Cincinnati in the direction of Crockett to the high lands bordering on said river bottom; that said road shall be constructed above high water mark and shall not be laid out so as to interfere with the road as now used.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the county court of Walker county, at the request of said company to appoint three commissioners whose duty it shall be to inspect said road; and if they shall find the same completed in accordance with this act and suitable for travelling, they shall give said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany a certificate of the fact; upon the receipt of said certificate the company may erect upon any portion of said road a toll-gate at which they may collect and receive toll at not exceeding the following rates:&#8212;For each road-wagon and four wheel pleasure carriage, sixty cents; every other vehicle fifty cents; for man and horse twenty cents; for single horse ten cents; for footman ten cents; for cattle purchased three cents; for sheep, goats and hogs two cents.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the commissioners appoint<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed under this act shall have their office for the term of one year and until their successors shall be appointed by the court afore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />said, and it shall be their duty at any time when said road shall be out of order and unfit for travel to direct said toll-gate to be thrown open and so to continue until the same shall be put in order by said company.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of said commissioners to inspect said road at least once in each and every year, for which they shall each receive two dollars to be paid by said company.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That if any person travelling on said road shall wilfully go around said toll-gate for the purpose of evading the payment of the toll levied by this act, shall forfeit and pay to the company, five dollars for each and every offence, to be recovered before any justice of the peace in whose jurisdic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion such person may be found. This act to take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 4, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="801" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Angelina Bridge and Turnpike Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That James H. Durst and such persons as he may associate with him, are hereby incorporated under the name and style of the Angelina Bridge and Turnpike Company, and under such name may sue and be sued, and have succession for twenty years from and after the passage of this act. They may also have a corporate seal and also the right of holding such real and per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonal property as may necessary for carrying out the objects of this incorporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That it shall be the duty of said company within three years after the first day of January, 1851, to construct a good and substantial bridge across the river Angelina where the present mail route from Nacogdoches, Crockett and Huntsville, crosses said stream, and construct a good and substantial bridge across the main slough which runs through the river bottom, and shall throw up a turnpike and erect sufficient bridges wherever the same may be necessary, for the river out of the edge of the overflow, and shall make a good and convenient road through said bottom, all to be constructed above high water mark, and it shall be the duty of said company to keep said bridges and roads so constructed in a good state of repair during the aforesaid period of twenty years.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That it shall be the duty of the county court of Nacog<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />doches county at the request of said company to appoint three com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners whose duty it shall be to inspect said bridges and roads, and if said commissioners shall find the same completed in accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance with this act, they shall give said company a certificate of the fact; upon the receipt of said certificate the company may erect upon any portion of said road, or upon any of the bridges, a toll<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gate, at which they may collect and receive toll at not exceeding the following rates.&#8212;For each road wagon and four wheel pleasure carriage, sixty cents; every other vehicle, twenty-five cents; man and horse, ten cents; single horse, five cents; footman, five cents; cattle per head, two cents; sheep, goats and hogs, one cent.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the commisioners appointed under this act shall hold their office for the term of one year and until their successors shall be appointed by the court aforesaid, and it shall be their duty at any time when said road or bridge be out of order and <pb n="802" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>unfit for travel, to direct said toll-gate to be thrown open and so to continue until the said road and bridges shall have been put in order by said company.</p>
<p>Sec 5. That it shall be the duty of said commisioners to inspect said bridges and road at least twice a year, for which they shall each receive two dollars to be paid by said company.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That if any person travelling on said road or crossing on any of said bridges shall wilfully go around said toll-gate for the purpose of evading the payment of the toll levied by this act, shall forfeit and pay to the company five dollars and cost of suit for each and every offence, to be recovered before any justice of the peace in whose jurisdiction such person may be found.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That it shall be the duty of said James H. Durst to notify the chief justice of Nacogdoches county in writing within three months from the passage of this act, that he accepts the same; and in case said Durst fails in giving such notice, it shall then be the duty of said chief justice to assign this charter to some respon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sible person or persons applying for the same, for the purpose of undertaking and carrying out the proposed work.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That this act be in force and take effct from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to prohibit Assessors and Collectors of Taxes from exer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cising official Functions before they are duly qualified.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That hereafter no assessor and collector of taxes shall ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ercise any official function or perform any official act before he shall have been commissioned.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That if after any election for asssesor and collector, it shall appear that the person elected is a defaulter, it shall be the duty of the Secretary of State immediately to notify the chief jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tice of the county in which the election was held, of such default and the amount thereof, who shall forthwith order an election to fill said office, and the said defaulter shall be ineligible at said second election, unless in the meantime he shall have made his settlement with the Comptroller, and produced said Comptroller&#8217;s receipt thereof.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="803" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Colorado Navigation Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Thomas J. Hardeman, John Caldwell, John Duncan, John Rugely, John W. Gordon, John D. Newell, Eli Mercer, C. K. Tate, John E. Miller, John Rabb, Jon W. Dancy, Geo. Hancock, John Craft, and their associates and successors, be, and they are hereby constituted a body corporate and politic, by the name and style of the Colorado Navigation Company, and under that name shall be competent to contract for, buy, and receive all kinds of property that may be necessary for the purpose for which said cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration is created; to make all contracts, and do all things which may be necessary to carry out the successful navigation of the Colo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rado river; to sue and be sued; to have a common seal; to bind themselves with or without seal, and to make their own by-laws, rules and regulations not conflicting with the provisions of this act, or with the constitution and laws of the State; and to hold and own property to any amount not exceeding one hundred thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the capital stock of said company shall consist of subscriptions already made for the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />moval of the obstructions from the Colorado river, and of such sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scriptions as may hereafter be made for that purpose, and of such amounts as may be paid for the purchase of stock certificates, and shall not exceed the sum of one hundred and fifty thousand dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars; that the said stock shall be held in shares of twenty-five dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars; and that any person who is a subscriber at the passage of this act shall have the right to increase his subscription to any amount he may desire, and shall be the holder of a share of said stock for every twenty-five dollars subscribed and paid.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the shareholders shall elect a board of twenty commissioners from among their number as soon after the passage of this act as may be deemed expedient by Thomas J. Hardeman, the present president of the board of river commissioners, for which purpose he may assemble said subscribers at such time and place as he may designate, giving notice thereof by previous publications for one month in two or more newspapers published on the river; and said commissioners shall hold their offices for the term of one year, or until such time as their suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessors may be elected in a manner to be determined by said board of commissioners.</p>
<pb n="804" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That in all elections provided for by this act, or by the by-laws and regulations that may be estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished by the board of commissioners, the subscribers shall have the right to vote in person or by proxy, in such manner as may be designated by the board of commissioners, except in the first election for commissioners, when they shall vote by ballot; and each subscriber shall be entitled to one vote for every share of twenty-five dollars subscribed by him, in the election of commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners, and in all other matters which may come before the whole company for their action.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the hoard of commissioners, within one month after their election as provided in section 3, shall meet at such place as shall be designated by Thos. J. Hardeman, the present president of the board of river commissioners, and elect from their number a president and six directors, who shall compose a board of directors, who shall hold their offices for one year, and until their successors are elected in a manner to be pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided by the board of commissioners; and said president so chosen by the board of directors, shall be president of the hoard of com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the board of commissioners shall meet at such stated times and places as a majority of the same in attendance may designate, and shall have power to pass all by-laws and regulations for the government of the company, and shall have a general superintendence and control of the board of directors; shall fix the salaries which the different officers of the company are to receive; prescribe such rules and regulations, for the government of the board of directors and all other officers of the company, as the board of commissioners may think proper; and shall have power to make all rules and regulations necessary to supply the places of officers who may resign, or die, or fail to attend, or from any other cause not be able to discharge the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spective duties appertaining to their offices; and a majority of said board of commissioners shall constitute a quorum to transact busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the president to attend all the meetings of the board of commissioners, of the board of directors, and to preside over the deliberations of the same; to order call meetings in such manner as the commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners direct; and to perform such other duties as may be pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed for him by the board of commissioners.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the board of directors shall hold their first meeting at such time and place as may be designated by the board of commissioners, and at such times and <pb n="805" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>places thereafter as they may think proper; shall have immediate control and supervision over the work of removing the obstruc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions in said river, and opening the same for navigation, under such rules and regulations as may be prescribed for their govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment by the board of commissioners; and the said board of direc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors shall, at their first meeting, elect a treasurer and secretary, who shall also be secretary for the board of commissioners.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the treasurer to receive all moneys due the company from the secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary, any one of the commissioners, or from the subscribers, and give his receipt for the same, and pay the same out in such man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner as he may by the board of directors be authorised to do; and said treasurer shall give bond, with approved security, in such amount as the board of directors may determine, payable to the president of the Colorado Navigation Company and his successors, conditioned for the faithful performance of all his duties, and the safe keeping of all funds which may be committed to him, which bond shall not be void upon the first recovery, but shall remain in full force until the same be fully exhausted.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the secretary to keep a correct record of the proceedings of the board of directors and of the board of commissioners; he shall enter in a book to be kept by him for that purpose, the names of all the sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribers, the amount subscribed, and the date thereof&#8212;enter first the subscriptions now made, and shall also enter the different pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments that may be made, by whom and when.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That subscriptions and pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments may be made with any one of the commissioners, with the secretary or treasurer; and the board of commissioners shall have full power and authority to make all necessary rules and regula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions for their government in receiving subscriptions.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Be it further enacted, That should a greater amount of money be subscribed than is necessary for the purpose of re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />moving the obstructions in said river, that it shall be the duty of the board of directors to refund such excess as may so remain, to the respective subscribers, in proportion to the amount that may have been paid in by them.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. Be it further enacted, That said company shall have the right to charge and receive tolls on all vessels and freight pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing up and down said river, at a rate to he fixed by the board of commissioners, specifying the amount per ton burthen upon ves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sels, and per barrel or hundred pounds upon freight on board of every such vessel navigating said river, until the full amount ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="806" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>pended in removing the obstructions in said river, together with ten per cent, interest per annum thereon, shall be refunded.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. Be it further enacted, That any county situated on said river shall at any time after the completion of the work of removing the obstructions to the navigation of the same, have the right to pay into the treasury of said company her proportionate share of the whole amount of the sum expended in removing said obstructions and such interest as may have accrued thereon; the said proportion of the expenditure to be paid by such county to be determined by comparing her tax assessment-list with that of other counties situated on said river, and upon paying said amount such county shall have the right to navigate said river free of tolls; and all vessels navigating said river shall be exempted from the payment of tolls upon all freight to such county as may so pay her proportions of said expenditures; and said vessels shall be also entitled to a proportionate reduction of tolls upon her per tonnage burthen.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. Be it further enacted, That the several counties on said river shall have the right at any time to raise a sum of money by taxation or otherwise sufficient to pay off the whole amount of the expenses of removing said obstructions together with the interest thereon; and upon the payment of such sum of money into the treasury of said company or to the president thereof, said river shall be free for the navigation of all vessels, without toll or chage, of any character whatever; provided however that no coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties shall be so taxed except by vote of a majority of the citizens thereof, to obtain which vote the chief justice of any of such coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties may order an election to be holden after ten days notice; and should a majority of the votes of such county vote in the affirma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive, then it shall be competent for the county court of such county to assess such tax.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Cass County Male and Female Academy, in the County of Cass.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That J. D. Crawford, J. Dennard, R. P. Crump, Thomas M. Self, W. M. Freeman, J. G. Eason and N. Trawick, and their <pb n="807" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>associates and successors, are hereby created a body politic and cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate in deed and in law, by the name of the Cass County Male and Female Academy; and by that name, may have perpetual suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cession, and be capable in law of holding by purchase or donation, property both real and personal, in fee for years, so long as they confine their operations to the promotion of education; provided, that the capital stock shall not exceed fifty thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Books shall be opened to receive subscriptions, in sums not less than five dollars, and any person who has heretofore sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed or may hereafter give the above amount, shall be consid<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ered a patron or stockholder of said academy; may have the right to sell or transfer the stock at pleasure, and shall have the privilege of voting in person or by proxy, in all elections necessary for the government of said academy; provided, no one stockholder shall own more than twenty shares, and provided also, that no teacher in said academy shall be a stockholder in the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The stockholders may have the power to disfranchise any of their members, by a vote of two-thirds of them; provided, they pay to such stockholder, the amount of his subscription.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The stockholders shall elect from their number not less than five, nor more than seven trustees, who shall hold their office as such for the term of one year, whose duty it shall be to procure teachers, regulate prices of tuition, and govern generally the oper<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ations of the school; and shall have power to elect from their num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber a president, secretary and treasurer, who shall hold their offices during the time for which the trustees are elected.</p>
<p>Sec. 5 The trustees shall have power to make such by-laws, as they may deem necessary for their own government, and the man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />agement of the school; provided, they do not conflict with the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution and laws of this State; and may alter and amend them at pleasure.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. This act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="808" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution requiring an Increase in the mail Service from Austin to Clarksville.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the contractors on route No. 6287, from Austin by Georgetown to the Falls of Brazos; route No. 6267, from Falls of the Brazos by Chambers&#8217; Creek, Red Oak, Pleasant Run, to Dal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />las; route No. 6260, from Dallas by Cedar Springs and McKinney to Bonham; route No. 6265, from Clarksville by Paris and Honey Grove, be and they are hereby required to convey the mails in two horse coaches.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That our delegates in Congress, be requested to urge upon the Post Office department the necessity of this increase of service, and that the department allow increased pay accordingly; and that the following changes be made: that route No. 6287 shall pass through Georgetown, Nolansvilie and terminate at Waco Village, instead of Falls of the Brazos; and route No. 6267 shall commence at Waco Village instead Falls of Brazos.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an Appropriation to pay Balance due for printing the Laws in the German and Spanish Languages, and for print<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the Report of the Joint Committee, ordered to investigate the Offices of Treasurer and Comptroller.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of eleven hundred and thirty-five dollars and eighty cents be, and the same is hereby appropriated, to pay bal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance due for printing the laws in the German and Spanish langu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ages, and the report of the joint committee to investigate the offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ces of Treasurer and Comptroller; and the Comptroller is hereby authorized and required to order the payment of the same, out of the unexpended balance of appropriation for printing the laws and journals of the regular session of the third Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="809" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to regulate the Shipping and Slaughtering of Cattle.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the captains of steamboats or vessels on which cattle are shipped to leave the State, or the proprietor or proprietors or agents of the same of any slaughtering establishments, shall keep, or cause to be kept, a register-book, in which the marks, brands, and general description of all cattle, of all ages, received on said boats or vessels, or slaughtered at said establishments, shall be registered, together with the names of the person or persons selling them, and the county from which they were driven.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said register on the first day of each month, or as near thereto as possible, shall be presented by said captains or proprietors, to the county clerk of the county where said cattle were shipped or establishments are situated: and said clerk shall keep a register of the same, and the registers shall at all times be open for inspection; and said captains, proprietors or clerks may charge a fee of fifty cents for each and every inspection thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That a non-compliance with, the provisions of this act shall subject said captains, proprietors or clerks to a fine not less than ten dollars nor more than fifty dollars, for each head of cattle shipped or slaughtered, not registered; and said fine with proper proof made shall be recoverable in any court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution Granting Leave of Absence to the State Treasurer.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That James H. Raymond, State Treasurer be, and he is hereby granted leave of absence from the State, for twelve weeks during the year 1851; provided, that nothing herein contained shall release said Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer or his securities from liability on the official bond of said Treasurer, during such absence.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="810" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making Appropriations for Printing the Laws and Jour<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nals of the Extra Session of the Legislature, convened on the 12th Day of August, 1850, and for other Purposes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of twelve hundred dollars be and the same is hereby appropriated to pay for copying and printing the laws and journals of the extra session of the third Legislature, convened on the twelfth day of August, 1850: and the further sum of two hundred and fifty dollars, or as much thereof as may be necessary, is hereby appropriated to pay for distributing the same, which shall be done by mail.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the following sums be also appropriated for the purposes mentioned, to wit:</p>
<p>For the purchase of blank books, in order to comply with the fourth section of the direct-tax law in relation to the abstract of landtitles to be furnished the Comptroller&#39;s office, one hundred and ninety-eight dollars;</p>
<p>For the hire of two clerks six months, to prepare abstracts, seven hundred dollars;</p>
<p>For postage for State Department, two hundred dollars;</p>
<p>For postage for Comptroller&#39;s office, two hundred dollars;</p>
<p>For pay or expressmen to carry the proclamation of the Gover<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nor convening the Legislature in extra Session, four dollars per day each;</p>
<p>For amount due Fleeson and Palmer, for publishing in the American Flag, 1847, the laws of Texas relating to elections, and orders of elections in English and Spanish, fifty dollars;</p>
<p>To pay for publishing proclamation of the Governor ordering elections for seat of government, for judges of eighth and twelfth districts, and general elections for county officers, also declaring Austin the seat of government, and ordering election in fourth senatorial district, and convening the Legislature in extra session, two thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="811" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="29" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to change an Appropriation therein named, and appropri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ating the same for the Contingent Expenses of the Extra Session of the Legislature, for the year 1850.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That so much of the unexpended appropriation for pay and mileage of the members of the third Legislature, as may be neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary, be and is hereby appropriated to meet the contingent ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penses of the present extra session, and that the same be trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred on the books of the Comptroller, to the credit of the appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priation.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it enacted, That this act take effct and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an Act entitled an Act to incorporate the City of Austin, passed May 11, 1846.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the city council shall have power to levy and collect a tax of one-fourth of one per cent., on all property within the limits of said city, both personal and real; provided, that the revenue so collected shall be applied to no other purpose than that of the cleaning and improvement of the streets, sidewalks, alleys, etc.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That it shall not be lawful to summons the citizens residing within the limits of the same, to work on any road beyond the city.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That all laws, and parts of laws contravening the provisions of this act be, and they are hereby re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pealed; and that this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="812" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="30" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Various tribes and parts of tribes of Indians have emi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />grated from the territory of the United States and have intru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ded themselves upon the territory of this State against the wishes, and greatly to the annoyance and injury of the citizens thereof, greatly retarding the settlement of the country, and very materially and injuriosly affecting the general prosperity of the State by inciting the wild Indians through an illicit traffic carried on with them, and by other and more direct means to kill and plunder our frontier settlements and by perpetrating the same offences themselves, sometimes openly and without dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />guise, but mostly upon the credit of the wild Indians; and Whereas, it is believed by those who are most familiar with, and best informed in regard to our Indian relations, that the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />moval of the intruding Indians referred to, from amongst those properly belonging to this State, and their return and all fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ther intercourse between them being prevented, would be fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowed by most salutary results greatly tending to secure peace and permanent quiet to our frontiers; but which cannot be ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pected while they are allowed to remain, and such trade and in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tercourse is permitted to be continued: Therefore, Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the (Governor of the State be and he is hereby requested to demand of the Government of the United States, the immediate removal be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />yond the limits of this State of all Indians who have emigrated from any of the States or Territories of the United States and in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />truded upon any part of the territory of this State, and that effi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cient measures be adopted by said government to prevent their return at any time hereafter; and that this resolution be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate Lockhart Academy, in the County of Caldwell.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Wm. Larremore, Lewis C. Sims, J. P. [I. J.?] Goode, Marcus Trumble and John Montgomery, be and they are hereby <pb n="813" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="31" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>incorporated a body politic, under the name and style of the Trus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tees of Lockhart Academy, capable of suing and being sued, of pleading and being impleaded, of holding property, either real, personal or mixed, of selling and conveying the same at pleasure, of having a common seal, and of doing and performing whatever else that may be proper and necessary to be done for the advance<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of said institution, not contrary to the laws and constitution of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this charter and privilege shall extend to the said trustees, and their successors in office, as long as they confine the benefit of the same to the advancement of the sciences and the promotion of useful knowledge; which in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution shall be alike accessible to all, without regard to opinions of religion or politics.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the trustees, for the time being, shall have full power to enact by-laws, rules and regulations for the government of said academy, as may seem to them neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary for that object.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to change the Names of Helen Bass and Clara Bass, to that of Helen Menard and Clara Menard, on certain Condi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the names of Helen Bass and Clara Bass, children of Mrs. Rebecca Bass, formerly, now the wife of Mishell B. Menard, be and the same are hereby changed to that of Helen Menard and Clara Menard, upon condition that the said Mishell B. Menard shall execute, according to law, an act adopting said Helen and Clara as his children and heirs.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="814" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="32" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the San Antonio Railroad Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That S. A. Maverick, Gideon Lee, L. G. Capers, John D. Groesbeeck, Nathaniel Lewis, L. A. Paschal, Thos. J. Devine, Fran<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cis Gilbean, Thos. J. Perriman, B. Calaghan, J. J. Giddings, Vol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ney E. Howard, John James, B. E. Edwards, John Twohig, Lud<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wic Colqnhoun, J. O. Meusebach, O. Evans, J. H. Beck, Rob&#8217;t S. Neighbors, A. Lockwood, W. H. Merriwether, Enoch Jones, and their associates and successors, be and they are hereby enacted, and established a body corporate and politic, under the name of the San Antonio and Mexican Gulf Railroad, with capacity in said corporate name, to make contracts, to have succession and a com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mon seal, to make by-laws for the government and the regulations of the affairs, to sue and be sued, to plead and to be impleaded, to grant and receive, and generally to do and perform all such act as may be necessary or proper for, or incident to the fulfilment of its obligations, or maintenance of its rights under this act, and in accordance with the constitution of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the said company be, and is hereby invested with the rights of locating, contracting, owning, and maintaining a railway, commencing at any suitable point on the Gulf between Galveston and Corpus Christi, and thence running by such course and to such point at, or near the city of San Antonio, as said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany shall deem most suitable, with the privilege of making, own<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, and maintaining such branches of said railway, as they may deem most expedient.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the parties named in this act, or a majority of them, with such persons as they may associate with themselves for this purpose, are hereby appointed commisioners, and invested with the rights of forming and organizing said company, and of exer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cising the powers of directors until directors are chosen, when the powers of the commissioners shall cease.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the capital stock of said company shall be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each; each share entitling the owner thereof to one vote in person, or by proxy at all meetings of the company, and the shares shall be deemed personal estate, and shall be transferable by any conveyance in writing re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corded either by the treasurer in books kept by him for that purpose at his office, or by any officer duly authorized by the directors, in books kept by him at such other place, as the direc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="815" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="33" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>tors may appoint, such transfers as are recorded in any other place, being within thirty days communicated to the treasurer and by him entered on his books.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The immediate control and direction of the affairs of the company shall be vested in a board of not less than thirteen directors; said directors shall elect one of their own number to be president of the company; the first board of directors shall be chosen by the persons named in this act, and such persons as they may associate with themselves for that purpose; said election shall be held in the city of San Antonio, and at such time as the per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons named in this act, or a majority of them with their associ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ates shall determine, the directors thus elected by the stockholders; no person shall [be] eligible to the office of director, unless a sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scriber or owner of at least three shares of the capital stock; the directors shall have power to fill any vacancy in their body arising from non-election or other cause; they shall have power to appoint a clerk, treasurer, or any such other officers or agents as they may deem necessary, and prescribe and require bonds for the faithful performance of their duties; they may make all necessary rules and regulations for the holding of meetings, and all other lawful things they may deem proper for the carrying out the provisions of this charter, and business of the company; they shall keep or cause to be kept correct records of all meetings of the directors and com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, and accurate books and accounts of the receipts and expendi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tures of the company, and all other books and accounts necessary and proper to be kept by such a company; a majority of the board of directors shall have the power of a full board, and all convey<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ances and contracts executed in writing, signed by the President and counter-signed by the treasurer, or any other officer duly au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorised by the directors, under the seal of the company, and in pursuance of a vote of the directors, shall be valid and binding; and the book shall be open to inspection of stockholders.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the directors shall have power to dispose of the shares in said capital stock, in such manner and on such terms, as they may deem best for the interest of the company; and any agreement in writing, whereby any person shall become a sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scriber to the capital stock of said company, may be enforced against him according to its terms; if any subscriber shall fail to pay any amount due upon shares, subscribed for by him accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing to the terms of his subscription, the directors may after twenty days public notice, sell at public auction, the shares subscribed for by said delinquents, and transfer to the purchaser such shares; if the proceeds of the sale shall not be sufficient to pay the amount <pb n="816" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="34" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>due with interest and charges, such delinquent shall be held lia<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ble to the company for the deficiency, and if the proceeds shall ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed the amount so due with interest and charges, he shall be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled to the surplus.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. It shall be lawful for the company to purchase and hold any land that may be necessary for the purpose of locating, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stituting and maintaining said Rail-way; with all necessary depots and other buildings, and may by their engineers and agents, enter upon and take possession of all such lands as may be necessary for the locating, constructing and maintaining said rail way, and if they shall not be able to obtain such lands by agreement with the owner; they shall pay for the same such amount as shall be de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />termined in the manner provided for in the following section; the land so taken for the rail road shall not exceed fifty yards in width, and for depots and buildings only such further width as may be necessary.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That any persons from whom land has been taken for the purpose set forth in the preceding section may apply to the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict court of the county wherein said land is situated, for the ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointment of appraisers, and said court after proof that the Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent of the company has been served with a notice describing the land, ten days before the holding of the court, the court shall there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />upon appoint three disinterested free holders, citizens of the county, who shall appoint a time and place to hear the application; and the company to whose agent or President a reasonable notice shall be given by the court of said time and place and said free holders after being sworn shall after hearing the parties, determine the amount of compensation as aforesaid, and make return of their award to said court at its next term, and said award may be confirmed or for any sufficient reason rejected by said court in the same manner as awards by arbitrators, under a rule of court, and if confirmed by the court, judgment shall issue threon as in other cases; in deter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mining the amount of compensation to be paid as aforesaid said free holders shall be governed by the actual value of the land at the time it was taken, taking into consideration the benefit or in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jury done to other neighboring land of the owner by the estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lishment of said rail way; if in any case the amount found by the arbitrators shall not exceed the sum proved to have been offered by the company to the owner prior to his application to the court, the owner shall pay the cost of the proceedings, otherwise the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany shall pay the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That said company may acquire by purchase, dona<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion or in payment of stock, such real estate as the directors shall think desirable for the purpose of aiding in the construction or <pb n="817" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="35" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>maintenance of said road, and such real estate acquired by the company, may be alienated or mortgaged by a vote of the majority of the directors, for the constructing or maintaining said rail way; said alienation or mortgage shall be signed in the name of the President and countersigned by the treasurer.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That said company shall have power to borrow money on their bonds or notes, at such rates as the directors shall deem expedient: provided, however, that nothing in this act shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />strued to confer banking privileges of any kind.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That upon the written request of one-fourth of the stockholders, the President of the company shall call a special meeting of the directors; and upon the written request of said one<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fourth of the stockholders, an election shall be held for directors; and a vote of two-thirds of the stockholders shall be sufficient to remove the directors, and appoint others in their stead, at any time before the expiration of the period for which said directors were originally elected.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That the mayor and aldermen of the city of San An<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tonio be and they are hereby anthorised to subscribe to the capital stock of said company for said city, to an amount not to exceed fifty thousand dollars, as also such incorporated towns through which said railway may pass, inclusive of the town, if any, that may be its terminus on the gulf; and to issue bonds bearing interest, or otherwise to pledge the faith of said city or towns to pay for the same; and the chief justice and county commissioners of the sev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral counties through which the railway may pass, shall be and they are hereby authorised to subscribe to the capital stock of said company for their respective counties, to an amount not to exceed fifty thousand dollars, and to issue bonds bearing interest, or other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise to pledge the faith of their respective counties to pay the same: provided, that the chief justice and county commissioners of said counties shall not make such subscription unless two-thirds of the qualified electors of said county or counties, at an election to be held for that purpose, shall vote in favor of such subscription being made and the chief justice of any of such counties may order such election to be held, and shall give notice of the time and object of such election, by causing notice thereof to be posted up in each precinct of the county, at least thirty days before the holding of such, election; said election to be conducted in the manner regulating county elections, so far as the same may be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plicable: provided also, that said mayor and aldermen of the city of San Antoino, and the towns upon the line and at the terminus of said railway on the gulf, shall not make such subscriptions unless two-thirds of the electors of said city <pb n="818" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="36" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>or towns qualified to vote for town or city officers, at an election to be held for that purpose, shall Vote in favor of such subscrip<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion being made; and the mayor of said city or towns may order such an election to be held, and shall give notice by publication in the newspaper published in the city or town, or by notice posted up in the precints of said city or town, for at least twenty days pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vious to such election being held; and said elections shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ducted in the same manner regulating the respective city or town elections, so far as the same may be applicable: provided further, that where any such subscriptions shall be made, and bonds thereof be issued, by the mayor and aldermen of any of said towns or city, or by the chief justice and county commissioners of any of said coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties, it shall be their duty, respectively, to provide for the punctual payment of the interest that may from time to time become due upon the same, and for the payment of the principal thereof by levying and collecting a tax on the real and personal property in the city, town or county for which said subscription shall be made and bonds issued, which tax shall not be less than ten cents nor more than fifty cents on each and every one hundred dollars taxable property in said city, town or county, and shall be assessed and col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lected and paid into the treasury of said city, town or counties by which it is levied in the same manner the city or county tax in such city or towns or counties is assessed and collected, which tax shall be continued from year to year, until the whole amount of the principal and interest due on said bonds shall have been fully paid and discharged, and when collected, after deducting there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />from the expenses of assessing and collecting, shall first be applied to the payment of the interest due on such bonds, and the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mainder shall be applied to the payment of the principal on such bonds.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That all dividends on the capital stock of said railway company that may accrue to said city, towns, or either of said counties, shall be appropriated to the payment of the principal and interest of any bonds that may be owing by them respectively, and that may have been executed under the provisions of this act, until the whole of said principal and interest shall have been discharged; and the said railway company is hereby authorized to pay the same accordingly.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That it shall be the duty of said company, whenever any State or county road now established, shall be crossed by said railway, to make and keep in repair good and sufficient cause<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ways at such crossing; and in all cases where any person shall own land on both sides of the railway, and there shall be no other convenient access from one point to the other, such own<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="819" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="37" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>er shall have the right of passage free of cost, at all reasonable times, crossing said railway; and if said company shall cross any navigable stream, they shall not interfere with the navigation of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. That if any person shall negligently or designedly in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jure or destroy any of the fixtures, buildings, machines or improve<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments of said company, or any portion of the railway or its branches, he shall be liable to indictment for such offence or of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fences, and, upon conviction, he shall be punished by fine and im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prisonment, at the discretion of the court, and shall also be liable to the company, in addition, for damages.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. That said company shall have the right to charge and receive such rates and prices for the transportation of passengers and freight, as shall not exceed eight cents per mile for passengers, and for freight, not exceeding seventy-five cents per one hundred pounds for every hundred miles the same may be carried: provided, however, that the State shall have the right to regulate the charge for carrying the mails.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. That the company shall after the completion of the rail way sell and alienate all lands held by said company, save such as shall be necessary for the maintenance of the rail way, within the following periods, one third of said lands within five years, one third within ten years and the remainder within fifteen years after the completion of said rail way, and on failure by the company to alienate within the time limited, the Comptroller of the State may after public notice in a newspaper published at the seat of govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment and in the counties where the land may lie, cause said lands to be publicly sold for cash, the proceeds of said sale after deduct<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing expenses of sale to be paid to the authorised agents of the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. That if said rail way is not completed within one year from the first of November, 1850, and if at least twenty miles are not in running order within three years from its commencement then this charter shall be null and void.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="820" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="38" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize and require the County Courts to issue uncon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ditional Certificates in certain Cases.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the county courts of the several counties in this State, are hereby authorized and required to issue unconditional certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cates in all cases to bona fide claimants, where the party applicant has previously obtained a conditional one; and make the same proof that has been required in all such cases under the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion and laws of the Republic, or the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the county courts shall be entitled to the same fees, and governed in all respects by former laws, as in such eases heretofore.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to an Act entitled an Act to secure to all actual Settlers within the Limits of the Colony granted to Peters and others, commonly known as Peters&#8217; Colony, the Lands to which they are entitled as Colonists.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the certificates issued by the commissioner for Peters&#8217; colony, may be located on any vacant land within the limits of said colony not otherwise appropriated, as other headright certificates are located; and the same laws relative thereto shall govern the sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyors and other officers in the discharge of their official duties, in relation to the surveying, recording and patenting the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That any certificate which has been, or may be issued contrary to the true intent and meaning of said act, to which this is supplementary; and each and every sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vey which has been or may be made in virtue of such certificate, and each and every patent which may be issued in virtue thereof, and every sale and transfer of said unauthorized certificates, and of the land located under the same, is and shall be null and void; and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 6, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="821" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="39" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to create the County of Freestone.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all that territory comprised within the following limits, to wit: beginning at the upper corner of Leon county, on the Trin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ity river; thence with the north-west line of said county, south 60 deg. west 29&#190; miles; thence north 30 deg. west 31&#189; miles; thence north 60 deg. east to the Trinity river; thence down the Trinity river with its meanders, to the place of beginning; shall be consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tuted into a new county, and be called Freestone.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That William S. Adams, Emanuel Clements, W. G. Harris, Leander Walker,-Simmons, be and they are hereby appointed commissioners, with authority to select not exceeding three places, to be put in nomination as the county seat of said county, (one of which shall be at the centre of said county, to be ascertained by actual survey, which survey the said commissioners are hereby authorized to have made at the expense of the county, and the other places shall be within five miles of the centre of said county,) and the said commissioners shall then pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed to order an election between the different places put in nomi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nation for the county seat of said county, by giving a written notice to be posted up, at not less than five places in said county for the term of one month, which notice shall specify the different places put in nomination, and the election be governed according to the laws regulating elections generally, and the returns made to com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners herein appointed, at a day and place to be named in the writs of election, not to exceed ten days from and after the day of election; and said election returns shall not be opened by less than a majority of said commissioners; then if any place nomi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nated at, or within three miles of the centre, shall receive a ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jority of all the votes polled, it shall be duly declared to be the county seat of said county, by said commissioners; but if no place receive a majority of all the votes given, the said commissioners shall put in nomination, the two places that receive the highest number of votes at the first election, giving fifteen days notice of said election by posting up notices, at not less than five public places in said county, the result of which shall be ascertained as in the first election, provided for in this act; and the place receiving the highest number of votes, shall be declared by said commissioners the county seat of said county; and the said commissioners are <pb n="822" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="40" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>hereby required to order the first election contemplated by this act, to be held on the first Monday in December next, or as soon as this act shall come to their knowledge.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enaced, That the commissioners herein ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed, are required to take into consideration in the nomination of places for said county seat, donations in land or in money, as well as eligibility of situation and advantage of timber and water.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That should said commissioners select a tract of vacant and unappropriated land, on which to locate said county seat, they shall proceed to condemn to use of [the] county, a quanity of not more than three hundred and twenty acres of the same; and this act shall be a sufficient authority for any authorized surveyor to survey for said county the amount of land pointed out by said commisssioners, not to exceed three hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and twenty acres, in a square form, if pre-existing lines will admit of that shape; and when said commissioners, their successors or agents, shall present to the Commissioner of the General Land Office, the receipt of the State Treasurer for the sum of fifty cents per acre in gold or silver, for the amount of land contained in the survey authorized by this act to be made, then the said Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner of the General Land Office shall issue a patent to the county of Freestone for said land.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 6, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XL.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to an Act entitled an Act to reduce into one Act, and to amend the several Acts relating to the Establish<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of a General Landoffice, passed December 14, 1837.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the time limited for the payment of government dues on titled land, by the twenty-fourth section of the act to which this is supplementary, is hereby extended until the first day of January, 1852, with the privileges, and under the restrictions, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained in said section.</p>
<pb n="823" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="41" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the Commissioner of the General Landoffice is hereby authorized to receive the government dues on the lands referred to in the first section of this act; and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>September 6, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="824" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="42" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">THE STATE OF TEXAS.</head>
<p>I, JAMES W. WEBB, Acting Secretary of State, do certify that the second session of the third Legislature of said State, com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />menced its sesion at Austin on Monday, the twelfth day of August, in the year one thousand eight hundred and fifty, and adjourned on Friday the sixth day of September, of the same year.</p>
<p>And I further certify, that the Acts and Joint Resolutions con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained in this Volume, are true copies taken from the original laws deposited in the Department of State, with which they were care<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fully compared.</p>
<p>[L.S.] Given under my hand and seal of State, at the City of Austin, the first day of October, A. D. one thousand eight hundred and fifty.</p>
<closer>
<signed>JAMES W. WEBB.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>F. B.&#8212;The words in brackets were inserted by the Secretary of State, in comparing the laws with the originals, supposing them to be omissions in enrolling the bills.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="825" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX TO GENERAL AND SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECOND SESSION&#8212;THIRD LEGISLATURE.</head>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">A</head>
<p>ACADEMY&#8212;to incorporate Cass County Male and Female............... <ref>24</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; &#8220; Lockhart..................................... <ref>30</ref></p>
<p>APPROPRIATION&#8212;for payment of outstanding liabilities of the mission of R. S. Neighbors to organize the counties of El Paso, Worth and Santa F&#233;.... <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8212;for payment of mileage and per diem pay of members of the third Legislature............ <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8212;for balance due for printing the laws in Ger<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man and Spanish, and for printing report of joint committee to investigate the offices of Treasurer and Comptroller..................... <ref>26</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8212;for contingent expenses of extra session of the third Legislature.................... <ref>29</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8212;for printing laws and journals of extra session of third Legislature <ref>28</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8212;for construction of Penitentiary................ <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>ASSESSORS AND COLLECTORS&#8212;to be prohibited from exercising official functions before qualified, <ref>20</ref></p>
<p>AUSTIN CITY&#8212;to amend an act incorporating................... <ref>29</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; LOTS&#8212;authorizing the sale of.................... <ref>8</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">B</head>
<p>BASS&#8212;to change the names of Helen and Clara....................... <ref>31</ref></p>
<p>BRIDGE AND TURNPIKE&#8212;to incorporate Angelina Comp&#8217;y...... <ref>19</ref></p>
<pb n="826" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="ii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">C</head>
<p>CATTLE&#8212;to regulate shipping and slaughtering........................ <ref>27</ref></p>
<p>COLONY&#8212;to perfect land titles in Castro&#8217;s................................. <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8212;securing to actual settler&#8217;s the lands to which they are en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled in Peters&#8217;................................ <ref>38</ref></p>
<p>COMPANY&#8212;to incorporate Sulphur Fork Navigation.................... <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; <i>&#8212;</i>&#8221; &#8220; Angelina Bridge...................... <ref>19</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; <i>&#8212;</i>&#8221; &#8220; Colorado Navigation................ <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8212;&#8221; &#8220; Trinity Plank Road.................... <ref>17</ref></p>
<p>COOKE&#8212;joint resolution for the relief of the heirs of Louis P......... <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>COURTS, DISTRICT&#8212;to define the time of holding in the several judicial districts.................... <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; &#8212;to define the time of holding in the third ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicial district..................... <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; &#8212;to define the time of holding in the eighth ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicial district........................ <ref>15</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; COUNTY&#8212;required to issue unconditional certificates in certain cases............................... <ref>38</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">E &#38; F</head>
<p>ELECTION&#8212;for county site in Tarrant county.......................... <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>FALLS COUNTY&#8212;to locate county site of................................. <ref>17</ref></p>
<p>FREESTONE COUNTY&#8212;creating................................................ <ref>39</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">I &#38; J</head>
<p>INDIANS&#8212;joint resolution relating to............................ <ref>30</ref></p>
<p>INSTITUTE&#8212;to incorporate Central Male and Female................... <ref>14</ref></p>
<p>JEFFERSON&#8212;to repeal the third and fourth sections of an act to in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corporate the town of................................ <ref>9</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">L &#38; M</head>
<p>LAND OFFICE, GENERAL&#8212;reducing into one several acts relat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing to......................... <ref>40</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; TITLES&#8212;[vide TITLES.]</p>
<p>MAIL&#8212;requiring increase of service from Austin to Clarksville...... <ref>26</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">N &#38; O</head>
<p>NAVIGATION&#8212;to incorporate Sulphur Fork Company............. <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8212;&#8220; &#8220; Colorado Company.................. <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>OFFICE&#8212;reducing into one several acts relating to General Land... <ref>40</ref></p>
<pb n="827" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">P &#38; R</head>
<p>PENITENTIARY&#8212;making appropriation for construction of........ <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>PLANK-ROAD COMPANY&#8212;to incorporate Trinity............. <ref>17</ref></p>
<p>RAIL &#8220; &#8220; &#8212;&#8221; organize Buffalo Bayou, Brazos and Colorado............................. <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; &#8220; &#8212;to incorporate San Antonio.................. <ref>32</ref></p>
<p>RIO GRANDE CITY&#8212;to repeal an act to incorporate.................... <ref>12</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">S</head>
<p>SAN AUGUSTINE&#8212;to authorize qualified electors of, to elect corpor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ation officers............................ <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>SCOTT&#8212;name of Antoniett D., changed.................................... <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>SULPHUR FORK NAVIGATION COMPANY&#8212;[vide COMPANY.]</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">T &#38; W</head>
<p>TARRANT COUNTY&#8212;election for county site of.................. <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>TITLES&#8212;an act confirming, and requiring the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue patents on, certain land...... <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>TREASURER OF THE STATE&#8212;leave of absence granted to......... <ref>27</ref></p>
<p>WAY&#8212;changing the name of Sidney B.............................. <ref>13</ref></p>
<pb n="828" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iv" />
</div4>
</div3>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>