<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="327" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="321" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">SPECIAL LAWS <lb/>PASSED BY <lb/>THE SECOND LEOISLATUHE <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS</head>
<byline>VOLUME II.</byline>
<byline>PUBLISHED BY AUTHORITY.</byline>
<byline>HOUSTON. 1848</byline>
<pb n="328" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="322" />
<byline>*<sub>*</sub>* For more convenient reference, the laws contained herein are severally designated by chapters and numbers in regular series. The laws of the first Legislature are considered as being embraced in vol I, and those of the second in volume II.</byline>
<byline>*<sub>*</sub>* The laws of the present or second volume are divided into two parts&#8212;Part 1, containing those denominated &#8220;laws of a gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral nature;&#8221; and Part II, those &#8220;for private relief&#8221; and &#8220;incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rating towns, cities, institutions of learning, and private associa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions of every nature,&#8221; in conformity to the provisions of Chapter 71, Section 2, (Part I.)</byline>
<byline>*<sub>*</sub>* Those laws signed by the Governor, are designated by the word Approved&#8212;and those not signed by him, are said to be Passed.</byline>
<pb n="329" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="323" />
<head type="sub">VOLUME II&#8212;PART.II. SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 163.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act To grant a ferry privilege to Nancy Hutchinson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Nancy Hutchinson, of the County of Jefferson, is hereby granted the privilege of keeping a ferry on river Neches, at Beaumont, upon her giving bond as required by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 14, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 164.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Martin Walker.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby required to issue a patent to Martin Walker, upon a certificate for one league of land issued to said Walker by the Board of Land Commissioners for Bastrop County, under the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of &#8220;an act making provisions for persons who have been permanently disabled in-the service of Texas,&#8221; approved December 18th, 1837.&#34;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 14, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="330" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="324" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 165.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of John S. McNairy, of Nashville, Tennessee.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller of Public Accounts, on receiving proper evidence of the loss of two several certificates of land scrip, number twelve and sixteen, issued by the government of Texas to Thomas Toby, for six hundred and forty acres each, and transferred to John S. McNairy, of Nashville, Tennessee, shall issue duplicates of the same to the said McNairy; which certificates, when issued, may be located on any of the unappropriated public domain of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this resolution take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 18, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 166.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Treasurer and Comptroller to pay over and deliver to Andrew Northington, assignee of the heirs of Caleb Kemp, the money and papers deposited with them by William J. Maynard, administrator of the estate of said Caleb Kemp.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Treasurer be and he is hereby authorized and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired, to pay to Andrew Northington, the sum of twelve hundred and sixty three dollars and thirty six cents&#8212;it being the amount deposited in the Treasury by William J. Maynard, administrator of Caleb Kemp, deceased; and that he take the receipt of said Northington therefor.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the Comptroller be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to deliver to Andrew Northington the papers and documents relating to the estate of Caleb Kemp, deposited with him by William J. Maynard, ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ministrator of said estate: Provided that the said Andrew Nor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="331" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="325" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>thington shall file in the office of the Comptroller, notarial copies of the assignment, from the heirs of the said Kemp.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 22, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 167.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to establish Public Schools in the County of Galveston.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the County Court of the County of Galveston, shall, at the time they levy a county tax, add thereto a tax for the sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />port of Public Schools hereby established in said county, on all real and personal property liable to taxation for State and county pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poses in said county, and it shall be assessed and collected by the Assessor and Collector of State and County taxes at the same time and in the same manner that the county taxes are; provided, that said tax shall not exceed in any one year, the one fourth of one per centum on the value of the property taxed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That each Ward in the City of Galveston, shall constitute a School District, and shall be entitled to two School Trustees; and all that part of Galveston Island not embraced within the corporate limits of the City of Galveston, shall constitute a school district, and shall be entitled to two trustees; and all that part of Galveston county lying North and West of Gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veston Bay, shall constitute a school district, and be entitled to one trustee; and all that part of Galveston county lying East and North of Galveston Bay, shall constitute a school district, and shall be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled to one trustee.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That all the qualified electors for county officers for the county of Galveston, shall be enti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tled to a vote for school trustees in the respective wards or precincts where they reside; and the board of trustees shall be elected for the term of two years, excepting as hereinafter pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, to wit: the first board of school trustees elected in pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="332" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="326" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>suance of this act, at their first meeting and organization, shall cause the trustees from each ward or precinct having two trustees, to determine by lot the time they shall serve, so that the first class, or one from each ward or precinct shall go out of office at the ter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mination of the first year; and the second class at the termination of the second year; and the Chief Justice of Galveston county shall order all elections for school trustees, and to fill vacancies to take place on the first Monday in the month of March of each year, ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cepting the first election held under this act, which shall be ordered to take place within twenty days after a certified copy of this act is in the hands of said Chief Justice; and all the trustees elected at the said first election, shall continue in office until their successors are duly elected at the annual election in the year eighteen hundred forty-nine; and said elections for school trustees shall be held at such places in each ward or precinct herein named, as shall be desig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nated by the Chief Justice in ordering the elections, and shall be governed by the laws of the State regulating general elections so far as the same are applicable hereto.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the Chief Justice of Galves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton County, shall be ex-officio President of the Board of School Trustees, and shall preside at all of the meetings of the board when present: but in case of his absence, refusal or inability to preside, the board shall elect from their own number, a President pro tem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pore, to preside and to perform all other duties incumbent on the President of the Board of school trustees; and in case of any other vacancy in the board, by resignation or otherwise, the board shall fill any such vacancy, until the next annual election for school trus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tees from the qualified electors in the ward or precinct where the vacancy occurs.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the board of school trustees shall have the supervision and control of the public schools, and they shall make such rules and by-laws for their own government, and that of the schools, as they may deem best, and alter and amend the same at their pleasure; and it shall be the duty of the board of school trustees, to report annually to the County Court, at least three days before the time of levying the tax, provided for in the first section of this act, the condition of the public schools; the num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber of pupils admitted and instructed; the average number that have attended the schools; the number of teachers employed; the various <pb n="333" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="327" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>branches of learning taught in the schools the preceding year; also, the amount of revenue received, and from what source; the amount expended and in what manner; and they shall, also, submit an esti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mate of the cost of conducting the schools for the ensuing year, on the most economical plan; and it shall also be the duty of the board of school trustees to keep a record of their proceedings; and such record shall be open to the inspection of any school tax payer in the county of Galveston at all times, and any five members of said board of school trustees shall constitute a quorum, and shall have full power to transact all business appertaining to said board.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the Trustees of the public schools shall establish in each ward or precinct at least one pri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mary school, provided, that there can be assembled conveniently in said ward or precinct a school of twenty-five pupils or upwards, and that a suitable building call be procured in the ward or pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cinct, for their accommodation; and further provided, that in case either of the precincts lying North and West of Galveston Bay, and East and North of Galveston Bay, as specified in section second of this act, shall fail or refuse to assemble the number of pupils herein required to constitute a school, then said precinct or precincts shall be exempt from taxation under the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That every minor or child over five years of age, and under sixteen years of age residing in Gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veston county, may be admitted on such terms and regulations as may be adopted by the board of school trustees, into the public schools herein provided for, and shall enjoy all the privileges and immunities of said schools.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the County Court for the county of Galveston, may, from time to time, so alter and change the school districts in said county as they may deem best, provided, that said change shall tend to equalize the pop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ulation in each district, and render it more convenient for the citizens, and that no greater number of districts be made than are provided for by this act; and said County Court shall also have power to borrow money in anticipation of the school taxes for the current year, to carry on the schools until the taxes are assessed and collected; and it shall be the further duty of the County Court to notify the board of school trustees, so soon as they have levied the tax for the support of the public schools for the year, of the amount of revenue that may rea<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="334" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="328" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>sonably be expected from said tax; and it shall also be the duty of the County Court to see that all funds belonging to, and appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated for the support of the public schools, and placed in the hands of the County Treasurer of Galveston County; and it shall be the duty of said County Court to take ample security for the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That all payments to teachers, and for incidental expenses of said schools, shall be made by a draft on the County Treasurer, signed by the President of the board of school trustees, and countersigned by one or more of the committee of accounts, which committee shall be erected as a stand<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing committee, whose duty it shall be to examine and audit all accounts, and every draft shall be accompanied by a specification, designating what the same was drawn for.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That at the same time when the first election is held for school trustees as contemplated and provided for in the third section of this act, polls shall also be held at which every qualified voter for county officers for Gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veston county shall by vote, be permitted to express his assent to, or dissent from the provisions of this act; and in case a majority of the votes then given in, shall be against the same, this act shall thereafter be of no effect.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That all laws, and parts of laws, that in any way conflict with the provisions of this act be, and the same are hereby repealed, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>January 24, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 168.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution to provide for a settlement of the claims of E. W. Moore, Post Captain commanding the late Navy of Texas, on ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />count of cash advances made for the use of said Navy.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, it appears upon a settlement of the accounts of E. W. Moore, Post Captain commanding the late Texas Navy, that there is a balance due said E. W. Moore, of eleven thousand <pb n="335" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="329" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>three hundred and ninety eight dollars thirty six and a half cents, from the late Republic of Texas, on account of cash advances made by him for the use of the Navy, Therefore:</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the said accounts and the vouchers of said E. W. Moore, together with the report of the Comptroller thereon, be deposited in the Comptroller&#8217;s office; and that the claim of said Moore for said sum of eleven thousand three hundred and ninety eight dollars thir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty six and a half cents, shall be as valid, and shall have the same force and effect, as if the same had been audited and settled by the proper accounting officers of the late Republic of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this Joint Resolution take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 24, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 169.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of persons who furnished supplies on the credit of Post Captain E. W. Moore, for the use of the Navy of the late Republic of Texas, while commanded by said Post Captain E. W. Moore.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, it appears that various supplies were furnished by dif<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferent individuals, for the use of the Navy of the late Republic of Texas, on the credit of Post Captain E. W. Moore, amounting to fifteen thousand two hundred and two dollars and six cents&#8212;the accounts and vouchers for which are on file among the archives of the late Auditorial Department, Therefore:</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That said acccounts and vouchers, together with the report of the Comptroller in relation to the same, shall be deposited in the office of the Comptroller of Public Accounts, and when so deposited, shall be as valid, and have the same force and effect-in favor of each claimant, who furnished said supplies, as if the same had been audited and settled by the proper accounting of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficers of the late Republic of Texas: Provided that said ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="336" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="330" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>counts shall not exced the sum of fifteen thousand two hundred and two dollars and six cents, as above specified: And further pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that said claimants shall release said E. W. Moore from any liability on account of the claims above referred to.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this joint resolution take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 24, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 170.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Union Marine and Fire Insurance Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Samuel M. Wiliams, C. W. Adams, A. E. Janies, J. S. Sydnor, A. Ball, S. W. Tichenor, Edward Hill, J. M. Jones, S. L. Jones, Wm. Hendley, Wm. M. Rice, J. H. Stevens, and T. W. House, and their present and future associates, successors and as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />signs, be and are hereby incorporated and created a body politic and corporate, by the name and style of the &#8220;UNION MARINE AND FIRE INSURANCE COMPANY;&#8221; and by the same name and style they and their successors shall be capable of suing and being sued, and maintaining any action to final judgment and exe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cution, and shall be in law capable of purchasing, holding, improv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, and conveying any estate, real, personal, or mixed, for the use of said Corporation; and the said Corporation shall have power to ordain, establish and put in execution, such by-laws, ordinances and regulations as shall be necessary for the government there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />of and it shall be lawful for the said Corporation, after the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />piration of the charter thereof, to use the corporate name, style and capacity, for the purpose of suits for the final settlement and liquidation of the affairs and accounts of the Corporation, and for the sale and disposition of their estate, real, personal, or mixed, but not for any other purpose, or in any other man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner whatsoever, nor for a period exceeding three years after the expiration of the term of incorporation: provided, neverthe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="337" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="331" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>less, that the foregoing section shall not be construed to authorise the said Corporation to purchase or hold any real estate exceed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing in value ten thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the capital stock of said Corporation shall be one hundred and fifty thousand dollars, di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided into shares of fifty dollars each; and the same shall be cre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated and paid in such manner, and at such times, as the President and Directors of said Corporation shall require&#8212;of which requisi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions the President shall give at least one month&#8217;s notice in the &#8220;Civilian&#8221; and &#8220;News&#8221; of Galveston, and the &#8220;Telegraph,&#8221; of Houston, or other public newspaper, and cause the same to be notified to the stockholders: and if any stockholder shall, after due notice, neglect or refuse to pay any instalment so required to be paid, he or she shall cease to be a member of said Corporation, and the share or shares, so forfeited, may be sold by the Corporation in such manner as they may think proper; but such forfeiture or forfeitures and sale of stock, shall not release the holder thereof, nor his, her or their securities on the notes contemplated to be given in section eight of this Act, from his, her or their liability, on account of said notes to any person to persons, having a just claim against the corporation created by this Act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That for the well ordering of the affairs of the said corporation, there shall be seven Directors, who shall be stockholders of the corporation. They shall be elected by the stockholders at their annual meeting, to be held on the first Monday in December, of each year, for that purpose; and the di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rectors, at their first meeting, shall choose one of their own num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber as President: Provided, nevertheless, that until the first annual election, the persons named in the first Section of this Act, shall have and may exercise all the powers given to the President and Directors by this act: and in all elections for Directors, the vote shall be by ballot, and each stockholder shall have one vote for each share he may hold: but no stockholder shall vote at any elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, unless the share or shares upon which he may claim to vote, shall have been standing in his or her name on the books of the said corporation, for at least three months previous to such elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion; in case of absence from any general meeting, any stockholder may be entitled to vote by proxy.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted. That the Directors of said corporation, for the time being, four of whom, including the <pb n="338" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="332" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>President, shall form a quorum, shall have power to appoint such officers, clerks, agents, and other persons, as shall he necessary for conducting and executing the business of the said corporation, and to allow said persons so appointed, such compensation for their services, respectively, as they shall deem reasonable and just; and generally, to exercise all other authority and powers for the well ordering and governing the affairs and funds of said corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That it shall be lawful for the said corporation to employ the funds thereof in establishing and sustaining the business of Marine and Fire Insurance; to insure against loss or damages by Sea, Fire, Moneys, and other risks of loss or damages, to which vessels and merchandise are liable; vessels, merchandise, treasure and freight; to insure vessels in port, build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings, merchandise, and all other perishable property on land, against loss or damage by fire; and to charge, collect, and receive for the same such permiums of Insurance as the President and Directors of said corporation may deem just, reasonable, and com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mensurate with the risk; but not at a higher rate than those charged in the city of New Orleans. It shall be lawful for the said corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion to lend at a rate of interest, not exceeding ten per centum per annum, any surplus capital which they at any time possess, which may not be required for the payment of losses as ascertained to have occurred; to lend money on bottomry and respondentia se<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curity at Marine interest, reserving therefrom, a sum, at the rate of two per centum, to be appropriated to the improvement of the navigation of the different streams tributary to the Bay of Gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veston and its Harbor, but it shall not be lawful for said corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion to issue any promissory notes of the character of Bank bills, or to exercise banking privileges.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the shares of said corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration shall be assignable and transferable upon the books of said company, according to such rules and regulations as the President and Directors thereof shall for that purpose ordain and establish; and in case the assignee of any share or shares of stock shall deposit his note with securities as contemplated and provided for in section eight of this Act, the same to be approved by the county court, as in said section eight is provided, then the assignor of such share or shares shall have the right to withdraw and cancel his note or notes and securities given for such share or shares of stock; otherwise the notes and <pb n="339" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="333" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>securities of said assigner to be and remain subject and liable to all the conditions and provisions contained in section ninth of this Act.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That the President and Directors of said corporation shall annually, or semi-annually, divide to the stockholders thereof so much of the profits of the business of the said corporation as in their discretion they shall deem safe and proper: but no dividend of any of the profits of the said company shall be made, unless the capital paid in be and remain unim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />paired: Provided, however, that the amount of two per cent, men<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned in section fifth of this Act, shall not be considered as form<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing a part of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the office of the company incorporated by this Act, shall be located in the city of Galveston, and so soon as the President and Directors thereof shall establish by evidence to the satisfaction of the County Court of Galveston County, that ten per centum of the capital stock of said corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion has been paid by the stockholders to the Actuary or Secretary thereof, and that the balance or residue of said Capital of One Hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and Fifty Thousand Dollars has been secured to be paid when called for, as contemplated in section second of this Act, by the notes of the holders of said capital stock, secured by not less than two good and solvent persons, who shall be citizens of and resident in either the county of Galveston or the County of Harris; and also shall establish to the satisfaction of said county court, that the Di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rection of said corporation has been organized in conformity with the provisions of section third of this Act, then said County Court shall give them a certificate thereof, which shall be their warrant to commence business operations, under the authority vested by this Act.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That in case the corporation cre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated by this Act, shall fail, refuse, or be unable to pay any judgment which may be recovered against the same, the person or persons in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terested in said judgment shall have a right of action against each stockholder thereof, and his, her or their securities on the notes re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to be given by section eighth of this Act, until such judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment or judgments are satisfied and discharged.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That the charter granted by this Act shall continue in full force and effect for the full term of twenty years from and after the passage of this Act.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 26, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="340" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="334" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 171.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution authorizing the Commisioner of the General Land Office to issue a patent in the name of Adolphus Sterne, assignee of Maria Josefa Sanchez.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and directed to issue to Adolphus Sterne, assignee of Maria Josef a Sanchez, a patent on certificate No. 335, issued by the Board of Land Commissioners for Nacogdoches Coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty. on the 20th day of February 1838, in accordance with said cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate and field notes returned, provided, the Governent dues thereon are paid.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 26, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 172.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution authorizing the Adjutant General, to issue a bounty land warrant, to Elijah. D. Holland.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas Elijah D. Holland, entered the service of the Republic of Texas, as a regular soldier, for during the war with Mexico, in the year 1837, as appears from the muster-roll of Capt. Jas. Jevon and furloughs signed by said Capt. Jevon, and E. More<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />house, Adjutant General, and Col. Com. T. A.; and as it appears from the certificate of G. R. L. Billups, acting Commissary, that the said Holland was prevented from returning to his company, before the army was discharged, in consequence of an injury he, the said Holland, received, while in discharge of his duty as a soldier, the consequence of which was, that he did not obtain his honorable discharge as the law directed: Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1.&#8212;Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Adjutant General be and he is hereby author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="341" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="335" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ized and directed to issue to the said Elijah D. Holland, his bounty land warrant, for the amount of land which may be due him, from the time he entered the army until the disbanding of Capt. Jas. Jevon&#8217;s company.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That such land warrant shall be as good, and valid in law, as if granted upon the delivery of an honorable discharge.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further resolved, That this resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 26, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 173.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate Protection Fire Company No. 1, City of Houston.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Helson T. Davis, Abraham M. Gentry, Henry Samp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, A. J. Burke, Houston Moore, William G. Evans, J. H. O. Smith, and their associates and successors, shall be and they are hereby constituted a body politic and corporate, under the name and style of Protection Fire Company, No. 1, City of Houston, with power to sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, to appear and prosecute to final judgment in any court or elsewhere; to have a common seal with such device as they may adopt; to elect in whatever manner they choose the officers necessary to command them; to establish by laws for the government and regulation of their affairs not inconsistent with the constitution and laws of this State, and the same to alter or amand at pleasure; and to hold real estate and personal property, and to dispose of the same: Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, however, such real estate and personal property shall at no time exceed twenty thousand dollars in value, and that said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany shall never exceed one hundred men, rank and file.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the actual members of said company shall be exempt from serving on juries, and from militia duty, except in time of insurrection, rebellion or war.</p>
<pb n="342" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="336" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That said company shall have power by their constitution and by-laws, to try all violators of their own ordinances agreed upon by a majority of the members of said company; to suspend, expel, or fine not exceeding ten dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars, those violating the Constitution and laws of said company.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That this act of incorporation shall be and continue in force for and during the term of twenty vears from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 26, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 174.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the heirs of Isaac Van Zandt, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Probate Judge of Harris County, or in his ab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sence, any Notary Public of said County, is hereby authorized to take the Probate of the Will of Isaac Van Zandt, deceased, and certify and transmit the same to the Probate Court of Harrison County, and the proof of said Will thus taken shall be as valid in the Probate Court of Harrison County, as if the same had been taken in said Court.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 27, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="343" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="337" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 175.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to make Robert Franklin Miller, the lawful heir of Solomon Miller.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas. That from and after the passage of this act, Robert Frank<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lin Miller, of San Augustine County, shall be and is hereby made the lawful heir of Solomon Miller, of said county.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 27, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 176.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the Incorporation of the City of Laredo.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the citizens of the city of Laredo, in the county of Webb, are hereby declared a body politic and corporate, by the name and style of the Corporation of the City of Laredo, and by that name may sue and be sued, plead, and be impleaded, in all courts, and in all actions and matters whatsoever, and by the same name may purchase, hold and dispose of any estate, real or personal, within the limits of the city, for the use and benefit of the corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, and may have a common seal, which they may alter and change at their pleasure.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the limits of the city of Laredo shall be one mile square, and bounded in the following man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner, viz:&#8212;the Rio Grande shall constitute one line, anl the upper and lower lines shall be equi-distant from the public square or plaza, and running back from the river, parallel to each other, shall intersect the back line at right angles; the lines shall all be one mile in length, and forming, as near as the meanders of the river will allow, a perfect square.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That there shall be elected one mayor, and six aldermen, who shall constitute the city council, <pb n="344" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="338" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and said mayor and aldermen shall choose or elect a clerk, a mar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />shal, and such other officers and subordinates as they may deem necessary to carry into effect the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the mayor, aldermen, clerk, marshal, and other officers appointed under this act, before enter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing upon the duties of their respective offices shall take and sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribe an oath to perform the duties thereof to the best of their skill and ability, which oath may be taken by the mayor before any per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son legally authorized to administer an oath; and by each of the other officers before the mayor.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the said mayor and alder<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men shall be invested with the following powers, viz:&#8212;First, They shall have authority to make and pass all by-laws and ordinances not repugnant to, or violative of the Constitution and laws of this State and those of the United States, which they may deem neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary for the good government of the city, its tranquility, safety and health. Secondly, They shall have authority to assess and collect a license tax, in all cases where the State has done the same; and also to assess and collect a tax on all property taxable by the State; but in no instance to exceed one half the amount imposed by the State. Thirdly, They shall have authority to establish ferries, build levies, wharves and landings, fix the rates, fees, and rents of the same, establish free schools, erect public buildings for the use of the city, pave and improve the streets, and sell and dispose of any property belonging to the city, for the benefit thereof. Fourthly, They shall have authority to organize a patrol or city guard, and also to call out the citizens for the defence of the place whenever they be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lieve it is necessary to the safety thereof: Fifthly, They shall have authority to impose and collect fines for a breach or violation of the city ordinances, and the money thus obtained shall be placed, with other funds, in the Treasury of the corporation: Provided, that said city, under no circumstances, shall impose or collect a fine to ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed ten dollars for any violation of the city ordinances whatever.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the mayor to preside at the meetings of the council; but, in case of his absence, the board of aldermen shall have power to choose one of their own body to preside; and their acts shall be as valid, at such meetings, as if the mayor was present.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted. That the mayor shall convene the board whenever required to do so by three of the aldermen; <pb n="345" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="339" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and any three of the aldermen, with the presiding officer, making a majority of the whole council, shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, and may do whatever a full board is capa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ble of doing; with the exception of the levying of taxes, which shall in all cases require a vote of two-thirds of the entire council.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the city council shall cause to be kept a record or journal of all its proceedings, judicial and legislative; that it may determine the compensation of the mayor, clerk, marshal, and all other officers and subordinates employed by them; and that when a vacancy occurs in any of said offices the council shall have authority to fill the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the clerk to keep a record of all the proceedings of the council, ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicial and legislative; and before entering upon the duties of his office he shall give bond, with good security, in such sum as the city council shall direct, payable to the Chief Justice of Webb county, and his successors in office.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the marshal and his deputies appointed by the council, to act as police officers, to preserve the quiet of the city, to execute the ordinances and judgments of the council, and to inform the mayor of all breaches committed against the city ordinances.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, The mayor shall also have au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thority (within the limits of the city,) to act as justice of the peace, that he shall he entitled to a commission as such from the Governor of the State, that he shall have the same jurisdiction, civil and criminal, shall perform the same duties, and be entitled to the same fees of other justices of the peace; and that he shall keep a docket of his judicial proceedings, and shall in all matters conform to, and be governed by the laws of the State establishing and regulating the Justice&#8217;s Court: Provided, that under no cir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cumstances, shall his authority extend beyond the chartered limits of the city.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Be it further enacted, That the first election for mayor and aldermen shall be held as soon as practicable after the passage of this act; that it shall be the duty of the justices of the peace, or either one of them in the city of Laredo, to ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />point a presiding officer, three judges and two clerks to hold said election, who shall be sworn to a faithful performance of their duties; and said presiding officer shall post up a written notice in three or more public places in the city, at least five <pb n="346" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="340" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>days before the election, of the time and place of holding the same, the polls for this purpose to be kept open from 10 o&#8217;clock, A. M. until 3 o&#8217;clock P. M., and after counting the votes in the pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ence of the three judges, the presiding officer shall cause a cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rect list thereof to be made out and signed by the judges; which list shall be sealed up and transmitted without delay to the Chief Justice, who shall thereupon give a certificate to the persons elected, who shall thereby be empowered to enter upon the duties of their office as soon as they qualify under the requirements of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. Be it further enacted, That immediately after entering upon the duties of their office, the city council shall lay off the city into six wards, and at all subsequent elections the mayor shall be elected by the joint ballot of all the wards; and each ward shall he entitled to elect one alderman, and no more.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. Be it further enacted, That the council shall decide upon the best manner of conducting its elections, as well as upon the places and time of keeping open the polls; always giving ten days notice of each election by posting advertisements in each ward, and by publication in one of the newspapers printed in the city.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. Be it further enacted, That the regular election for mayor and aldermen shall be annually, on the second Monday of December; and in case the office of mayor, or that of an alderman should become vacant, it shall be the duty of the council to order an election to fill the vacancy; and in case of the vacancy of the entire council, it shall be the duty of the Chief Justice of the county to order an election to fill the vacancies, in accordance with the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. Be it further enacted. That the officers elected at the first election shall hold their offices until the first day of January, 1849; nevertheless, it shall be the duty of the council to order an election for mayor and aldermen on the second Monday of De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cember, 1848; and the officers elected on that day, as well as at all the regular annual elections, shall hold their offices for twelve months from the first day of January next succeeding the election, or until their successors are qualified.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. Be it further enacted, That in all elections ordered by the council, the returns thereof shall be made to the clerk, whose duty it shall be to open them, in the presence of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cil; and he shall make an entry of the same in his journals, and issue certificates of election to the candidates elected.</p>
<pb n="347" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="341" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 18. Be it further enacted, That no person shall be eligible to any office, or entitled to vote for city officers, unless he shall be a citizen of the State, twenty-one years of age, and shall have re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sided in the city six months.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. Be it further enacted, That no election shall be contest<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed by any person unless within ten days after the holding of the same; and any person intending to contest shall cause the person having the certificate of election to be notified thereof, at least three days before the time he intends to appear and contest the election, and shall cause a statement in writing to be delivered to him by the city marshal or his deputy, stating the grounds upon which he relies to sustain the contest; and in case the candidate can not be found, then the notice and statement shall be left at his usual place of residence; and in all cases of contested elections, the city council shall have power to determine as to the legality and number of votes, or any other grounds upon which said contest may be made, and decide upon the candidate entitled to a certificate of election.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. Be it further enacted, That this act shall be in force and take effect from its passage, and that all laws conflicting with the provisions thereof, be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 29, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 177.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the town of Bonham, in the county of Fannin.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the citizens of the town of Bonham be, and they are hereby declared, a body corporate, by the name and title of the Incorporation of the Town of Bonham, and by that name may sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, and may hold and dispose of real and personal estate in said town.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the limits of said corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration shall include one half mile square, so laid off that the <pb n="348" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="342" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>public square of said town shall be in the centre of said corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That an election shall he held in said town, on the first Monday in March, in each and every year, for a mayor, a constable, a treasurer and four aldermen: the first election to be conducted by the Chief Justice of Fannin county, and every subsequent election to be conducted by the mayor, or a ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jority of the aldermen, acting at the time of such election; and the persons elected shall continue in office one year, or until their suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessors are duly qualified.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That whenever a vacancy shall occur in the office of mayor, a majority of the aldermen acting shall order and conduct an election to fill such vacancy; and the person so elected shall hold the office until the next regular elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, or until his successor shall be duly qualified.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That no person shall be eligible to the office of mayor or aldermen, unless a citizen of said town, and a householder or owner of real estate therein, and no person shall be eligible to the office of constable or treasurer, unless such person be a citizen of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the mayor shall be president of the board of aldermen; that three of members of said board, includ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the mayor, shall constitute a quorum to transact business, and that said board may enact such by-laws for the government of said town, not inconsistent with the Constitution and laws of this State, as may be deemed proper, and may inflict fines for disobedience of the same, not exceeding twenty dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That the board of aldermen shall have and exercise control over the public square and streets in said town, and may compel all free male citizens, ministers of the Gos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pel excepted, over the age of twenty-one and under forty-five years, to work on the same: Provided, That such persons shall not be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to work more than ten days in any one year, and they shall be exempt from other road duty in said county; and the board may impose such fines on defaulters as they may deem necessary, in which the board shall be governed by the law of this State regulat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing roads.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the board of aldermen shall have power to levy a tax on all persons and property, both real and personal, in said town, subject to taxation by the laws of this State: Provided, that the tax on property shall not, in any <pb n="349" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="343" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>one year, exceed one half of one per cent., ad valorem, on such property, and no tax shall be levied unless by two-thirds of the members present, which shall be assessed and collected by the constable in the same manner as the State tax is collected; and the board also shall have power to levy and collect a tax on any race track, billiard table, or ten pin alley which may be in said town.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That the board of aldermen shall have power to appoint such additional officers, with the regulation of their duties and compensation, as may be necessary, and may require of them bond with security to the mayor in such penalty as may be deemed requisite to compel the efficient discharge of such duties as may be assigned them.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That all offences, against the by-laws be prosecuted before the mayor, and governed by the law organizing Justices&#39; courts; and the constable shall execute and return all writs issued by the mayor, in the same manner as is provided by law, defining the duties of constables.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That in case of the death, resig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nation, or removal of any alderman, treasurer or constable, the mayor shall order an election, under such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the board, to fill such vacancy.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Be it further enacted, That the constable shall give bond and security as required of other constables; shall have the same power and entitled to the same fees, for similar services.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. Be it further enacted, That the mayor of said town, shall be entitled to such fees as may be allowed justices of the peace for similar services; together with such other compensation as may be allowed him by two-thirds of the aldermen present, at the time of such allowance.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. Be it further enacted, That the aldermen shall be entitled to such compensation as may be allowed them by the board: Provided, in no case shall the same exceed two dollars per day, for each day they may be required to sit such alder<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. Be it further enacted, That the treasurer shall keep safely all the money of said corporation; shall pay out the same upon the order of the board, and shall do such other duties as may be assigned him by the by-laws. He shall give bond with security, payable to the mayor in such sum as may be deemed proper, conditioned for the faithful performance of his duties, to <pb n="350" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="344" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>be approved by the board, and shall be allowed such compensa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion as may be allowed, from time to time, to county treasurers.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. Be it further enacted, That the mayor be, and he is hereby invested, with all the powers and jurisdiction of a justice of the peace, within the limits of said town.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. Be it further enacted, That the books and records of the incorporation shall, at all reasonable times, be open to the examination of any citizen of said town or property-holder therein desiring the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. Be it further enacted, That this act be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 2, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 178.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to remove the disability of minority from William Stean, Jnn&#8217;r, so as to enable him to receive his portion of the estate of his deceased parents.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the disability of minority attached to William Stean, Jr., be, and the same is hereby removed, and he is fully and legally vested with the right to apply for and receive the portion of prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty left him by his deceased parents, and use and dispose of the same as fully and completely as though he were of full age.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 2, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="351" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="345" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 179.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate and establish Guadalupe College.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That a school of learning be, and the same is hereby estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished at the town of Guadalupe, Guadalupe county, to be known as the Guadalupe College.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That there shall be five Trus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tees of said College, to take charge of and superintend its interest, and a majority of whom shall constitute a quorum to do business.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the following named per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons be, and they are hereby declared to be the Trustees of said College, to wit: Hon. William E. Jones, Hon. Michael Erskine, Dr. I. E. Park, Joseph F. Johnson, and Martin B. Lewis.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the aforesaid trustees be, and they are hereby constituted a body politic and corporate in deed and in law, by the name of the President and Trustees of Guadalupe College; and by that name they and their successors may and shall have perpetual succession, and be able and capable in law, to receive, have, and enjoy to them and their successors, lands, tenements, hereditaments of any kind in fee or for life, or for years, and personal property of any kind whatsoever, and all sums of money which may be given, granted or bequeathed to them for the purpose of promoting the interest of the said college.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That there shall be a stated meet<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing of the Board of Trustees in each year, at the time of conferring degrees; and that the President of said Board of Trustees shall have full power to call an occasional meeting of the Board whenever it shall appear to him necessary; and a majority of the Board shall have authority to call occasional meetings, whenever they shall think it necessary to do so.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the Trustees of said Col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lege may and shall have a common seal, for the business of themselves and their successors, with liberty to alter or change the same from time to time, as they shall think proper; and that by their aforesaid name, they and their successors, may and shall be able to sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, answer and be answered, defend and be defended in all courts of law and <pb n="352" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="346" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>equity in this State: and to grant, bargain, and sell, or assign any lands, tenements, goods, or chattles, now belonging to said Col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lege, or that may hereafter belong to the same; to construct all the necessary buildings for said institution; to establish a Pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />paratory Department; to organize, establish and control a separate department, and school for females, and such dependent institu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions as they shall deem necessary, in furtherance of the object of this act; to have the management of the finances; the privilege of electing their own officers; of appointing all necessary commit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tees; and to act and do all things whatsoever for the benefit of the said institution, in as ample a manner as any person or body politic or corporate may and can do by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That the said Trustees shall have the power of prescribing the course of studies to be pursued by the students, and of framing and enacting all such ordinances and by<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />laws, as shall appear to them necessary for the good government of said college, and for their own proceedings: Provided always, that the same be in accordance with the Constitution of the United States and the State of Texas,</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the head of said College shall be styled the President, and the instructors thereof, the Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fessors; and the President and Professors or a majority of them, the Faculty of Guadalupe College; which faculty shall have power of enforcing the ordinances and by-laws adopted by the Trustees for the government of the students, by rewarding or censuring them, and finally by suspending such of them as, after repeated admonitions, shall continue disobedient or refractory, until a de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />termination of a quorum of Trustees can be had; but it shall be only in the power of a quorum of Trustees to expel any student or students of the said College.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That the Trustees shall have full power, by the faculty of said College to grant or confer such degree or degrees in the arts and sciences to the students of said College, and to other persons worthy thereof, as are usually granted and conferred in other colleges, and to give certificates thereof, or diplomas, signed by them and sealed with the common seal of the trustees of the college, to authenticate and perpetuate the mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ory of such graduations,</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That whenever any vacancy shall occur in the board of Trustees, either by death, resignation, or expulsion for cause, such vacancy or vacancies shall be filled by the remaining trustees.</p>
<pb n="353" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="347" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That all necessary officers of said college shall be appointed by a majority of the Board of Trus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tees, viz: the faculty and minor officers; and that said officers shall always be subject to removal by the appointing power for cause.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Be it further enacted, That the salaries of all officers connected with the college, shall be fixed by a majority of the Board of Trustees.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. Be it further enacted, That the Guadalupe College shall be purely literary and scientific; and the students of all religious denominations shall enioy equal advantages.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 5, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 180.</head>
<opener>
<salute>To authorize the City of Galveston to appoint Firemen and to exempt the same from militia and jury duty.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Mayor and City Council of the City of Galveston, may, and they are hereby authorized to appoint and enrol such number of Firemen, and to appoint and commission such number of officers to command the said Firemen as they may deem suffi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cient to protect the property in the City of Galveston from de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struction by fire.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That each Fireman and officer (thus appointed by the Mayor and City Council of the City of Gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veston,) while doing duty as a Fireman in said city, shall be exempt from serving on any jury, and from all Militia duty, (except dur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing insurrection, rebellion, or invasion) provided, that there shall not be appointed more than forty Firemen for each Engine or Hook, and Ladder Truck and Apparatus, and twenty for each Hose Cart, procured and used by said City for the extinguishment of fires.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That said Firemen when form<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed into companies shall have the right to make their own by<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="354" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="348" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>laws, not inconsistent with the laws and Constitution of the State, for their better guidance and regulation, provided, the same are first approved by the said City Council.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>February 7, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 181.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of John Keiser.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a patent to John Keiser for one third of a league of land by virtue of certificate No. 670, issued to him by the Board of Land Commissioners for the county of Brazoria, on the 12th day of July A. D. 1838, which cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate was through mistake recommended by the Board of Trav<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />elling Commissioners in the name of John Reiser;&#8212;This act to take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 9, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 182.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the 11th section of an act to incorporate the Brazos Canal Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the 11th section of an act to incorporate the Brazos Canal Company, passed by the sixth Congress of the late Republic of Texas, and approved January 3d, 1842, be, and the same is hereby repealed, and the following be substi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tuted in place of said 11th section, to wit: That that the said <pb n="355" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="349" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Brazos Canal Company shall be allowed until 1st January, 1853, to complete and render navigable said canal, from the Brazos river to San Luis bay, twenty years after which time, the State of Texas shall have the right to purchase at par, the whole of the capital stock of said company; provided, that if the State does not pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chase said stock within twelve months after the expiration of the said twenty years, then this charter shall be considered as renewed, for the next ensuing twenty years, at the expiration of which sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ond term of twenty years, the Canal shall belong to the State of Texas, and all the rights of regulating the tolls on the Canal, which belonged to the Congress of the Republic of Texas, under the act of incorporation and amendment, shall accrue and hereafter be vested in the Legislature of the State of Texas.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 10, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 183.</head>
<opener>
<salute>For the relief of the heirs of Jeremiah Bowlin.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, by an error of the records of the Travelling Board of Land Commissioners, the head right certificate of Jeremiah Bowlin of the County of Shelby, was miscalled James Bowlin; whereby the heirs of the said Jeremiah Bowlin, are deprived of their just rights and are without legal remedy; Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to issue a patent to the heirs of the said Jeremiah Bowlin, deceased, upon said certificate, in the same manner as though no such error had been committed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 12, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="356" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="350" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 184.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to legalize the marriage of Rhesa Green Stalcup and Mary Ann Miller.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the rites of matrimony heretofore celebrated between Rhesa Green Stalcup and Mary Ann Miller, be, and the same are hereby declared to be as valid in law as though no legal disability had existed thereto at the time of the celebration of said marriage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 21, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 185.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to legitimate Maria Malicia Stalcup and render her capable of taking by descent, the estate or estates of her parents Rhesa Green Stalcup and Mary Ann Stalcup.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Mary Malicia Stalcup, he deemed and declared to be the legitimate child of Rhesa Green Stalcup and Mary Ann Stalcup, and she is hereby rendered capable of taking by descent the estate or estates of her parents; any disability existing at the time of her birth to the contrary notwithstanding.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 21, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 186.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution requiring the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue a patent in the name of the heirs of William P. Nunn, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the Board of Land Commissioners of Washington County, issued on the 19th of July, 1845, to John B. Nunn, as <pb n="357" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="351" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>administrator of William P. Nunn, deceased, a certificate for three hundred and twenty acres of land numbered 256, which the Clerk of said Board failed to record and report to the General Land office; and whereas, a certificate of the same date and number, is duly recorded and reported to the General Land Office in the name of Ealph W. Fuller; and, whereas it appears that the Clerk in re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cording the same by mistake, numbered the certificate of the said Nunn, in the same number of the said Fuller, for which reason a patent cannot according to law be issued upon the first named cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate: Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office is hereby directed to issue a patent in the name of the heirs of William P. Nunn, upon the certificate issued as above specified in the name of John B. Nunn, as administrator of William P. Nunn, deceased, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 22, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 187.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution making an appropriation for the payment of the pro rata pay due E. W. Moore, Post Captain Commanding late Texas Navy, under the provisions of an act of Congress of the Republic of Texas, approved 5th February, 1844.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the pro rata pay due E. W. Moore, Post Captain Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />manding the late Navy of Texas, having been suspended on the ground that he was supposed to be a defaulter to the Govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, which cause no longer exists, Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller is hereby required to pay E. W: Moore, Post Captain Commanding the late Navy of Texas, the amount of pro rata pay due him, under the provisions of the act of Congress of the Republic of Texas, approved, February <pb n="358" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="352" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>5th, 1844, appropriating &#8220;sixteen thousand dollars, to be paid pro rata to the officers of the Navy&#8221; and an appropriation is hereby made, sufficient to cover the same, which shall be paid out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That the Comptroller in ascer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />taining the amount of pro rata pay due E. W. Moore, Post Captain. Commanding late Texas Navy, is hereby required to be governed by the rule under which the other officers of the Navy were paid their pro rata pay, under the provisions of the act of Congress of the Republic of Texas above recited.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further resolved, That the sum of twelve hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and fifty dollars, shall be paid at this time, and the balance of two thousand three hundred and twenty-five dollars and thirty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nine cents shall be paid at any time after the first of February, A. D. 1849, and that this Joint Resolution take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 23, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 188.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution on behalf of Edward A. Weyman, a resident citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zen of the county of Nueces, and State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Edward A. Weyman, a resident citizen of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty of Nueces, and State of Texas, was, in the year one thousand eight hundred and forty-seven, engaged as a merchant in said county, in conformity with the laws of the State of Texas; and whereas, Giles Porter, acting as commandant of the post, at Brazos Santiago, did by military force, eject the said Weyman, from his own premises, and deprive him of the whole amount of his goods, wares and merchandize; and whereas the said Wey<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man, in order to perpetuate the testimony of the injuries done him as aforesaid, as well as to ascertain the amount of the damages sustained thereby, obtained a judgment at the Fall Term of the District Court in the county of Nueces against the said Giles Porter, after personal notice served, for the sum of fifteen thousand dollars; and whereas the said Giles <pb n="359" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="353" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Porter, is beyond the control of the Judicial tribunals of this State, and has no known property within the same, leaving the said Wey<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man in consequence, without remedy, by final process, against the said Giles Porter. Therefore,</p>
<p>Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor be requested to apply to the Government of the United States, for indemnity, to the amount of the damages as ascertained by the judgment aforesaid on behalf of the said Edward A. Wey<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 24, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 189.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of William Plucker.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office is hereby authorized and required to issue to William Plucker, assignee of John D. G. Varrelman, a patent for one labor of land upon certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate No. 530, first class, issued by the Board of Land Commissioners for Nacogdoches County, provided, the survey of said labor has been made according to law, and provided all government dues have been paid.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this Joint Resolution be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 26, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="360" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="354" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 190.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the opening and construction of a Turnpike Road from the City of Houston to the Brazos River.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That William E. Crump, and his associates be, and he is hereby authorized to survey, construct and open a Turnpike road to run from the City of Houston to the Brazos Biver, and one mile on the West side of said river, provided, the tolls hereafter estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished in this act, shall in no wise prohibit said Crump and his as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sociates from charging the same rates of ferriage, customary at other ferries on said river.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the said William E. Crump, shall have the right of way over any vacant and unappropriated public land through which said road may pass, and which may be necessary for the construction of said road, and keeping the same in good order.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the said Crump, with the consent of the owners of the soil through which said road may pass, is required to make a road not less than eighteen feet wide, and when he may deem it necessary, to cut ditches and make bridges across all shallow streams, and causeway such parts of swamp as he may deem expedient, so that the said Turnpike shall be at all times passable and in good order.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That said Crump is authorized, so soon as said road is completed to collect and receive the following rates of toll, to wit: for each vehicle, not to exceed twenty-five cents per wheel; for each horse or mule and rider ten cents; and for all loose horses, mules, or cattle, five cents per head.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That said Crump may erect as many Turnpike gates as he may think proper, without the corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rate limits of the City of Houston, but shall only charge the same person or persons, at one of said gates, provided, they shall have the right of charging the above rates, as well for a part of the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tance of said road, as for the whole distance.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That if any person or persons shall travel upon said road, or drive any waggon, or loose horse or horses or cattle upon said road without paying the toll above allowed or shall injure in any manner the said Turnpike <pb n="361" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="355" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>road, a right of action shall accrue to said Crump, and a suit may be instituted therefor before any Court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That the said Crump shall, by this act be entitled, either by him, his agent or assigns to receive the rates of toll herein allowed for the term of twenty-five years from and after the passage of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That should said Crump fail to complete said road as herein contemplated within five years from the passage of this act, then this act shall be null and void.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, Tnat this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 26, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 191.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Incorporate the Town of Montgomery.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the citizens of the town of Montgomery, in Mont<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gomery county, be, and they are hereby, declared a body politic and corporate, under the name and style of the Corporation of the Town of Montgomery, who shall have the power of suing and being sued, pleading, and being impleaded, and to hold property real and personal within the limits of said corporation, and at their pleasure to dispose of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the corporate limits of said town shall extend one half mile in every direction from the Centre of the public square.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the Chief Justice of the county, to order an election to be held as early as practicable, after the passage of this act, upon giving ten days notice thereof, for the election of one Mayor and six Aldermen, a Collector or Constable, Treasurer and Secretary, who shall hold their offices for the term of one year from the time of their election. In case a vacancy occur by death, resignation or otherwise, the vacancy for the unexpired term shall be filled <pb n="362" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="356" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>by a new election, as follows: in case of vacancy in the office of mayor, then the election to be conducted by a quorum of alder<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men; but in case of vacancy in the board of aldermen, collector, secretary or treasurer, then the election shall be conducted by the mayor. All persons residing within the corporation shall be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled to a vote for the above named officers, who are eligible to vote for members of Congress.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the mayor and two-thirds of the aldermen shall constitute a board to transact business.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the collector, treasurer and secretary, shall give bond to the mayor and his successors in office, in such sum, and with such securities, as shall be approved by the mayor and board of aldermen, and that all officers elected by virtue of this act, before entering upon the duties of their office, shall take and subscribe an oath for the faithful performance of the du<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of their respective offices.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the mayor to cause an election to be held, annually, at least ten days before the expiration of his term of office, for mayor, aldermen, collector, treasurer and secretary, who shall enter upon the duties of their offices respectively, upon the expiration of the term of their predecessors.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That the mayor shall have juris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diction, and exercise the powers of a Justice of the Peace over all the offences committed against the ordinances and decrees of the mayor and board of aldermen, within the limits of the corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted. That the mayor and aldermen shall have power to pass such ordinances and decrees as they shall deem necessary for establishing schools, and support of education; for the regulation of the police, and the preservation of order; to prescribe penalties; to levy taxes for the removal of nuisances, keep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing streets in order, and for such other purposes, as the board may deem proper and necessary within the limits of said town: Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that such ordinances and decrees shall not conflict with the Constitution and Laws of this State.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 26, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="363" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="357" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 192.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the widow and heirs at law of Major James L. Holmes, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the certificate for one league and one labor of land, issued on the fifth day of July, A. D. 1838, by the Board of Land Commissioners for the county of Washington, to Willet Holmes and J. B. Robertson, as the administrators of James L. Holmes, de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceased, be, and the same is hereby declared a just and genuine claim against the government of Texas; and the Commissioner Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral of the Land Office is hereby authorized and required to issue a patent or patents as in other cases on said certificate to Ann Holmes, surviving widow of said deceased, for the benefit of herself and the heirs at law of said deceased.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 1, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 193.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the heirs of Patrick Reels.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the certificate granted to Patrick Reels by the Board of Land Commissioners of Colorado county, for one-half league and one labor of land, shall be as good and valid as if said certi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficate had been recommended for the full amount of land, by the travelling Board of Land Commissioners; and the Commissioner of the General Land Office is hereby, authorized and required to is<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sue a patent thereon to the heirs of said Reels.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 1, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="364" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="358" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 194.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize Sarah Ann Kelton, wife of Oliver P. Kelton, a lunatic, to make valid conveyances of her real estate and ne<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />groes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Sarah Ann Kelton, wife of Oliver P. Kelton, a lunatic, be, and she is hereby authorized to sell and convey her separate property, consisting of real estate and negroes, and otherwise to transact business as a feme sole, and all acts hereafter performed by the said Sarah Ann Kelton, in reference to the management or sale of her separate property, are hereby declared to be valid, any laws or parts of laws to the contrary notwithstanding.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 1, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 195.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Jesse H. Cartwright.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, it appears that the Board of Land Commissioners for Fort Bend County, in 1838, issued to Jesse H. Cartwright, as assignee of Robert F. Roberts, a certificate for one league and one labor of land, on proper proof: And whereas, it appears that by an error of the clerk of said Board in making his record, the Board of Travelling Commissioners recommended said certificate for one-third of a league only:&#8212;Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to J. H. Cartwright a patent or patents, by virtue of certificate No. 219, 2nd class, issued to said Cartwright by the Board of Land Commissioners for Fort Bend county for one league and one labor of land.</p>
<pb n="365" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="359" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 2, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 196.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing Charles Covington and his Associates, to es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tablish a ferry across the river Yegua, and construct a cause<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />way across the bottom lands thereof.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Charles Covington and such Associates, as he may choose, be, and they are hereby, authorized to establish a ferry across the river Yegna, and construct a causeway across the bottom lands of said stream: Provided, The same shall be done with the consent of the owners of the land where said ferry shall be es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tablished, and over which said causeway shall pass.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the ferry and causeway shall be completed before the expiration of two years from the passage of this act, or all the privileges herein conferred shall be forfeited.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the County Court of Burle<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son county shall have the power to regulate the rates of toll and ferriage, to be collected by said Charles Covington, his Associates and successors, and the privilegs of this act shall enure to the above named Charles Covington, his Associates and successors, for fifteen years from the passage thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That alter the expiration of the aforesaid time of fifteen years, it shall and may be lawful for the County Court of Burleson county, to extend the privileges herein granted to any term of years, not exceeding ten, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 1, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="366" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="360" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 197.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the town of Springfield.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the citizens of the town of Springfield in Limestone county be, and they are hereby declared a body corporate and pol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />itic, under the name and style of the corporation of the town of Springfield, who shall have the power of suing and being sued, pleading and being impleaded, and to hold and dispose of prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty, both real and personal, within the limits of said corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That all that tract of land (con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />taining five hundred acres,) heretofore surveyed by A. McNeill, and known as the town tract shall be the limits and boundaries of said town.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the Chief Justice of the county, to order an election to be held, as early as practicable after the passage of this act, upon giving ten days notice thereof, for the election of one mayor and six alder<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men, a collector or constable, a treasurer, and secretary, who shall hold their offices for the term of one year from the time of their election. In case a vacancy occur, by death, resignation or other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise, the vacancy for the unexpired term shall be filled by new election as follows: in case of vacancy in the office of mayor, then the election to be conducted by a quorum of the board of aldermen; but in case of vacancy in the board of aldermen, collector, treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer, or secretary, then the election shall be conducted by the may<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />or. All persons residing within the corporation shall be entitled to a vote for the above named officers, who are eligible to vote for members of the Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the mayor and two-thirds of the board of aldermen shall constitute a board to transact busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the collector, treasurer, and secretary, shall give bond in such sum, and with such securities, as shall be approved by the mayor and board of aldermen, and that all officers elected by virtue of this act, before entering upon the duties of their office, shall take and subscribe an oath, for the faithful discharge of the duties of their respective offices.</p>
<pb n="367" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="361" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the mayor to cause an election to be held annually, at least ten days be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore the expiration of his term of office for all the officers men<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned in the third section of this act, who shall enter upon the duties of their offices respectively upon the expiration of the term of their predecessors.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That the mayor shall have juris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diction and exercise the powers of a justice of the peace, over all offences committed against the ordinances and decrees of the mayor and aldermen within the limits of the corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the mayor and aldermen shall have power to pass such ordinances and decrees as they may think necessary, for the establishing schools and support of educa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, for the regulating of the police and preservation of order; to prescribe penalties; to levy taxes for the removal of nuisances; keep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the streets in order, and such other purposes as the board may deem necessary and proper, within the corporate limits of said town: Provided, such ordinances and decrees, shall not conflict with the laws and Constitution of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 1, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 198.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the second section of an act for the incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration of the town of Paris, the county seat of Lamar county, approved February 3d, 1845.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the second section of an act for the incorporation of the town of Paris, the county seat of Lamar county, be and the same is so amended, as to read thus: That the citizens of the cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration of the town of Paris, shall have all the benefits and priv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ileges, and in all respects be governed by the provisions of an act incorporating the town of Bonham, in the county of Fannin, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved, February 2d, 1848.</p>
<pb n="368" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="362" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 2, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 199.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of J. W. E. Wallace.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the claim of Joseph W. E. Wallace, for six thousand five hundred and forty-three dollars, for goods furnished the Texas Army on the Colorado in the spring of 1836, be and the same is hereby acknowledged, as a good and valid claim against the late Republic of Texas, and to be ranked among the outstanding liabili<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That the vouchers and evidence of said claim shall be deposited in the Comptroller&#8217;s office, and that this resolution take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 8, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 200.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to establish the University of Eastern Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That S. W. Blound, L. V. Greer, J. D. Thomas, L. Randall, J. P. Henderson, Wm. Garrett, M. Cartwright, D. O. Warren, E. Price, Wm. H. Slaughter, C. Payne, F. G. Roberts, B. Rush Wallace, O. M. Roberts, and J. M. Rankin, be, and they are hereby incorporated and made a body politic in law and equity, under the name and style of &#8220;The President and Trustees of the University of Eastern Texas,&#8221; to be located in the town and county of San Augustine, and have a common <pb n="369" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="363" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>seal, with the power of changing the same at pleasure, be capable of suing and being sued, of pleading and being impleaded, of hold<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing property, real, personal and mixed, by deed, gift, devise or otherwise; of selling, alienating and conveying the same at pleas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ure, and of doing whatever else may be necessary to be done for the benefit and advantage of said Institution, that is not contrary to the laws and Constitution of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this charter, and the privi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />leges conferred by it, shall extend to said Trustees and their suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessors in office, as long as they may be engaged in the promotion of education and the diffusion of useful knowledge, as herein con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />templated.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That there shall not be more than three members of any one religious denomination in said Board at the same time, and that seven of said Board, and the President, shall constitute a quorum to transact business.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That hereafter, this body cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate shall consist of fifteen Trustees, from among whom they shall choose a President and Vice President, and when vacancies therein may occur, they shall be filled by said Board.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the President, Vice Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent, and other officers, shall annually be elected by said Board.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That, without the approval of the President or presiding officer no act shall be passed, nor reso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lution be adopted, except by the concurrence of two-thirds of the members present; unless two-thirds of the whole Board of Trustees shall be present at the time, in which event, the acts and resolu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions of a majority of those present shall be valid.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That if the President of the Board of Trustees be absent, the Vice President thereof, when he may deem it necessary, shall have power to call a special meeting of said Board, and may exercise all the powers vested in the Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent, and in the absence of both, should the necessity of the case demand it, two-thirds of their Board, by calling one of their num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber to the chair, shall have power to transact all such business as the entire Board, except in cases hereafter provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the Faculty of said Uni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />versity shall consist of a President and such number of Profes<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sors as the Board may deem necessary, all of whom shall be competent, and possess the necessary qualifications in every <pb n="370" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="364" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>particular, to take charge of such department in said University, as the board of Trustees may designate.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That in electing a President of said University, or any of the Professors therein, there shall be present the President or Vice president of the Board of Trustees, and at least two-thirds of the other members thereof, and a con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />currence of a majority of all the Board shall be necessary to elect a President or Professor of said University.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That the Trustees or said Uni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />versity, whenever they may deem it necessary, may add to said Institution the department of Law and Medicine.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That the Trustees and Faculty of said Institution shall have the power of granting diplomas, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferring degrees and of doing whatever else they may deem neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary for the promotion of education and for the diffusion of useful knowledge: Provided, it be not inconsistent with, nor repugnant to the Constitution and laws of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Be it further enacted, That the present Trustees and their successors, shall, before entering upon the duties of their offices, each take and subscribe the following oath: &#8220;I will en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />deavor well and truly to discharge the duties, incumbent on me as a Trustee of the University of Eastern Texas, in accordance with the charter of said Institution, without partiality for any particu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lar denomination of Christians or party in politics.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 13. Be it further enacted, That said Board of Trustees shall be, and they are hereby, authorized to establish in said town a Female Seminary of Learning, to be styled &#8220;The Female Insti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tute of San Augustine,&#8221; and shall have and exercise such power and control over the same, as they may over the University of Eastern Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. Be it further enacted, That the Board of Trustees may, for the Female Institute aforesaid, have the same power to receive property by devise, gift or otherwise, and may purchase and sell property, real, personal and mixed, in the same manner therefor as they may for the University aforesaid, and may provide a seal, confer degrees, and do and perform every act necessary for the promotion of female education, as fully as is provided herein for the University aforesaid.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. Be it further enacted, That said Board of Trustees shall have, and are hereby, vested with full and ample power to <pb n="371" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="365" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>make by-laws for the government of said University and Female Institute, and of the students of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. Be it further enacted, That this act of incorporation of said University and Female Institute, shall be taken notice of by all the Courts of this State, without being specially pleaded.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. Be it further enacted, That the property, real, personal and mixed, now belonging to the University of San Augustine, be, and the same is hereby transferred to the Board of Trustees of the University of Eastern Texas aforesaid, and that the University of Eastern Texas be vested with, and entitled to, all the rights, priv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ileges, and immunities whatsoever hitherto enjoyed by said Uni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />versity of San Augustine; and that the act incorporating the said University of San Augustine, be, and the same is hereby repealed; and that this act have effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 8, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 201.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the Relief of Ann Terrell, widow and relict of George W. Terrell, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Treasurer of the State be authorized and required to pay to Ann Terrell, widow of George W. Terrell, deceased, the sum of one thousand one hundred and sixty-seven dollars, it being the balance due said G. W. Terrell, as Charge d&#8217;Affaire of the late Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public of Texas to the kingdom of Great Britain: Provided, That five hundred dollars only shall be paid upon the passage of this act, and the balance at any time after the first day of January, 1849.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 9, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="372" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="366" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 202.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the several acts, incorporating the City of Houston.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That in case of the inability of the Mayor of the city of Houston, to perform his duties by reason of absence, refusal or other cause, or in the event of a vacancy in said office, occasioned by death, resignation or otherwise, the Board of Aldermen of said city, may be and they are hereby authorized and empowered to ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />point from their own body a presiding officer, who shall be Mayor pro tem, and shall have and may exercise all the powers conferred by law on the Mayor, and shall perform all the duties thereof, until his return, the removal of such inability, or a successor is elected and qualified, provided, that in case of a vacancy in said of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fice, the city council may order an election upon ten days notice, to fill such vacancy for the unexpired term.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That whenever any order, reso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lution, by-law or ordinance may be passed by the council, and is disagreed to by the Mayor, it shall be inoperative, unless the same shall be passed by a vote of a majority of the whole number of Aldermen, taken by yeas and nays and recorded upon the journal of their proceedings.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the Mayor and City Council, by a vote of a majority of the whole number of the Aldermen, taken by yeas and nays, and entered upon their journal, may assess and collect an annual direct tax, upon all property, real and per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonal, situate and being within the limits of the corporation, not exceeding one fifth of one per centum, advalorem, and shall have power to assess, and collect for the use of the city, an annual license tax, upon all persons pursuing a vocation or calling, upon which a license tax may be imposed by law, provided however, such tax shall in no case exceed said license tax, and provided further, that the said tax shall be imposed in the same ratio of the said license tax.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That every person or persons, on whom or whose vocation a license tax, may have been as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sessed, shall, before engaging in such vocation, pay to the city Assessor and Collector, the amount of such tax, taking his re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceipt therefor, which receipt shall entitle him, her or them to a <pb n="373" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="367" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>corresponding license, to be issued by the Mayor. If any person or persons shall engage in any vocation, within the limits of the city, on whom or which a license tax had been assessed by the city council without having first obtained a license therefor from the Mayor, such person or persons, shall be liable to pay one fourth of the amount of such annual license tax for each week, he, she or they may be so engaged and in the same proportion for each day, which may be recovered by action before the recorder or any Jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tice of the Peace, or the District Court, according to the amount; one fourth part of the recovery, for the use of the informer and the balance to the city.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That after the expiration of the time prescribed by law, for the payment of city taxes, the Asses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sor and Collector for the city, or such officer as the City Council may charge therewith, may proceed to seize upon any property, real or personal, the tax on which has not been paid or that be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />longs to a delinquent tax payer, and after advertising the same, in some newspaper published in the city of Houston, or by posting at three public places, in said city, if there be no newspaper pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished as aforesaid, for twenty days, specifying the time and place of sale, may sell at the court house door, of Harris county, to the highest bidder for cash, so much of said property as will pay the taxes thereon or may be due from such delinquent, as the case may be, together with costs of advertising and selling, unless the taxes and costs be paid before the day of sale. If the sales should not be completed on the day appointed, the Assessor and Collector may adjourn the sales from day to day until they are all completed.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That at the conclusion of the sales, and on compliance with the terms thereof, by a purchaser, the Assessor and Collector shall give to such purchaser, a certificate of purchase stating the amount of tax and costs paid, and describing the property sold, which shall entitle the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chaser to a deed for said property, at the expiration of twelve months, from the Mayor of the city; but such certificate may be redeemed, within one year from the day of sale, by the owner of the property sold, or some person for them, by payment of double the amount of tax and costs paid by the holder; which payment may be made either to the city Treasurer for the use of the holder of such certificate or to the holder thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That if any certificate of pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="374" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="368" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>chase, given as before provided, be not redeemed within one year from the day of sale, then the holder may demand, and it shall be the duty of the Mayor of the city to give a deed, to such holder, conveying all the right and interest of the person in whose name the property is sold, and of the owner, in case of unknown or non resident owners, in and to the property specified in the certificate, on production and delivery of the certificate to him, such deed shall be signed by the Mayor in his official capacity and countersigned by the Secretary of the Council under the city seal.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the city shall not be held responsible on any implied warranty, or for any damages under any deed or sale made for taxes, but the person injured by any neglect or malfeasance of any officer, shall have recourse against him for any damage sustained in consequence thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That any tax deed made as re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired by this act, shall be prima facie evidence, that all the pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />requisites of the law have been complied with, and shall pass all the right of the person owning the property conveyed, unless it can be proven, that the tax thereon had been paid, before the sale, or the certificate of sale redeemed within the year aforesaid.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That the Assessor and Collector, shall, after his sales, make returns to the Council, of all property sold, and the names of the purchasers of each parcel of property, to whom certificates of purchase may be issued; which returns shall be preserved among the archives of the city.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That the Mayor and City Coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cil of Houston, shall have power to appropriate, so much of the revenues of the city emanating from whatever source to the im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />provement of the public market, roads, within or without the lim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />its of the corporation, leading to the city, as they, in their wisdom, may from time to time deem expedient.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Be it further enacted, That all process from the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corder, may be executed by the Sheriff, any Constable of the City, or the City Marshall in the same manner that similar process from Justices of the Peace is executed</p>
<p>Sec. 13. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 11, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="375" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="369" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 203.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act incorporating the Houston Mechanics Institute.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Martin K. Snell, President, James B. Hogan and J. C. Schell, Vice Presidents, Jno. N. O. Smith, corresponding Secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary, John W. Bergin, Recording Secretary, Thomas Martin, Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer, Librarian, William Gangawa, Thomas G. Green, J. R. Slocomb, William M. Barrett and S. W. Kemper, Directors; and George Henry, E. Simmler, Samuel Arnold, William H. King, H. Michels, A. Otto, F. Baumgarten, L. Brocke, G. W. Capron, J. L. Wilson, John Shea, S. L. Isaac, D. A. Smith, S. D. Staats, John P. Morris, W. Martin, S. A. Jones, James Strother, John S. Kennon, P. Brownfield, Philip Thompson, John McDermot, John Holcroft, John G. Berlin, and their successors in office, and their associate members of the Houston Mechanics Institute, be, and they are hereby declared to be a community corporate and body politic, and in the name, style, and title of the &#8220;Houston Mechanics Insti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tute,&#8221; they and their successors shall and may at all times be capa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ble in law to have, receive and retain to themselves and their suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessors, property, real, personal, and mixed; also, devises and be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quests of any person or persons, bodies corporate or politic, capable of making the same and the same at their pleasure, to transfer or dispose of, in such manner as they may think proper, provided al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ways: that the said corporation or body politic shall not at any time, bold or possess property, real, personal and mixed, exceeding in value the sum of fifty thousand dollars, and provided further: that if any real estate, over and above the value of fifty thousand dollars shall accrue to said Institute, by bequest, donation or otherwise, the term of one year shall be allowed the directors, or other competent offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers of the Institute, to dispose of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the said corporation and their successors, by the name, style and title aforesaid, shall be for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever capable in law to sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />swer and be answered unto, defend and be defended, in any court under or within the jurisdiction of the State, and before all Judges, officers, and other persons whomsoever, in all and singular actions, matters and demands whatsoever.</p>
<pb n="376" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="370" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That it shall and may be lawful for the said Mechanics Institute to have a common seal, and the same by the consent of a majority of the members present, at any regular semi-annual meeting, to alter or amend.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That it shall be lawful for the said Houston Mechanics Institute, to adopt such constitution, by-laws, rules and regulations for the internal government of the same, as may be deemed necessary and expedient; all of which shall have the same force and effect as this enactment, provided, however, that none of the same shall conflict with the Constitution of the State, or be in contravention of any of the statutory enactments of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That this act shall be in full force and effect, from and after its passage. Approved, March 11, 1848.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 204.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to establish the Galveston and Red River Railway Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That a body politic and corporate be, and the same is hereby created and established, under the name and style of the Galveston and Red River Railway Company, with capacity to make contracts, to have succession and a common seal, to make by-laws for its gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment, and in its said corporate name to sue and be sued, to grant and to receive, and generally to do and perform all such acts and things as may be necessary or proper for, or incident to the fulfil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of its obligations, or the maintenance of its rights under this act, and consistent with the provisions of the Constitution of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the said Company be, and hereby is invested with the right of making, owning and maintaining a railway from such point on Galveston Bay, or its contiguous waters, to such point upon Red River, between the eastern boundary line of Texas and Coffee&#8217;s station, as the said company may deem most suitable, with the privilege of making, owning and main<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="377" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="371" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>taining such branches to the railway as they may deem expedient.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That Ebenezer Allen, and such other persons as he may associate with him for the purpose, are hereby appointed Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners, and invested with the right and privilege of forming and organizing the said company, of obtaining subscriptions to the capital stock, and distributing the shares thereof; and generally of taking such lawful measures to secure the effectual organization and successful operation of said company, as they may deem ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pedient.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the capital stock of said company shall be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, and the holders of such shares shall constitute the said company, and each member shall be entitled to one vote in person or by proxy, for each and every share he may own; and such shares of stock shall be transferable alone upon the books of the company, which books shall be kept open for the inspection of any stockholder who may wish to ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />amine them at the office of the company, in proper business hours.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the affairs and business of the said company shall be conducted and managed by a board of directors, not to exceed nine in number, who shall be elected by the company, at such time as the said commissioners may appoint, and annually thereafter: Provided, that in case of failure so to elect at the stated time, the board of directors incumbent shall continue in office until there be an election, the time for which may be fixed by said board, whereof reasonable notice shall be given.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That no person shall he eligible as a director unless he be owner of at least five shares of the capital stock; the said board shall elect a President from their number, to fill vacancies occurring from death, resignation or otherwise: have power to appoint a secretary and such other officers as they may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sider necessary, and to require security for the faithful perform<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance of their duties; also, to prescribe the time for the payment of instalments, or assessments upon the stock, and the amount of such instalments or assessments, to declare the forfeiture of such stock for non-payment; and to do or cause to be done all other lawful acts or things which they may deem necessary or proper in conducting the business of said company. A major<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ity of said board of directors shall constitute a quorum for do<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing business. All instruments in writing executed by the Pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="378" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="372" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>sident and secretary, under the seal of the company, with the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sent of the board of directors, shall be valid and binding.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the said company shall be empowered to occupy such portions of the public lands, not exceeding one hundred yards in width, as the said railway or any of its branches, to be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structed in accordance with this act, shall pass through, and to take from the public lands contiguous thereto such metals, timber and other materials as may be useful or necesssary in the construction and maintenance of their works, and the prosecution of their opera<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions or business, the company paying a reasonable compensation to the State for the said privilege.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That if the said company shall not commence its opera<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, within two years from the first day of June, 1848, and shall not have completed at least one hundred miles, of the said railway within five years thereafter, then, and in such case the rights, powers and privileges herein granted to the said company, for the construction of said railway shall cease and he determined.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That the said company shall have the right of con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structing bridges and other improvements upon and over any water course bordering upon or crossing the said railway, or any of its branches: Provided, that the navigation of such water course shall not be obstructed thereby.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That if any person shall negligently or designedly in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jure or destroy any of the fixtures, building machines or improve<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments of the company, or any portion of the said railway or its branches, he shall he subject to indictment therefor, and on con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />viction may be punished by fine and imprisonment, and shall be also liable to the said company in a civil action for damages.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That no provision contained in this act shall be So construed as to grant or allow any banking privileges, or any privi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lege of issuing any species of paper to circulate as money to the aforesaid company.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That the said company shall have the right to charge five cents per mile for passagers and no more, and shall have the right to charge not exceeding fifty cents on the hundred pounds for freight for every hundred miles that the same may he transported on said railway: Provided, however, that the Legislature of the State of Texas shall have the right to <pb n="379" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="373" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>fix and regulate the price that said company shall charge for carry<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the public mails of the United States.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 11, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 205.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate Montgomery Academy.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the institution for the educating of youth, now located at the town of Montgomery, in the county of Montgomery, shall be, and the same is hereby established at said town, by the name of the &#8220;Montgomery Academy of Montgomery County.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That C. B. Stewart, Jacob Shan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />non, R. F. Oliver, W. M. Rankin, Benjamin Rigly, J. H. Price, R. B. Martin, M. 0. Dimon, J. Wamack, and E. J. Arnold, the Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent and Trustees of said Academy be, and they are hereby consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tuted and incorporated a body politic in deed and in law, by the name and style of the President and Trustees of the Montgomery Academy of Montgomery County, and by that name they and their successors may, and shall have succession and exercise the privileges herein granted them, be capable of suing and being sued, of plead<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing and being impleaded, of holding property real and personal, and mixed, and of granting, selling, and conveying the same at pleasure, of having a common seal to be changed at their pleasure, of establishing a Female Department, and such other dependent in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitutions as they shall deem necessary, and of doing and perform<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing whatever else they may deem proper and necessary for the ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vancement of said institution, in as ample a manner as persons or bodies politic or corporate can or may by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted. That this charter and these priv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ileges shall include and extend to the present President and Trus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tees of said institution, and to their successors in office, so long as they shall restrict the benefits of the same to the promotion of edu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cation and the advancement of science.</p>
<pb n="380" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="374" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That on the first Saturday in No<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vember, 1848, (unto which time the present President and Trustees shall continue in office) and annually thereafter the subscribers to said institution shall elect ten Trustees to serve for the ensuing year: Provided, no one shall be held to be a subscriber, and be per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitted to vote for Trustees, who has not subscribed and paid toward the erection of the buildings now used by the institute: Provided, further, that any one may become a subscriber by paying for the use of the institution such regular sum as may be determined by said Board of Trustees or their successors, and that all persons whose children are being educated at said institution, shall during such time be held to be subscribers to its support.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the election of Trustees of said Academy shall he held by the President, or in his absence by any one of the Trustees thereof; and a majority of votes from those subscribers present, and voting in favor of any person shall be suf<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficient to constitute such person duly elected a trustee of said acad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />emy; if, for any cause an election for trustee should not be held upon the first Saturday in November of each year, said election may be held upon first or second Saturday in said month; in all cases the President and trustees shall continue in office until their suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessors are elected.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That said trustees, or a majority of their whole number shall elect a President of said academy to serve one year, and if they deem proper a Secretary, to continue in office until their successors are regularly elected; said President and trustees, shall have and exercise the powers constitutionally and lawfully incident to corporations and shall have power to enact such laws or rules for their own government and for the government of the schools by them established, as they may deem proper not inconsistent with the Constitution and laws of the State. When<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever vacancies occur in the offices of President or trustees, such vacancy shall he filled by the remaining trustees appointing suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessors to the vacancies, to continue in office until the next an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nual election, or until their successors are elected; if a regular elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of trustees be not held upon the days herein prescribed for annual elections, a majority of the subscribers present may at any time proceed to elect trustees to serve until the next annual election can be held.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted. That said institution shall be <pb n="381" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="375" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>open to all denominations of religion, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 11, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 206.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of James Stewart.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Adjutant General be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to issue to James Stewart of Bastrop county, a do<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nation claim of six hundred and forty acres of land, for being at the battle of San Jacinto, whose name was not returned upon the muster roll of his Captain, Jesse Billingsly, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 11, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 207.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Moses Evans, surviving administrator of H. S. Williamson, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a patent to Moses, Evans, surviving administrator of the estate of H. S. Williamson, deceased, for one-third of a league of land, bv virtue of a certificate of the Board of Land Commissioners of Washington County, No. 154, and dated the 5th day of September, 1839, which certificate was, through error, issued in the name of J. H. Williamson.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 11, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="382" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="376" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 208.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Isaac Delany.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the Board of Land Commissioners for the County of Sa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bine, issued to James Delany, a conditional certificate for 1280 acres of land; and, whereas, it appears there was no such person in the county of Sabine entitled to such a certificate, and that the certificate should have been issued to Isaac Delany; and whereas, it appears to have been a clerical error in the clerk of said Board, in issuing a certificate to James instead of Isaac De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lany. Therefore:</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office is hereby required to issue a patent to Isaac Delany, instead of James De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lany, he complying with the law in all other requirements.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 13, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 209.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the City of Lavaca.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the citizens of Lavaca, in the county of Calhoun, be a body Corporate, by the name and style of the City of Lavaca, and by that name may sue and be sued, implead and be impleaded, in all courts and in all matters and actions whatsoever; and by that name may purchase, hold, and dispose of any estate, real or personal, within the limits of the city, for the use of the corporation, and may have a common seal, which they may alter or change at their pleasure.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the limits of said city shall be the boundaries of the league of land upon which the town of Lavaca laid out by Thomas McConnell, on Lavaca bay is situated, it being the tract of land purchased by John M. Smith, at a sale of the estate of the said Thomas McConnell.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That there shall he elected, <pb n="383" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="377" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>annually, by ballot, on the first Monday of January in each and every year, one Mayor, one Recorder and eight Aldermen, to serve one year or until their successors be elected, who shall constitute the City Councils which election shall be held by the Mayor and two Aldermen, except the first, which shall be held by the Chief Jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tice of the county, by giving ten days notice thereof in the news<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />paper printed in Lavaca or otherwise: but the charter shall not be forfeited by reason of any failure to elect a Mayor and Aider<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men on the day specified; but may be held at any future day, the old council remaining in office until the new council is qualified, The City Council, immediately after being qualified, shall appoint, one Treasurer, one Assessor and Tax Collector, one Marshal, and as many subordinate officers for preserving, the peace and well order<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the affairs of the city as they shall deem necessary: the Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer, Assessor and Collector, shall each give bond and security for the faithful discharge of their duty, in such amount and form as the council may determine.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the Mayor, Aldermen, and all other city officers, before entering upon the duties of their re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spective offices, shall take and subscribe an oath to perform the du<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties thereof to the best of their abilities, which oath the Mayor shall take before the Judge of Probate or a Justice of the Peace, and each of the other officers, before the Mayor or Recorder; the Mayor and Recorder shall have all the authority of Justices of the Peace, and the Marshal, all the authority of a Constable in the county.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That whenever the City Council shall deem it necessary to suppress riots and disturbances, or to protect the persons or property of the citizens, when they may be threatened with dangers from any source, they shall have power to call out the citizens, to appoint a place of rendezvous, and to or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganize a patrol or city guard, to be continued as long as circum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stances may require; and if any citizen, after being summoned by the Marshall shall fail to attend or to act as a member of the city guard, without good and sufficient cause shown, he shall be fined, in any sum not exceeding ten dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the Council shall have full power and authority to make and pass such ordinances and by-laws as they shall deem necessary to maintain the cleanliness and salubrity of the city; to secure the safe and convenient <pb n="384" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="378" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>passage of the streets, side walks and public ways; to prevent en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />croachments upon public grounds, works or city property; to order and determine the construction of side walks, at the cost of the proprietors of lots in front of which the improvement is to be made; to establish an active system of inspection over the conduct of slaves; to determine in what part of the city wooden buildings and wooden chimneys shall be allowed to be erected; to regulate the keeping and sale of gunpowder within the city; to determine on the means to be resorted to in order to prevent and extinguish con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />flagration; to establish one or more market places, and to deter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mine the mode of inspection of all comestibles sold publicly; to regulate every thing which relates to bakers, butchers, tavern keepers, oyster houses, restaurats, eating houses and grog-shops, ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cept the prices of the articles vended; and to regulate and control all public wharves, landing places, and ferries within the city limits.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That whenever it may be deemed necessary, the Council shall divide the city into a convenient num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber of wards, each ward to be represented by at least one alderman.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the City Council shall have, power to assess and collect a tax not exceeding two per cent, per annum on the value of all land and lots within the city limits; also a poll tax of one dollar each on all males of the age of twenty-one years and upward, and on the value of all slaves over the age of five Years, not exceeding one-half of one per cent., annually.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That the City Council shall have power to levy and collect a tax not to exceed one-fourth of one per cent., annually, upon all real estate within the city, for the express purpose of raising a public school fund, and the proceeds of such tax shall he applied to no other purpose but that of advancing the cause of education in the city of Lavaca.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That the council shall have power to levy and collect a license tax upon all places of public amusements, and retail of spirituous, vinous and malt liquors, and upon drays, carts, hacks, omnibusses or other vehicles, carrying freight or passengers for hire within the city, and to regulate the rates of fare on the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That all persons qualified to vote under the Constitution of the State, who have resided six months in the city immediately preceding the election, and have <pb n="385" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="379" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>paid a tax into the city treasury prior to the day of election, shall be entitled to vote for Mayor, Aldermen and Recorder.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Be it further enacted, That a majority of the Alder<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men shall constitute a quorum to do business: the Mayor shall pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />side at all meetings of the council, (except when prevented by sick<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness or otherwise, when the Aldermen present shall appoint one of their body to preside,) and shall convene the Board whenever re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quested so to do in writing by three of the Aldermen.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>March 13, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 210.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize Jacob F. Winfree to adopt Zachary Taylor Long as his lawful child.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the name of Zachary Taylor Long, infant son of Andrew Long, be, and is hereby changed to Zachary Taylor Winfree, and that said infant is hereby declared to be the adopted son of Jacob F. Winfree, and capable of inheriting the estate of said Jacob F. Winfree in the same manner as if said infant were the lawful child of said Jacob F. Winfree.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 13, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 211.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Kisiah Taylor, whose maiden name was Kisiah Cryer.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the title to one league of land, situated on the waters of the Navidad river, in the county of Fayette, in this State, which was granted to Kisiah Taylor, now the wife of George Taylor, of said county of Fayette, by her maiden name of Kisi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="386" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="380" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ah Cryer, as a colonist of Austin&#8217;s colony, previous to the declara<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of Texian independence, and who was then the head of a family, shall be as good and valid to said Kisiah Taylor, her heirs and assigns, to all intents and purposes, as if she had not been known by any other name up to the date of the grant of said land, than her maiden name of Kisiah Cryer; and that this act take ef<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 13, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 212.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Incorporate the Town of Palestine, in the County of Anderson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the citizens of the town of Palestine, in the county of Ander<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, be, and they are hereby incorporated and formed into a body politic and corporate, under the name and style of &#8220;The Corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the Town of Palestine,&#8221; and shall have the same rights and privileges, and be subject to the same regulations and restrictions as are conferred and imposed upon the citizens of Crockett, by an act to incorporate the town of Crockett, in the county of Houston, passed 11th May. A. D. 1846.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the first election for officers of said town, shall be held in said town on the first Saturday in May, 1848, and each election thereafter shall he held on the first Monday in January in each year; and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 14, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="387" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="381" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 213.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to to legalize the marriage of Eli Gray with Ann Eliza Gray.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the rites of matrimony heretofore celebrated between Eli Gray and Ann Eliza Gray, be, and the same are hereby declared to be as valid in law as though at the time of the celebration of said marriage no legal disability existed thereto.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage. Approved, March 14, 1848.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 214.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate Williamson Academy in the County of Hays.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Henry Cheatham, John D. Pitts, U. A. Young, E. T. Merri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man, C. R. Johns, and Wm. L. Massy, be and they are hereby in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corporated a body politic, under the name and style of &#8220;The Trus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tees of Williamson Academy, capable of suing and being sued, of pleading and being impleaded, of holding property, real, personal and mixed, of selling and conveying the same at pleasure, of having a common seal, and of doing and performing, whatever else that may be proper and necessary to be done for the advancement of said institution, not contrary to the laws, and constitution of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this charter and privilege, shall extend to the said Trustees and their successers in office as long as they confine the operations of the same and the benefit thereof to the promotion of useful knowledge to the young, and the advancement of the sciences; and the said institution <pb n="388" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="382" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>shall be accessible alike to all without regard to opinions in religion or politics.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the Trustees for the time being shall have full power to enact such by-laws, rules and regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lations for the government of said Academy, as may seem to them necessary for that object.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the institution herein created, shall be located at or near the town of San Marcos in Hays County.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 14, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 215.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of Louis Sanches.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Captain Louis Sanches, acting under the direction of General Thomas J. Rusk, did humanely provide for the support of many Mexican women and children, who were left destitute, in Nacogdoches County, after the rebellion in 1838, and whereas the private property of the said Louis Sanches, has been sacri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficed to meet the liabilities incurred by him for the support of said women and children, and thereby the said Sanches and his own family have experienced great embarrassment and injury, and no compensation has ever been made by Government for the advances made by said Sanches, therefore.</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller of Public Accounts he authorized to allow and audit the claim of Louis Sanches, and the Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer shall pay the same in the following manner, viz; the sum of three hundred dollars payable immediately after the pas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sage of this Resolution; the sum of two hundred dollars pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able on the first day of January, A. D. 1849, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, and the balance of said claim, for the sum of eight hundred and eighty dollars, <pb n="389" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="383" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>shall be audited for that amount subject to future settlement by the Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this Joint Resolution shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>March 16th, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 216.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing and requiring the transfer of the succession of Alexander Jordan, deceased, from the county of Nacogdoches to the county of Rusk.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Clerk of the Probate Court of Nacogdoches county, is hereby authorized and required by this act to transfer all the original papers and a transcript of the Record, relating to the suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cession or administration of the estate of Alexander Jordan, de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceased, from his office to the office of the Clerk of the Probate Court of Rusk county, in such manner that said succession or ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ministration, shall be entirely conducted and closed in the County of Rusk, as though it had been originally commenced in that county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 15, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 217.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of J. Harris Catlin.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller of Public Accounts be, and he is hereby authorized and required to discharge J. Harris Catlin, from all liabilities to the late Republic of Texas, upon his fil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="390" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="384" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ing with the Comptroller, a receipt in full for all claims the said J. Harris Catlin holds against said Republic; and that this act take effect and he in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 15, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 218.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution auditing and acknowledging the claims of Stuart Perry, against the late Republic of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas it appears upon the investigation of the claims of Stuart Perry that there is a balance due said Perry of thirty eight thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand, fifty three dollars and seventy three cents, from the late Republic of Texas, on account of services rendered the said Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public, and for spoliations of sundry goods, wares and merchan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dize, the property of said Perry, by the Custom House officers and other persons in the employ of the Government of said Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public, therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the claims of Stuart Perry, against the late Republic of Texas, be and the same are hereby audited and acknowledged as good and valid claims, against the said Republic for the amount of thirty eight thousand fifty three dollars and seventy-three cents, and that the said accounts and vouchers, shall be deposited in the office of the Comptroller of Public Accounts, and when so deposited, shall have the same force and effect, as if the same had been audited and settled by the proper accounting officer of the late Republic of Texas, provided, further, that the said amount, hereby audited is hereby declared, to be in full of all claims, and demands which the said Perry may have against the said Republic, including inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />est up to this date.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this Joint Resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 15, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="391" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="385" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 219.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of James P. Wallace and Robert M. Wil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liamson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Adjutant General of the State, be, and he is hereby au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized and directed to issue his land warrants, one to James P. Wallace, for sixteen hundred and eight acres; and one to Robert M. Williamson for twenty two hundred and two acres of land, which land warrants when issued, may be located on any unappro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated public domain belonging to the State, and when surveyed, patents shall issue thereon as in other cases.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That when the Adjutant General delivers said warrants he shall take receipts in full, one from James P. Wallace for his bounty land as a twelve months ranger, from 17th January, 1836, and his per diem pay for four months and eleven days services; and one from Robert M. Williamson for ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vices as Major in the ranging service of the late Republic of Texas, from the 28th November, 1835, to the 10th June, 1836.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act be in force, and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 15, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 220.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Christopher Columbus Browning.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Board of Land Commissioners for the County of Travis, be and they are hereby authorized and required to issue to Christopher Columbus Browning a certificate for twelve hundred and eighty acres of land, to which he as a mar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ried man, was entitled, by virtue of his arrival in the Republic of Texas, as an emigrant, prior to the first day of Octo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber, 1837, upon said Browning&#8217;s delivering to said Board, to be <pb n="392" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="386" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>canceled, the conditional certificate for six hundred and forty acres of land, heretofore granted to him by the Board of Land Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners for Harris County, provided said Christopher Columbus Browning introduce satisfactory proof before said Board of Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners that he was a married man, and emigrated to the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public of Texas, prior to the first of October, 1837.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 15, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 221.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution authorizing the transfer of one half of a certain lot in the City of Austin on certain conditions.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That on the execution of a deed to the State, and filing the same in the office of the Comptroller of Public Accounts, by the owner of lot No. 11, in block 83 in the City of Austin, of the one half of said lot&#8212;that is to say 80 feet by 23&#8212;it shall be the duty of the Comptroller, when said deed shall have been deposited in his office, to give a certificate to that effect, which, on being pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sented to the Commisisoner of the General Land Office, he shall issue to the owner of the aforesaid lot, a patent for the east half of lot No. 12 in block 83, in the said City of Austin.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this Joint Resolution take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 15, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="393" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="387" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 222.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution confirming a certificate for one league and one labor of land issued to John vandenworth by the Board of Land Commissioners of Austin County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, a certificate for one league and one labor of land, was heretofore issued by the Board of Land Commissioners of Aus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tin County, to John vanderworth, which certificate was recom<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mended as genuine and legal, by the local and traveling Boards of land Commissioners, appointed to detect fraudulent Land Cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates, and was so reported to the General Land Office, but owing to some informality in the form of said report, the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land Office, does not feel authorized to issue a patent thereon, Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a patent to John vander<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />worth, upon the certificate for one league and one labor of land heretofore issued to him by the Board of Land Commissioners of Austin County and now on file in the General Land Office.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this Joint Resolution shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 16, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 233.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution to validate the election of Mayor and Aldermen for the City of New Braunfels.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas by section second of an act to incorporate the City of New Braunfels, passed the 11th day of May, A. D. 1846, it is made the duty of the Chief Justice of Bexar County to order an election for the Corporate officers of said City; and whereas by section fifteen of said act it is prescribed that <pb n="394" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="388" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the citizens of said city should vote for the acceptance of their charter of incorporation on the second Monday of July, A. D. 1846; and whereas the election for Mayor and Aldermen of said City and also for the acceptance of its charter, was ordered by the Chief Justice of Comal County, and was held on the seven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teenth day of June, A. D. 1847, Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the election for the acceptance of the charter of said City of New Braunfels, and for Mayor and Aldermen of the same held on the 7th day of June, 1847, by order of the Chief Justice of Comal County, be as legal and valid as if said elections had been held at the time and in the manner prescribed in the act entitled &#8220;an act to incorporate the City of New Braunfels,&#8221; passed the 11th day of May, A. D. 1846.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this Joint Resolution take effect from and after its passage. Approved, March 16, 1848.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 224.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution authorizing the Comptroller of Public Accounts to transfer to S. L. Johnson an Austin City lot.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller of Public Accounts be, and he is hereby authorized to transfer to S. L. Johnson of the City of Aus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tin, an Austin City lot, of equal size and value to one owned by said Johnson, in said City, which has formerly been appropriated, as a burying ground, on condition said Johnson relinquish his said lot to the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this Resolution he in force and take effect, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 16, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="395" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="389" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 225.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the Relief of Henry M. Smith.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Henry M. Smith was permanently disabled in battle in defence of his country; and whereas, grants of land have here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tofore been made to others, who have been so disabled, Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby required to issue to Henry M. Smith, a certificate for one League and one Labor of Land, to be located on any of the vacant and unappropriated lands of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That when said certificate is located, and the land sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyed, and the field notes returned to the General Land Office, in accordance with law, it is hereby made the duty of the Commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />er, to issue a patent thereon.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this Joint Resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March. 16, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 226.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to be entitled an act to incorporate the City of Nacog<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />doches.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the citizens of Nacogdoches be, and are hereby de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clared a body corporate and politic under the name and style of the &#8220;Corporation of the City of Nacogdoches,&#8221; who shall have power of suing and being sued, or pleading and being impleaded, to hold and dispose of real and personal property within the limits of said corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the limits of said corporation shall he as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows, to wit: Bridget&#8217;s bayou to be the western boundary; the bayou LaNana, to be the eastern boundary; and a line to be run from said bayou LaNana to Bridget&#8217;s bayou, due east <pb n="396" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="390" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and west, so far as to include within the limits of said corporation the residences of James H. Starr and John Noblett, which line is to be the northern boundary line of said corporation; and it shall be the duty of the Mayor and Board of Aldermen to employ a le<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gally authorized surveyor to run and plainly mark said boundary lines, within one month after the organization of the corporation under this act, a certified copy of the plat and field notes of said survey, shall be delivered to the principal Surveyor of the Nacog<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />doches Land District, whose duty it shall be to plot the same on the map of said land district, and one certified copy of said field notes shall be transmitted to the Commissioner of the General Land Office, where the same shall also be represented on the map of said land district.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That it shall be the duty of said citizens to elect eight Aldermen, and that a presiding officer or Mayor, a Treasurer and Secretary, shall be elected by the Aldermen from their own body; and that a Collector and Corporation Constable be elected by said citizens; said Treasurer and Collector being required to give a bond with sufficient security, to be approved by the Mayor; which bond shall be recorded in the office of the Clerk of the County Court, and then filed with the Secretary of the corporation: the Treasurer and Collector shall make reports when required by the Mayor&#8217;s warrant.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the first election under this act shall be held on the first Monday in May next, under the direction of the Chief Justice of the county, after giving ten days notice thereof, and an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nually thereafter by the Mayor, at least ten days prior to the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />piration of his term of office; and that in case of death, or resigna<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, the vacancy shall be filled by new elections.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That no person shall be eligible to any office in said corporate body, or entitled to vote for corporation officers, unless he shall be a citizen of the State of Texas, and shall have resided at least six months, and owns or rents real estate in said corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the Mayor of the corporation of the city of Nacogdoches shall have jurisdiction and exercise the powers of a justice of the peace over all offences committed against the by-laws, ordinances and decrees of the Mayor and Board of Aldermen within the limits of the corporation; and it shall be the duty of the Chief Justice, after the first election, and annu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ally thereafter the Mayor of said corporation, to notify the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor of the State of the election of the Mayor: upon the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="397" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="391" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ceipt of such notice, the Governor is hereby authorized and required to issue to the Mayor elect a commission of Justice of the Peace, whose jurisdiction shall be limited by and confined to the by-laws, ordinances and decrees of said corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the Mayor and Board of Aldermen shall have power to pass such rules and ordinances as may be necessary for the regulation of the police and the preservation of order within the corporate limits, to levy taxes for the removal of nuisances and keeping the streets in good order, as also, to drain effectually all such swamps and ponds within the corporate limits, as may he deemed necessary to the preservation of the health of the inhabi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tants of said city; and shall have the further power to prescribe fines and penalties for the violation of such ordinances or by-laws; provided, however, that in no case such fine or penalty exceed one hundred dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That the Mayor and Board of Aldermen of said corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion shall have the control of all vacant land or lots within the cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate limits, and may dispose of the same, or any portion thereof, the proceeds of which shall he applied to the improvement of said city, in such manner as the Mayor and Aldermen, or a majority may determine.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That the Mayor and Board of Aldermen shall have power to regulate the streets and squares of said corporate limits, to widen or straighten the streets, close up and make new ones, whenever it may be deemed expedient, having a due regard in all cases to private property, and in all cases making a fair remunera<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion to the owner or owners of such property, whenever it shall be taken for public uses.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That the Mayor and Board of Aldermen shall have power to lay a reasonable tax on all persons and property, both real and personal in said city, and shall also be empowered to lay a tax, on all taverns and houses of public entertainment, tipling houses, billiard tables, nine or ten pin alleys, upon all merchants, whole<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sale or retail, and upon all lawyers and doctors in said corporation, to be assessed and collected by the collector of said corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That all fines and penalties assessed by the Mayor, and collected by him, or by the collector or constable of said corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, shall be paid to the Treasurer of the corporation to be applied to the improvement of the city, in such manner as the Mayor and board of aldermen or a majority of them may determine.</p>
<pb n="398" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="392" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 12 That for all services performed by the Mayor or Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stable, the same fees shall be allowed them as by law are allowed Justices of the Peace and Constables for similar services.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That the rules and ordinances of said corporation shall not be contrary to the Constitution of the United States, nor the Constitution and laws of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That an act entitled &#8220;an act to incorporate the town of Nacogdoches, and other towns therein mentioned,&#8221; approved June 5th, 1837, so far as said act refers to the town of Nacogdoches, be, and the same is hereby repealed; and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 16, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 227.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Thomas J. Stell.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, a certain Land Scrip Certificate for 640 acres, being No. 154, of Class No. 2, issued by the Government of the late Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public of Texas, and now owned by Thomas J. Stell, of the State of Florida, was after its location and survey, accidentally destroyed; and whereas, there is no law now in force, authorizing a duplicate of the same to be issued, by reason whereof, the said Stell is unable to obtain a patent thereon, Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to issue to the said Thomas J. Stell, a patent on said Certificate in accordance with the survey made thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 16, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="399" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="393" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 228.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution fox the relief of Robert H. Beale, who was per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />manently disabled in the service of the country.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Robert M. Beale, was permanently disabled in the serv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ice of the country, and whereas grants of land have heretofore been made to others for the same cause, Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby required to issue to Robert H. Beale, a certificate for one league and one labor of land to be located on any vacant and unappropriated lands in this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That when the survey is made, and field notes returned in accordance with law, it is hereby made the duty of the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner of the General Land Office to issue a patent thereon, and that this Joint Resolution take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 16, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 229.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the town of Goliad in the County of Goliad.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the citizens of the town of Goliad, in the county of Goliad be, and they are hereby declared a body politic and corpor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ate, by the name and style of the &#8220;Town of Goliad,&#8221; and by that name may sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded in all courts and in all matters and actions whatsoever, and by that name may purchase, hold and dispose of any estate, real or personal within the limits of said town, for the use of the corporation, and may have a common seal which they may alter or change at pleasure.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the boundaries of said town, and the limits within which said corporation may exercise jurisdiction, shall <pb n="400" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="394" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>be co-extensive with those set forth and described in a patent granted to said corporation by the authorities of the late Republic of Texas for four leagues of land, under date of the twenty-fifth of October, A. D. 1844.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the officers of said town shall be, one Mayor, one Recorder, one Treasurer, and five Aldermen, and may for every additional thousand of inhabitants after the first thousand, the number of Aldermen may be increased one, provided the number shall never exceed twelve, and when additions are made to the number of Aldermen, the electorial districts of said town shall be so altered and arranged as to give the every part of said town a fair representation in the body of Aldermen.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That all persons who are efaulified voters under the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution of the State, and are citizens of the town of Goliad shall be authorized to vote in elections held in said town.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That there shall be a board consisting, when full, of the Mayor, Recorder and Aldermen; with the Mayor, (or in his ab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sence, the Recorder,) as President, a majority of the whole number of Aldermen may constitute a board for the transaction of business, the President voting only in cases of equal division among the Al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dermen present and voting. The board to be called the Council of the town of Goliad, shall represent the corporation, using its name in all appropriate business not otherwise provided for, and so shall have full power subject to the general law of the country and the special provisions of this charter, to regulate the further organiza<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the board and its own proceedings, to prescribe the duties of all officers and agents, whether elected by the qualified electors of said town, or appointed by the town Council.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That every officer and agent of the corporation, before entering upon the duties of his office, and the Treasurer and other officers or agents appointed by the town council, shall before enter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing on the duties of their office, give bond with satisfactory secur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ity to be approved by the town council, payable to the Mayor and his successors in office, for the use of the corporation, conditioned for the faithful performance of the duties of his office. If any per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son elected to office under this charter fail to qualify within ten days after his election, the office shall be declared vacant and an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />other election ordered.</p>
<pb n="401" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="395" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 7. That the regular time for electing the Mayor, Recorder, Treasurer and Aldermen shall be the first Monday of January, an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nually: but elections to supply vacancies may be held at any time after ten days notice.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That all elections under this charter shall be conducted in accordance with the general law regulating elections, and all contests shall be determined by the council of said town.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That the office of Recorder shall supercede that of Clerk under the former charter, and all officers of the corporation duly elected, previously to the first Monday of January next, shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue to hold their respective offices, subject to the terms of this charter until their successors shall be qualified, and so of like offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers subsequently elected from year to year.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That the Mayor and Recorder shall have and exercise the power and jurisdiction of a Justice of the Peace, within the limits of said town.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That the town council shall have power to enact and enforce such ordinances and regulations as they may deem neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary for the government of said town; they shall have power to pass by-laws to regulate their own proceedings; shall have entire con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trol of the police of said town, and they are authorized to levy and collect moderate and equitable taxes, on all fixed and moveable property within their jurisdiction not exceeding one half of one per centum of the State tax; and to make such laws as are neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary for recovery and collection of the same: said Council are also authorised to grant license to persons, dealers in goods and mer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chandize, and retailers of spirituous liquors; to grant license for billiard tables and ten pin alleys, providing no gaming establish<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, contrary to law shall be licensed or tolerated.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That said town council in conjunction with the Coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty Court, are hereby empowered and authorized to sell and alienate such public lots or parcels of land, as may be within said corporation, and to which there is no legal claimant or title, and also to dispose of such houses or other buildings as may now be the property of the corporation of said town; and the town council may sue for and recover all debts and forfeitures accruing or due to said corporation, the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeds of such debts and forfeitures to be appropriated to the erection or repair of a court house, jail, and such other public <pb n="402" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="396" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>edifices as may be necessary, and to the establishment of a public school for said town.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That the Mayor and Recorder of said town shall be commissioned by the Governor.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That this law take effect from and after its passage, and that all laws heretofore passed incorporating the town of Go<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liad, be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 16, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 230.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Republican Academy in the county of Harrison.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That O. Hendrick, G. W. Young, L. D. Evans, L. B. Whit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />set, F. Washington, L. J. W. Busick, W. S. Taylor, S. C. T. Ford, George Dunarroy, T. A. Harris, T. T. Gamage, B. F. Young, J. R. Tanner, R. P. Brown, Henry Martin, R. A. Walton, A. D. Burress; W. P. Hill, S. Richardson, C. Frazier, J. Stephens, C. M. Adams, N. R, Goode, and their associates and successors, be, and they are hereby created a body politic and corporate in deed and in law, by the name of the Republican Academy, and by that name may have perpetual succession and be capable in law of holding by purchase or donation, property, both real and personal in fee, for years so long as they confine their operations to the promotion of educa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Books shall be opened to receive subscriptions in sums not less than ten dollars; which subscriptions may be in lands, money, labor or materials for building purposes; and any person who has heretofore subscribed, or may hereafter give the above amount, shall be considered a patron or stockholder of said Acad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />emy, may have the right to sell or transfer the stock at pleasure, and shall have the privilege of voting in person or by proxy in all elections necessary for the government of said Academy.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The stockholders may hare power to disfranchise any of their members by the vote of the majority of them: pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="403" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="397" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>vided, they pay to such stockholder, the amount of his subscription, with interest thereon from the time it was paid to the institution.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The stockholders shall elect from their number not less than five trustees, who shall hold their office as such, for the term of one year, or until their successors are elected; whose duty it shall be to procure teachers, regulate prices of tuition, and govern gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erally the operations of the school, and shall have power to elect from their number, a President, Secretary and Treasurer, who shall hold their office during the term for which the trustees are elected.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The Trustees shall have power to make such by-laws as they deem necessary for their own government and the manage<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the school: provided, they are not in conflict with the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution and laws of this State; and may alter and amend them at pleasure.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. This act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 16, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 231.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Western Texas Orphan Asylum.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That L. Bene, H. Spiess and L. C. Ervenberg, their asso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciates and successors, be, and they are hereby constituted a body politic and corporate under the name and style of the Western Texas Orphan Asylum, with power and capacity to sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, to own and take by purchase, devise, dona<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion or otherwise, real and personal property, not exceeding twen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty-five thousand dollars in value, and to dispose of the same, for the purpose of founding, erecting and maintaining an institution for the protection, support and education of orphan children.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the said L. Bene, H. Speiss and L. C. Ervenberg, shall be directors of said corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration and they their successors and associates shall have power to increase the number of directors to five, they can fill vacancies in their own body; elect from among themselves a <pb n="404" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="398" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>President, who shall hold his office for one year, appoint such offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers as may he necessary for the proper management of the proper<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty and affairs of the corporation, and make by-laws for the regula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of their internal affairs not inconsistent with the laws of the land, they shall have a common seal which, with the signature of their President shall be evidence of their corporate acts, and they can do and perform all other acts that may be proper and necessary within the limits of this charter, for the protection, maintenance and education of indigent orphan children.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the President shall have all the rights of guardianship oyer the orphans in said asylum, except that he shall not have the management nor control of the estates of any such orphans.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the said Orphan Asylum shall be located in the county of Comal, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 16, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 232.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to Incorporate the Huntsville Male Institute.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Thomas G. Birdwell, Benjamin S. Wilson, George W. Rogers, James T. Sims, and Thomas King, Trustees of the Hunts<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ville Male Institute, in the county of Walker, and their successors in office, be, and they are hereby incorporated under the name and style of the &#8220;Huntsville Male Institute,&#8221; and under that name may sue and be sued.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The said Trustees shall hold their offices until the first Saturday in January next, and until their successors shall be elect<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed; and they and their successors shall have power to purchase and sell real estate, to open books for stock for the erection of all build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings and improvements necessary to carry on and support an Acad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />emy for the education of male children.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The Trustees shall have power to employ teachers, to receive and dismiss students; to make rules for the govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="405" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="399" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ment of the Institute; to see that they are enforced; to associate with them as many subscribers of stock as they may think proper; to call meetings of the stockholders; to receive donations for the use of the Institute: Provided, That the capital stock subscribed and paid in shall never exceed the sum of twenty thousand dollars: the said Trustees shall also have power to pass a code of by-laws, not incompatible with this act of incorporation and the Constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion and laws of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The stockholders shall, on the first Saturday of January next, and annually thereafter, proceed to elect, at the Academy, from their body, five persons as trustees for the ensuing year. The election shall he holden by the President of the preceding board, and each share shall entitle the holder to one vote; should the elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion from any cause be omitted on the day pointed out, it shall be the duty of the President to give ten days notice of said election, at which time said officers shall be chosen, and all elections shall be by ballot: the person receiving the highest number of votes shall be President of the board: said board shall thereupon immediately organize, and they shall elect from amongst the stockholders, a person to act as secretary and treasurer.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The Board of Trustees shall take bond and security of said secretary and treasurer in double the amount of stock paid in, for the faithful performance of his office. In all cases of the death or resignation of an officer, ten days notice shall be given by the board, and the vacancy filled by the stockholders.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The secretary shall keep a faithful record of all the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceedings of the board, and of all monies received and paid out, and which shall only he paid out upon the warrant of the hoard, signed by the President: he shall also issue certificates of stock to all who may wish to become members, upon their making the necessary pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments; and the books and proceedings of the hoard shall at all times be open to the inspection of any stockholder who may wish to exam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ine the same. Transfers of stock shall not be made except upon the books of the company.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The Board of Trustees shall, on the day of the elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of their successors, previous to holding said election, make a full report of the proceedings of the past year, embracing the state and condition of the Institute, the number of students en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tered, the rates of tuition for each class, and the dividend on <pb n="406" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="400" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the stock subscribed, which shall be subiect to the call of the stockholders.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. A majority of the Board of Trustees shall he competent to transact any business, and may, when they deem it necessary, call a meeting of the stockholders.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. To avoid debt in every form, any Board of Trustees who may contract debts that they have not the means of paying by the funds placed in their hands, shall be jointly and individually re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sponsible for the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. This charter shall continue for twenty years from and after the passage hereof.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 16, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 233.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Alfred Brigance.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby required to respect as valid, land certificate No. 1,375, issued in February, 1839, to Alfred Brigance, by the Board of Land Commissioners for Harrisburg county, for 320 acres of land, the same being his headright, and that the Commissioner of the Land Office issue a patent accordingly.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 16, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="407" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="401" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 234.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act, supplementary to an act to regulate the Public Printing, approved, March 8th, 1848.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas at the time of the passage of the above recited act, James F. Johnson had, and subsequently thereto, down to the present time has, transcribed and prepared for the press, the Journals of the present session of the Senate:&#8212;Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That James F. Johnson be, and he is hereby authorized to complete his transcript of the Journals of the present session of the Senate, prepare the same for the press, and superintend the printing there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />of as required by law, for which he shall receive the compensation fixed and allowed by the above recited act, to which this is a sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plement.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 18, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 235.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Alfred Johnson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas in the year 1838, the Board of Land Commissioners for Robertson county, issued to Alexander D. Orr, a land certificate No. 25, class 2, for one-third of a league of land, which appears by the record of the Investigating Board of Land Commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers, to have been recommended for patent as genuine and legal; that afterwards, the said Orr sold and conveyed the same by deed duly authenticated, to the above Alfred Johnson; but from a mis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />take of the clerk to said investigating board, the said certificate stands as a rejected claim in the general Land Office, and a pat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent therefor is withheld;&#8212;Therefore,</p>
<pb n="408" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="402" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby, required to issue a patent to Alfred Johnson, on certificate No. 25, 2nd class, issued to Alexander D. Orr, by the Board of Land Commissioners for Bobertson county, in the same manner as if the same had been returned to the General Land Office as genuine and legal.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 18, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 236.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize John H. Reagan and his Associates to open and construct a turnpike road from the Town of Buffalo, on the Trinity river, across the bottom to the high land, on the west side, in the direction to the Town of Corsicana.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That John H. Reagan and his Associates, be, and they are hereby authorized to construct a turnpike road from the town of Buffalo, on the Trinity river, across the bottom thereof on the west side, in the direction to the town to Corsicana, to the high lands.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, lliat the said John H. Reagan and his associates shall have the right of way, together with timber and stone, upon such vacant and public lands through which said road may pass, which may be necessary for the construction of said road.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That so soon as the said John H. Reagan and his associates shall establish all necessary ferry boats, bridges, embankments, causeways, to render said road passable and safe at all seasons of the year, the said John H. Reagan and his associates shall be authorized to demand and receive the following tolls, viz: for each wagon or other car<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />riage, not to exceed ten cents per wheel; for each horse or mule and rider, ten cents; for loose horses, mules or cattle, not <pb n="409" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="403" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>to exceed five cents per head; tor each sheep, hog or goat, not to ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed two cents per head.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That there may he erected as many gates for the collec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of tolls as may be deemed necessary: Provided, no person shall be required to pay toll at more than one gate; And, further provid<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed, That persons travelling a part of the distance, shall be required to pay full toll, if such person cross the main river.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That if any person or persons shall travel upon said road or drive any horses, mules, cattle, sheep, hogs or goats, wagon or other carriage, without paying the tolls there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />for, or shall obstruct or damage the said road, then a right of action shall accrue to the said company, in any court having jurisdiction, to recover the tolls or damage sustained.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That should any person or per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons, using or travelling upon said turnpike, be detained or dam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />aged, either in his or her person or property, by reason of the inat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tention, negligence, inexperience or mal conduct, of any agent or other person employed by the company, then the said John H. Reagan and his associates shall be liable to the person or persons in an action in any court having competent jurisdiction, and that said turnpike may be seized and sold as other property, to satisfy any judgment thus obtained.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That said company shall enjoy, and exercise the privilege herein granted, for the term of twenty years from and after the completion of said turnpike; after which time it shall belong to the counties of Henderson and Navarro, in equal moieties.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That said John H. Reagan and his associates shall have three years to complete said turnpike road, and in ease the same is not completed, then this charter to be for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />feited.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 18, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="410" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="404" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 237.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of Garrison Greenwood.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, a certificate for one league and one labor of land, was on the first day of February, 1838, issued by the Board of Land Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners for San Augustine County, to Isaac Campbell, as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />signee of Harrison Graham, and assigned by said Campbell, on the 16th of March, 1838, to Garrison Greenwood, which certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate was curtailed by the Board investigating Land Commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers to one-third of a league, Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of tbe State of Texas, That certificate No. 166, which issued to Isaac Campbell, assignee of Harrison Graham, from the Board of Land Commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers of San Augustine County, on the first day of February, 1838, calling for one league and one labor of land be, and the same is hereby declared good against the State for one-third of a league of land only; and the Commissioner of the General Land Office, is hereby directed to issue a patent thereon, to Garrison Greenwood, assignee of Isaac Campbell, whenever the field notes for said certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate may be returned to the Land Office, as in other cases, and that this Joint Resolution take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 18, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 238.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate Cherokee Academy in the town of Rusk in the County of Cherokee.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Joseph L. Hogg, L. H. Dillard, T. J. Moore, B. B. Cannon, J. H. Parsons, J. F. Henry, and E. L. Givens, be, and they are hereby appointed and incorporated a body pol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />itic, under the name and style of the trustees of Cherokee Acad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />emy, capable of suing and being sued, pleading and being im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleaded, of holding property, either real, personal or mixed; of <pb n="411" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="405" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>selling and conveying the same at pleasure, and of doing and per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />forming whatsoever else that may be proper and necessary to be done for the advancement of said institution, not contrary to the Constitution and laws of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this charter and privilege shall extend to the said trustees and their successors in office, so long as they confine the benefit of the same to the advancement of the sciences and the promotion of useful knowledge to the rising generation.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the said institution may he accessible alike to all, without regard to opinions of religion or poli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That a majority of said trustees shall fill all vacancies which may occur from any cause whatever, under such rules and regulations as said majority may think best for the benefit of said academy, so as to have at all times, as nearly as may be, a full board of trustees for said institution.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the said trustees shall elect, by a majority thereof, a President and such other officers as they may deem necessary, and fill vacancies therein when they may oc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cur, and may enact such by-laws, rules and regulations, for the gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment of said academy, as may seem to them necessary for that object.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the institution aforesaid shall be located upon the lot appropriated by the Commisisoners of Cherokee County, appointed to locate the County site thereof, where J. B. Mitchell, A. M., is now teaching, in the town of Rusk in said County.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 18, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 239.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the town of San Augustine.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of <pb n="412" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="406" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Texas, That the citizens of the town of San Augustine be, and they are hereby declared a body corporate, by the name and title of the Incorporation of the Town of San Augustine, and by that name may sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, and may hold and dispose of real and personal estate.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the limits of said corporation shall be one half mile square, or contain one hundred and sixty acres of land, hav<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the public square of said town in the centre thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That an election for a mayor, six aldermen, a treasurer, a recorder and a constable shall be held in June, 1848, by the Chief<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Justice of San Augustine county, or one of the Commissioners thereof, and annually thereafter for a similar purpose an election shall he conducted by the mayor, or a majority of the aldermen act<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing at the time of such election, and the persons elected shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in office one year or until their successors are duly qualified, and the annual election for mayor and aldermen shall be held at such place in the town as may be designated by the board for the convenience of the people.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That whenever a vacancy shall occur in the office of mayor, a majority of the aldermen acting shall order and conduct an election to fill such vacancy, and the person so elected shall hold the office until the nest regular election or until his successor be duly qualified, and in case of the death, resignation, or removal of any alderman, treasurer, or constable the mayor shall order an election, under such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the board to fill such vacancy.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That no person shall he eligible to the office of mayor or alderman, constable or treasurer, unless such person be a citizen of said town.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the mayor shall be president ol the board of alder<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men; that four of the members of said board shall constitute a quorum to transact business, and that said board may enact such by-laws for the government of said town, not inconsistent with the Constitution and laws of the State, as may be deemed proper, and may impose fines for the disobedience of the same, not exceeding twenty dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the board of aldermen shall have and exercise control oxer the public square and streets in said town, and may compel all free male citizens, (ministers of the Gospel ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cepted) over the age of sixteen and under forty-five, to work on the same: Provided, that such persons shall not be required to <pb n="413" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="407" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>work more than ten days in any one year, and they shall he exempt from other road duty in said county, and the board may impose such fines on defaulters as they may deem necessary, in which the board shall be governed by the laws of this State, regulating roads.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That the board of aldermen shall have power to levy a tax on all persons and property, both real and personal, in said town, subject to a taxation by the laws of this State: Provided, that the tax on property shall not in any one year exceed one half of one per cent. ad valorem, on such property, and no tax shall be levied unless by two-thirds of the members present, which shall be as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sessed and collected by the constable in the same manner as the State tax is collected.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That the board of aldermen shall have power to appoint such additional officers, with the regulations of their duties and compensation as may he necessary, and may require of them bond, with security, to the mayor, in such sum as may be deemed requi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />site to compel the efficient discharge of such duties as may he as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />signed them.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That all offences against the by-laws be prosecuted be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore the mayor, and governed by the law organizing Justice Courts, and the constable shall execute and return all writs issued by the mayor in the same manner as is provided by law defining the du<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of constables.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That the constables shall give bond and security, as required of other constables, and shall have the same power and be entitled to the same fees for similar services.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That the mayor of said town shall he entitled to such fees as may he allowed instices of the peace for similar services, together with such other compensation as may he allowed him by a majority of the aldermen present at the time of such allowance.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That the aldermen shall be entitled to such compensa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion as may be allowed them by a majority of the board: Provided, that in no ease shall the same exceed two dollars per day for each day they may be required to sit as such aldermen.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That the treasurer shall keep safely all the money of said corporation, shall pay out the same upon the order of the board, and shall do such other duty as may be assigned him by the by-laws; he shall give bond, with security payable to the mayor, in such sum as may be deemed proper, conditioned for the faithful performance of his duties to be approved by the <pb n="414" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="408" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>board, and shall be allowed such compensation as may be specified by the board of aldermen.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. That the mayor be and he is hereby vested with all the powers and jurisdiction of a justice of the peace, within the limits of said corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. That the hooks and records of the corporation shall, at all times, be open to the examination of any citizen of said town.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. That all laws and parts of laws contravening the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act he repealed, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 18, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 240.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution to authorize the Comptroller of the State of Texas to settle with R. S. Neighbors.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller be and he is hereby required to audit and pass upon the claims and accounts of R. S. Neighbors, late Quartermaster and Commissary in the Army of the Republic of Texas for the years 1839, &#8217;4.0, and &#8217;41.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this Joint Resolution take effect from and after its passage</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 18, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 241.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of the legal heirs of Mark Noble, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office is <pb n="415" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="409" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>hereby required to issue to the heirs of Mark Noble, deceased, an unconditional certificate for six hundred and forty acres of land, and issue a patent thereon, after the same shall have been surveyed according to law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this Joint Resolution be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 18, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 242.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution authorizing and requiring the Comptroller of Public accounts to issue warrants paying A. B. Gray for services, in running and marking the Eastern Boundary Line of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller be authorized and required to pay A. B. Gray, late engineer and surveyor, for services in running and marking the eastern boundary line of Texas, in three several, drafts of three hundred dollars each; the first payable out of any money in the treasury not otherwise appropriated, at any time af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter the first day of May next; and the second payable as above, for three hundred dollars at any time after the first day of October next: and the third for three hundred dollars, payable at any time after the first day of January, 1849.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Comptroller is hereby authorized to issue a cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate to the said A. B. Gray, for eight hundred and sixteen dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars, payable at any time after the first day of December, A. D. 1849, out of any moneys in the treasury not otherwise appropriated: Provided, the said A. B. Gray shall receipt to the Comptroller, in full, for services in running and surveying the eastern boundary line of Texas: and that this joint resolution shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>March 20, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="416" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="410" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 243.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to Incorporate the Milam Liberal Institute.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That George B. Erath, George Green, Isaac Cook, E. R. Hubby, Daniel Monroe, William Lampkin, and J. J. Turnham, and their successors in office, be, and they are hereby incorporated a body politic, under the name and style of the Milam Liberal Insti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tute, capable of suing and being sued, of pleading and being im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleaded, of holding property, either real, personal or mixed, of sell<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing and conveying the same at pleasure, of having a common seal, and changing the same at pleasure, and of doing and performing whatever else that may be proper and necessary to be done for the advancement of said Institution, not contrary to the Constitution and laws of this State: Provided, That the real and personal prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty acquired shall not at any time exceed twenty thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this charter and privilege shall extend to the aforesaid trustees and their successors in office, as long as they confine the benefits of the same to the advancement of the sciences, and the promotion of useful knowledge to the rising, generation, which Institution shall be accessible alike to all, without regard to opinions of religion or politics.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That on the first Saturday in January, 1850, (until which time present trustees shall hold their office,) and biennially there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after, the subscribers to said Institution shall elect seven trustees for the ensuing two years: Provided, That no one shall be consid<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ered a subscriber who has not subscribed or paid ten dollars for the use of said Institution, other than tuition fees.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the trustees for the time being shall choose from among their number a presiding officer, and they shall have full power to enact by-laws, rules and regulations for the government of said Academy, as may seem to them necessary for that object.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the Institution herein created shall be located at or near the town of Cameron, in Milam country.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 20, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="417" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="411" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 244.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Michael Short.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner General of the Land Office may, and he is hereby, required to issue a patent for one league and labor of Land to Michael Short, in accordance with the field notes returned to the General Land Office, by John James, District Surveyor for the county of Bexar, upon a certificate issued by the Board of Land Commissioners of Brazoria county, No. 447.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the title to said land shall he deemed as legally vested in said Short, as if all the requisitions of the law had been complied with; and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 20, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 245.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of Theodore D. Maltby, John Her<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vey, and Nathaniel R. Mallon, who were disabled for life in the service of the country.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby required to issue to Theodore D. Maltby, John Hervey, and Nathaniel R. Mallon, each, a certificate for one league and one labor of land, to be located on any vacant and unappropriated lands of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further Resolved, That when the survey shall he made, and field notes returned on the same, in accordance with law, it is hereby made the duty of the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue patents thereon.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 20, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="418" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="412" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 246.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Houston Lyceum.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section. 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Abner Cooke, Peter W. Gray, William C. Gould, E. A. Palmer, William F. Weeks, James Walker, C. McAnnelly, T. M. Bagby, and their associates and successors, be, and they are hereby constituted a body politic and corporate, for the encouragement of literary and scientific pursuits, by the name and style of the Hous<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton Lyceum; may sue and be sued, prosecute and defend in any of the courts of this State; may grant, purchase and receive by its corporate name real and personal property not exceeding twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />five thousand dollars in value; may have a common seal, with any device upon the same the Lyceum may determine, to be altered or changed at the will of said Lyceum; may adopt such a constitution, by-laws and regulations for the management of the affairs of the Lyceum as the regular members thereof may deem proper, not con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trary to the Constitution and laws of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The library, cabinet, and apparatus of the Lyceum shall be exempt and free from all taxation: but the balance of the prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty thereof shall be regularly given in for taxation by such officer as the Lyceum may direct, according to the provisions of the tax laws of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act of incorporation shall he subject to such modification, extensions, and limitations as the Legislature may from time to time provide.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 20, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="419" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="413" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 247.</head>
<opener>
<salute>A Joint Resolution for the relief of Luis Thuner.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of General Land Office be, and he is hereby required to issue a patent to Luis Thuner, for twelve hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and eighty acres of land, on conditional certificate No. 1035, issued by the board of Land Commissioners of Harrisburg county, and dated November the 2d, A. D. 1838, without the necessity of his procuring an unconditional certificate.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this Joint Resolution be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 20, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 248.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Seth Marvin.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the claim of Seth Marvin for sixty days service, up to the 7th March, 1842, as a minute man, in the San Patricio Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, under the command of W. J. Carnes, be, and the same is hereby audited to the amount of sixty dollars, and the State Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer is hereby authorized to pay to said Marvin, one-half of said amount, out of the unexpended balance of the appropriation made on the 3d February, 1842.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act shall be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>March 20, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="420" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="414" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 249.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the town of Mount Pleasant, in the county of Titus.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the citizens of Mount Pleasant be, and they are hereby declared a body corporate and politic, under the name and style of the corporation of the town of Mount Pleasant, and that they be entitled to and have extended to them, all the privileges, and be, in all respects governed by the provisions of &#8220;an act for the incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration of the town of Bonham, in the county of Fannin,&#8221; approved, February 2d, 1848.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 20, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 250.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of E. B. Cogswell.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller of Public Accounts be, and he is hereby required to issue to E. B. Cogswell duplicates for four Cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates of Land Scrip issued to him by Thomas Toby, on the twelfth day of August, A. D. 1836, for six hundred and forty acres, which Certificates of Scrip were numbered 476, 477, 478, and 479.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That said duplicates shall have all the virtue in law that the original certificates could have had, and that this Joint Resolution be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 20, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="421" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="415" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 251.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the eighteenth section of &#8220;an act to incorporate the City of Anstin,&#8221; passed 11th May, A. D. 1846.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the eighteenth section of &#8220;an act to incorporate the City of Austin,&#8221; passed 11th May, A. D. 1846, shall be, and is here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by amended, so that it shall hereafter read as follows, viz: that the City Council shall have power to levy and collect a city tax upon all property, persons and occupations, in the limits of the city, on which a tax is levied by the State, provided, that such tax shall not exceed one eighth the amount of the State tax upon such property, persons and occupations, and, provided, also, that such tax shall be levied in the month of January in each year.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 20, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 252.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of Ford and Cronican.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by tire Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of three hundred and fifty-nine dollars and eighty-five cents be, and the same is hereby appropriated to pay Ford and Cronican for transcribing the laws passed by the last Legislature, and for affixing marginal notes to the same, provided that the above amount shall be in full for all the demands of the said Ford and Cronican as Public Printers, against the State up to the commencement of the present session of the Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That the Comptroller of Pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic Accounts be, and he is hereby required to draw his war<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rant on the Treasury in favor of Ford and Cronican for the above amount on receiving a properly authenticated copy of <pb n="422" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="416" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>this Joint Resolution, and that the same take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 20, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 253.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the town of Jefferson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all the free white inhabitants thereof, shall be a body corporate, by the name of the mayor and aldermen of the town of Jefferson, and by that name, they and their successors, shall be known in law, and be capable of suing and of being sued, in all courts of this State, and shall have a common seal, and by the same, shall be capable of holding and conveying property, real and personal, for the use of said corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That there shall be a mayor and five aldermen of said town, and as many subordinate officers, elected by the citizens of said town as may be necessary to enforce all the laws and regula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions of said corporation, which said officers shall, before they enter upon the discharge of the duties assigned them, shall take and sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribe an oath before some officer authorized to administer the same, that they will faithfully and promptly discharge, all the du<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties assigned them, under this act and the laws regulating the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the first mayor and aldermen, shall be elected by a vote by ballot of all citizens of said town, who have resided with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />in the corporate limits thereof, for the term of three months, which election shall be held, by the Chief Justice of the county of Cass, after giving ten days notice, in three public places in said town, and said election shall be conducted in accordance with the laws regulat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing elections of county officers, held annually, on the first Monday in January, and when so elected and qualified as aforesaid, they shall have full power, and authority to make and pass such ordinances as they shall deem necessary to maintain the cleanliness and salu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />brity of said town; to secure the safety and convenience of passing in the streets and squares, ways, lanes and other public streets and <pb n="423" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="417" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>alleys; to fix the squaring and to prevent any encroachment or other undertaking on the said streets; to determine the completion and dimensions, the maintenance and repair of pavements in said streets, at the cost of the proprietors of houses, lands or neighbor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing lots, to fix the place or places of landing and anchoring for all water crafts, in the stream adjacent thereto; to establish an active system of inspection over the slaves of said town; and those em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ployed in any water craft, that may be at such landing; to estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lish a town guard or patrols; to provide for the lighting the streets; to determine in what part of the town, wooden chimneys shall be allowed to be erected; to prevent gunpowder being stored within the town and suburbs, in such quantity as to endanger the public safety; to determine on the means to be resorted to extinguish con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />flagration and to prevent the same; to regulate the service of per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons employed in working fire engines; to permit or forbid all pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic amusements; whenever the preservation of order, tranquility or public safety may require it; to establish market places; to erect all public buildings; to determine the mode of inspection, for all mar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ketable commodities, sold publicly in said town; to regulate every thing which relates to bakers, butchers, tavern keepers, and all establishments in which liquors or food of any kind are sold, or per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons keeping any public house whatever; to regulate the prices of draymen and teamsters, water carriers, to erect bridges whenever the public convenience of the citizens of said town may require it, and to make all other regulations which may contribute to the bet<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter administration of the affairs of said corporation, as well as for the maintenance of the tranquility and safety of the same, provided, that, no ordinance of said corporation shall be enforced, that is con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trary to any law of this State, or of the United States: and all official acts of said corporation shall be sanctioned by a majority of all the members of the same, except the levying of a tax, which shall require the votes of two-thirds of the members of said cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That so soon as the first mayor and aldermen are quali<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied under the provisions of this act, they shall proceed to lay off the corporate limits of said town, to include the lands covered by the head right certificates of Allen Urqua<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />hart and Stephen Smith, and divide the same into five wards, in each of which, in all subsequent elections, there shall he elected, one alderman, by a majority of all the voters living in said ward; and that said mayor shall be elected, by a majority of all the <pb n="424" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="418" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>votes of said corporation, and said mayor and aldermen, shall elect from among their number, a Recorder and Treasurer, and from among the citizens of said town, an officer to be styled the town constable, who shall perform such duties as may be assigned him by said mayor and aldermen. The said mayor and aldermen shall keep a record of all their official acts, which shall be at all times open for inspection for the public, and pass all by-laws for their own government.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That no ordinance shall take effect or he enforced until the same has been published for five days, in said corporation, and all sums of money collected, from any source whatever, shall be collected by the town constable, or Treasurer in such manner, and under such regulations as may be made by the mayor and aider<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men; and no tax shall ever be imposed at a higher rate than the State tax assessed upon the same property, nor any person be fined for the violation of any ordinance, more than the sum of fifty dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That all his expenses and official acts of the said corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration, shall he published once, every six months, except the ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nances and by laws, which shall be published forthwith, after their enactment; and that all resident citizens of said town, who pay taxes to said corporation, shall not be required to work on roads and highways.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the mayor of said corporation, shall have the same jurisdiction over offences committed against the by-laws and ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nances of said corporation, as justices of the peace; and that a town constable shall have the same power and authority as a constable, in enforcing the laws of the State, and shall be governed in all their official acts, by the laws of the State, governing justices of the peace and constables, and that all taxes assessed by said corporation, shall be collected under the laws regulating the collection of taxes for the State.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 20, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="425" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="419" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 254.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution authorizing the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue a patent to Edward Hall,</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land office be, and he is hereby required to issue a patent for one League of land to Edward Hall, by virtue of a resolution of the Consultation &#8220;grant<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing him a donation of one League of land&#8221; passed November 9th. 1835, on the presentation of a copy of said resolution and the field notes of the survey at the General Land Office.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 20, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 255.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the German Texian Friendship Association of Galveston.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That D. E. Rump, H. W. Wagner, E. W. Bumgarten, and their successors and associates in office be, and they are hereby con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stituted a body corporate and politic for the promotion of educa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion morality and benevolence under the name and style of &#8220;the German Texian Friendship Association,&#8221; and by that name, may receive, hold, enjoy sell, convey and alienate property real and per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonal, provided the amount so held shall at no time exceed in value twenty-five thousand dollars, and by the aforesaid name may sue and be sued, defend and be defended, in any Court of law or equity within this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That said Association shall have power to make such by-laws as they may deem necessary for their own government not contrary to the Constitution and laws of this State and may elect from their own body all the officers necessary for conducting the business of the Association.</p>
<pb n="426" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="420" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the privileges hereby con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred, shall extend to the present trustees and their successors in office so long as they confine their action to the promotion of edu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cation and benevolence.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 20, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 256.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Galveston Steam Ferry, Freight and Tow Boat Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That A. C. Crawford, Albert Ball, Joshua C. Straw, A. Bal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dinger and Stephen Southwick, together with such other persons as shall associate with them for the purposes hereinafter mentioned, shall be, and they are hereby created a body corporate and politic under the name and style of the Galveston Steam Perry, Freight and Tow Boat Company, and by this right, and under this title to transfer their right by succession or assignment, and as such shall be capable of suing and being sued, answering and being answered unto, defending and being defended in all Courts of law or equity, to have a common seal, and the same to use and alter, and of purchasing, holding, leasing selling and conveying estates, either real, personal or mixed, to receive donations, borrow money, and to have, exercise and enjoy all the rights and privileges incident to corporations so far as may be necessary to carry out the objects for which said company is created and not inconsistent with the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution of this State and the United States.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Capital stock of said Company shall be one hundred thousand dollars and the same to be divided into shares of twenty-five dollars each.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That said Company shall have full power to transport passengers, cattle, produce or any and all other species of property or freight from any point on Galveston Island to any other point on the waters of Galveston Bay or any of the trib<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="427" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="421" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>utaries thereof, or from any such place or places to Galveston Island, to tow vessels in, and out of Galveston Harbor, and to do and perform all other matters necessary and proper to promote those objects.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That all vessels towed into, or out of the port of Galves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />n, &#8220; any of the boats or vessels of said Company, shall be exempt from the payment of pilotage whenever pilot service has not been reouqred.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the management of the affairs of said Company shall be by a board of seven directors, each of whom shall own at least ten shares of the stock of said Company, a majority of whom shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. They shall appoint one of their number a President, and shall fill such vacancies as may occur in their board, from death, resignation or otherwise, and shall hold their office for one year, and until others are elected in their stead.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That said President and Directors shall have power to fix once in each year a uniform rate of ferriage, freight and ton<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nage to be charged by said Company: to appoint employ and fix the compensation of such subordinate officers, agents and servants, as the affairs of the company may require, and to make all needful by-laws, rules and regulations for the government of the affairs of said Company and not inconsistent with this act, and such general rules and directions as may be adopted by the stockholders at any regular meeting.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That books for the subscription of stock shall be opened on or after the tenth day of April, 1848, at the City of Galveston under the superintendence of Alfred F. James, James Croni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />can and John U. Durst, or any two of them, acting as Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners, and shall remain open until the entire amount of stock is subscribed for; and five dollars in cash shall be paid said Commissioners for every share of stock so sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed for at the time of subscribing; that as soon as four hundred shares of said stock shall be subscribed for, and the said five dollars paid upon each share, the said Commissioners shall call a meeting of the stockholders at which the Company shall be organized by the election of directors. As soon as directors are elected, said Commissioners shall hand over to them the subscription books and all such monies as shall have been paid them on payment of, stock, each stockholder shall be entitled <pb n="428" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="422" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>to one vote for every share of stock owned by him, and may either vote in person or by proxy.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That said Board of Directors may at any time call upon the stockholders for the payment of any additional instalments upon said stock that may he required by the wants of the Company, in case any instalment so ordered shall remain unpaid for the space of thirty days beyond the time fixed by the Directors for payment thereon, the owner or owners thereof shall forfeit the same to the Company, together with all previous payments made thereon, and the books of the Company shall be open for the subscription of an amount sufficient to make up the deficiency.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That the Directors shall make declare and pay to the stockholders such dividends as may result from the profits of the business of the Company, at such time and in such manner as they may be directed by the stockholders at any regular meeting there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />of, provided, that no such dividend shall impair or in any way les<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sen the capital stock of the company or such part thereof as shall have been paid in at the time of making such dividend.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That said Company shall keep a regular set of books, upon which shall be entered and kept a correct account of all the receipts and disbursements, by and from said Company, which book shall be opened to the inspection of any stockholder.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That this act shall take effect from and after its pas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March, 20, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 257.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Goliad Statistical Society.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the present and associate members of the Goliad Statistical Society and their successors shall be a body politic and corporate; the society may adopt such ordinances (not in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />consistent with the Constitution and laws of the general and <pb n="429" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="423" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>State Government) as it may deem proper for its organization and for conducting its affairs. The leading objects being to obtain and diffuse statistical knowledge, particularly concerning the south<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />western part of the United States with the adjacent country. The society may hold real and personal property, not to exceed twenty thousand dollars in value at any one time, and may dispose of any part thereof, or the whole at pleasure, but subject to the payment of any debt then existing against the society, which shall not con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tract debts amounting at any particular time to more than one thousand dollars.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 20, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 258.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of Allen Kellough.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Adjutant General be, and is hereby authorized and required to issue to Allen Kellough, land scrip for one thousand six hundred and fifty-nine acres of land, to be surveyed at his own ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pense, on any unappropriated domain in the State; provided; that the said Kellough shall file in the Adjutant General&#8217;s office, his written relinquishment to all demands against the State for mili<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary services.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 20, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="430" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="424" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 259.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution authorizing M. M. Potter to draw the mileage and per diem of the Hon. Richard Bache; Senator from Galveston, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That M. M. Potter be, and he is hereby authorized to draw the mileage and per diem pay of Hon, Richard Bache, deceased, for his services during the second session of the State Legislature, and that the accounting officer of the Treasury Department audit the same, and that this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 20, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 260.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution granting leave of absence to Janies B. Shaw, Comptroller of Public Accounts.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Janies B. Shaw, Comptroller of Public Accounts, be allowed leave of absence for the term of six weeks from his office during the year 1848, and that this Joint Resolution take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 20, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 261.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to an act to incorporate the town of Kefugio.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all persons residing within the limits of the town <pb n="431" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="425" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>tract of Refugio who are entitled to vote for members of the Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature under the Constitution and laws of this State shall be deemed qualified electors and shall be permitted to vote for Mayor, Aider<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man, or any other officer created under said act of incorporation to which this is a supplement.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That all property belonging to said town tract of Refugio which shall hereafter be offered for sale by said corporate authorities shall be sold at public auction, after giving notice of said sale by publishing the same in the nearest newspaper for at least sixty days previous to the sale of said prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty, and provided that not more than one fourth of said town lots and one fourth of said farm lots shall be sold during any one year.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That all sales of property belong<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing to said town tract of Refugio which sale hereafter be made con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trary to the provisions of this act shall be void.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in. force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 20, 1848</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="432" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="426" /><fw type="header" place="top">Certificate.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">STATE OF TEXAS.</head>
<p>I, the undersigned, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, certify that the second Legislature of said State commenced its session at the City of Austin, on Monday, the thirteenth day of December, in the year one thousand eight hundred and forty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />seven, and adjourned on the twentieth day of March, in the year one thousand eight hundred and forty-eight.</p>
<p>And I further certify, that the Acts and Joint Resolutions con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained in this Part and Volume, are true copies of the original rolls deposited in the Department of State, with which they have been carefully compared.</p>
<p>[L. s. Given under my hand and official seal, at the city of Austin, the fifth day of May, one thousand eight hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and forty-eight, and of the independence of Texas the thirteenth year.</p>
<closer>
<signed>W. D. MILLER.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="433" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="i" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX TO SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">INCORPORATIONS.</head>
<p>Brazos Canal Company, (amended) .............<ref>182</ref> <ref>348</ref></p>
<p>City of Austin, (amended) ..............................<ref>251</ref> <ref>415</ref></p>
<p>Houston, (amended) 	......................<ref>202</ref> <ref>366</ref></p>
<p>Laredo   .........................<ref>176</ref> <ref>337</ref></p>
<p>Lavaca .......................... <ref>209</ref> <ref>376</ref></p>
<p>Macogdoches  .................... <ref>226</ref> <ref>389</ref></p>
<p>Cherokee Academy................... <ref>238</ref> <ref>404</ref></p>
<p>Galveston and Red River Railway Company.......... <ref>204</ref> <ref>370</ref></p>
<p>Galveston Steam, Ferry, Freight and Tow-boat Company .................................... <ref>256</ref> <ref>420</ref></p>
<p>German Texian Friendship Association................. <ref>255</ref> <ref>419</ref></p>
<p>Goliad Statistical Society.................. <ref>257</ref> <ref>422</ref></p>
<p>Guadalupe College............. <ref>179</ref> <ref>345</ref></p>
<p>Houston Mechanics’ Institute ...................... <ref>203</ref> <ref>369</ref></p>
<p>Houston Lyceum................................. <ref>246</ref> <ref>412</ref></p>
<p>Huntsville Male Institute....................... <ref>232</ref> <ref>398</ref></p>
<p>Montgomery Academy....................	<ref>205</ref> <ref>373</ref></p>
<p>Milam Liberal Institute............................ <ref>243</ref> <ref>410</ref></p>
<p>Protection Fire Company, No. 1, City of Houston.... <ref>173</ref> <ref>335</ref></p>
<p>Bepublican Academy............. <ref>230</ref> <ref>396</ref></p>
<p>Town of Bonham  ..................... <ref>177</ref> <ref>341</ref></p>
<p>Goliad.................... <ref>229</ref> <ref>393</ref></p>
<p>Jefferson............................ <ref>253</ref> <ref>416</ref></p>
<p>Montgomery.......................  <ref>191</ref> <ref>355</ref></p>
<pb n="434" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="ii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Mount Pleasant ....................... <ref>249</ref> <ref>414</ref></p>
<p>Paris, (amended)........................... <ref>198</ref> <ref>361</ref></p>
<p>Palestine.............................. <ref>212</ref> <ref>380</ref></p>
<p>Refugio. .......................... <ref>261</ref> <ref>424</ref></p>
<p>San Augustine........................ <ref>239</ref> <ref>405</ref></p>
<p>Springfield. ............................. <ref>197</ref> <ref>360</ref></p>
<p>Union Marine and Fire Insurance Company............... <ref>170</ref> <ref>330</ref></p>
<p>University of Eastern Texas......................... <ref>200</ref> <ref>362</ref></p>
<p>Williamson Academy.............................. <ref>214</ref> <ref>381</ref></p>
<p>Western Texas Orphan Asylum....................... <ref>231</ref> <ref>397</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">RELIEF, &#38;c.</head>
<p>Austin City—owner of certain half lot................... <ref>221</ref> <ref>386</ref></p>
<p>Beale, Robert H......................................... <ref>228</ref> <ref>393</ref></p>
<p>Bowlin, Jeremiah—heirs of............................... <ref>183</ref> <ref>349</ref></p>
<p>Brigance, Alfred........................................ <ref>233</ref> <ref>400</ref></p>
<p>Browning, Christopher Columbus.......................... <ref>220</ref> <ref>385</ref></p>
<p>Cartwright, Jesse H..................................... <ref>195</ref> <ref>358</ref></p>
<p>Catlin, J. Harris....................................... <ref>217</ref> <ref>383</ref></p>
<p>City of Galveston—to appoint firemen.................... <ref>180</ref> <ref>347</ref></p>
<p>County of Galveston—to establish Public Schools......... <ref>167</ref> <ref>325</ref></p>
<p>City of Austin—owner of certain city half lot.......... <ref>221</ref> <ref>386</ref></p>
<p>Cogswell, E. B.......................................... <ref>250</ref> <ref>414</ref></p>
<p>Covington, Charles—ferry privilege...................... <ref>196</ref> <ref>3591</ref></p>
<p>Crump, William E.—to construct turnpike................. <ref>190</ref> <ref>354</ref></p>
<p>Delany, Isaac........................................... <ref>208</ref> <ref>376</ref></p>
<p>Evans, Moses............................................ <ref>207</ref> <ref>375</ref></p>
<p>Ford &#38; Cronican......................................... <ref>252</ref> <ref>415</ref></p>
<p>Galveston City—to appoint firemen....................... <ref>180</ref> <ref>347</ref></p>
<p>Galveston County—to establish Public Schools............ <ref>167</ref> <ref>325</ref></p>
<p>Gray, Eli............................................... <ref>213</ref> <ref>381</ref></p>
<p>Gray, Ann Eliza......................................... <ref>213</ref> <ref>381</ref></p>
<p>Gray, A. B............................................... <ref>242</ref> <ref>409</ref></p>
<p>Greenwood, Garrison..................................... <ref>237</ref> <ref>404</ref></p>
<p>Hale, Edward............................................ <ref>254</ref> <ref>419</ref></p>
<p>Hervey, John............................................ <ref>245</ref> <ref>411</ref></p>
<p>Homes, J. L.,—widow and heirs of........................ <ref>192</ref> <ref>357</ref></p>
<p>Holland, Elijah D....................................... <ref>172</ref> <ref>334</ref></p>
<p>Hutchinson, Nancy—-ferry privilege...................... <ref>163</ref> <ref>323</ref></p>
<p>Johnson, Alfred......................................... <ref>235</ref> <ref>401</ref></p>
<p>Johnson, S. L........................................... <ref>224</ref> <ref>388</ref></p>
<pb n="435" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Johnson, James F. ............................ <ref>234</ref> <ref>401</ref></p>
<p>Jordan, Alexander, dece’d—succession transferred.... <ref>216</ref> <ref>383</ref></p>
<p>Helton, Sarah Ann.................................... <ref>194</ref> <ref>358</ref></p>
<p>Ivellough, Allen........................... <ref>258</ref> <ref>423</ref></p>
<p>Neiser, John................................... <ref>181</ref> <ref>348</ref></p>
<p>Long, Zachary Taylor................................. <ref>210</ref> <ref>379</ref></p>
<p>Mallon, Nathaniel R.	.................................. <ref>245</ref> <ref>411</ref></p>
<p>Marvin, Seth..................................... <ref>248</ref> <ref>413</ref></p>
<p>Maltby, Theodore D. .......................<ref>245</ref> <ref>411</ref></p>
<p>McNairy, John S. ...........................<ref>165</ref> <ref>324</ref>.</p>
<p>Miller, Mary Ann.................................. <ref>184</ref> <ref>350</ref></p>
<p>Miller, Robert Franklin............................ <ref>175</ref> <ref>337</ref></p>
<p>Moore, E. W.—Post Captain........................ <ref>168</ref> <ref>328</ref></p>
<p>Moore, E. W.—Post Captain......................... <ref>187</ref> <ref>351</ref></p>
<p>Navy—persons furnishing supplies....................... <ref>169</ref> <ref>329</ref></p>
<p>Neighbors, E. S. ..........................<ref>240</ref> <ref>408</ref></p>
<p>New Braunfels, city of...................... <ref>223</ref> <ref>387</ref></p>
<p>Noble, Mark—heirs of.......................... <ref>241</ref> <ref>408</ref></p>
<p>Northington, Andrew........................ <ref>166</ref> <ref>324</ref></p>
<p>Nunn, William P.—heirs of........................ <ref>186</ref> <ref>350</ref></p>
<p>Perry, Stuart..................................... <ref>218</ref> <ref>384</ref></p>
<p>Plncker, William................................. <ref>189</ref> <ref>353</ref></p>
<p>Potter, M. M.—to draw pay for Hon. R. Bache, Sen., deceased................................... <ref>259</ref> <ref>424</ref></p>
<p>Public Schools—established in Galveston county..... <ref>167</ref> <ref>325</ref></p>
<p>Eeagan, John H.—to construct a turnpike............ <ref>236</ref> <ref>402</ref></p>
<p>Peels, Patrick—heirs of........................ <ref>193</ref> <ref>357</ref></p>
<p>Sanchez, Louis.................................. <ref>215</ref> <ref>382</ref></p>
<p>Shaw, James B., Comptroller — leave of absence granted. ................................ <ref>260</ref> <ref>424</ref></p>
<p>Short, Michael................................ <ref>244</ref> <ref>411</ref></p>
<p>Smith, Henry M. .................................<ref>225</ref> <ref>389</ref></p>
<p>Staleup, Mary Melicia. ....................... <ref>185</ref> <ref>350</ref></p>
<p>Stalcup, Rhesa Green....................... <ref>184</ref> <ref>350</ref></p>
<p>Steel, Thomas J. ............................<ref>227</ref> <ref>392</ref></p>
<p>Sterne, Adolphus, assignee.................... <ref>171</ref> <ref>334</ref></p>
<p>Stewart, James......................... <ref>206</ref> <ref>375</ref></p>
<p>Stean, Jr., William.......................... <ref>178</ref> <ref>344</ref></p>
<p>Taylor, Kisiah........................ <ref>211</ref> <ref>379</ref></p>
<p>Terrell, Ann........................... <ref>201</ref> <ref>365</ref></p>
<p>Thuner, Luis................................. <ref>247</ref> <ref>413</ref></p>
<p>Van Zandt, Isaac, deceased—probate of will <ref>174</ref> <ref>336</ref></p>
<p>Yanderworth, John........................... <ref>222</ref> <ref>387</ref></p>
<pb n="436" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iv" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Walker, Martin.......................... <ref>164</ref> <ref>323</ref></p>
<p>Wallace, J. W. E. ......................<ref>199</ref> <ref>362</ref></p>
<p>Weyman, Edward A. ..........................<ref>188</ref> <ref>352</ref></p>
<p>Wallace, James P. ..........................<ref>219</ref> <ref>385</ref></p>
<p>Weyman, Edward E. .............................<ref>188</ref> <ref>352</ref></p>
<p>WiÌliamson, P. M. ..............................<ref>219</ref> <ref>385</ref></p>
<p>Winfree, Jacob F.—to adopt Zachary Taylor Long..... <ref>210</ref> <ref>379</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CAPTIONS&#8212;SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<p>Page</p>
<p>An act to grant a ferry privilege to Nancy Hutchinson ............ <ref>323</ref></p>
<p>An act for the relief of Martin Walker............................ <ref>323</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution for the relief of John S. McNairy, of Nashville, Tennessee................................................ <ref>324</ref></p>
<p>An act to authorize the Treasurer and Comptroller to pay over and deliver to Andrew Northington, assignee of the heirs of Caleb Kemp, the money and papers deposited with them by William J. Maynard, administrator of the estate of said Caleb Kemp... ... <ref>324</ref></p>
<p>An act to establish Public Schools in the county of Galveston......... <ref>325</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution to provide for a settlement of the claims of E. W. Moore, Post Captain, commanding the late Navy of Texas, on account of cash advances made for the use of said Navy.. ..... <ref>328</ref></p>
<p>Joint Resolution for the relief of persons who furnished supplies on the credit of post captain E. W. Moore, for the use of the navy of the late Republic of Texas, while commanded by said post captain E. W. Moore..............................        ......... <ref>329</ref></p>
<p>An act to incorporate the Union Marine and Fire Insurance Company.. <ref>330</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution authorizing the Adjutant General to issue a bounty land warrant to Elijah D. Holland.................. <ref>334</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution authorizing the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue a patent in the name of Adolphus Sterne, assignee Maria Josefa Sanches.</p>
<p>An act to incorporate Protection Fire Company No. 1, city of Houston. <ref>335</ref></p>
<p>An act for the relief of the heirs of Isaac Van Zandt, deceased ...... <ref>336</ref></p>
<p>An act to make Robert Franklin Miller the Lawful heir of Solomon Miller........... <ref>337</ref></p>
<p>An act for the incorporation of the city of Laredo.......... <ref>337</ref></p>
<p>An act to incorporate the town of Bonham, in the county of Fannin.. <ref>341</ref></p>
<p>An act to remove the disability of minority from William Stean, Jun&#8217;r, so as to enable him to receive his portion of the estate of his de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceased parents.......................................... <ref>344</ref></p>
<p>An act to incorporate and establish Guadalupe College .......... <ref>345</ref></p>
<p>To authorize the city ot Galveston to appoint Firemen, and to exempt the same from militia and jury duty...................... <ref>347</ref></p>
<p>An act for the relief of John Keiser............................ <ref>348</ref></p>
<p>An act to amend the 11th section of an act to incorporate the Brazos Canal Company............. <ref>348</ref></p>
<p>An act for the relief of the heirs of Jeremian Bowlin.......... <ref>349</ref></p>
<p>An act to legalize the marriage of Rhesa Green Stalcup and Mary Ann Miller ................................................ <ref>350</ref></p>
<p>An act to legitimate Mary Malicia Stalcup, and render her capable of taking by descent the estate or estates of her parents, Rhesa Green Stalcup and Mary Ann Stalcup............................... <ref>350</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution requiring the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue a patent in the name of the heirs of William P. Nunn, deceased.............................................. <ref>350</ref></p>
<pb n="437" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="v" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Joint resolution making an appropriation for the payment of the pro rata pay due E. W. Moore, post captain, commanding late Texas navy, under the provisions of an act of Congress of the Republic of Texas, approved 5th February, 1844............... <ref>351</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution on behalf of Edward A. Weyman, a resident citizen of the county of Nueces, and State of Texas............ <ref>325</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution for the relief of William Plucker.................. <ref>353</ref></p>
<p>An act to authorize the opening and construction of a turnpike road from the city of Houston to the Brazos river........... <ref>354</ref></p>
<p>An act to incorporate the town of Montgomery................. <ref>355</ref></p>
<p>An act for the relief of the widow and heirs at law of Major James L. Holmes, deceased ................ <ref>357</ref></p>
<p>An act for the relief of the heirs of Patrick Reels................ <ref>357</ref></p>
<p>An act to authorize Sarah Ann Kelton, wife of Oliver P. Kelton, a lunatic, to make valid conveyances of her real estate and negroes.. <ref>358</ref></p>
<p>An act for the relief of Jesse H. Cartwright........................ <ref>358</ref></p>
<p>An act authorizing Charles Covington and his associates, to establish a ferry across the river Yegua, and construct a causeway across the bottom lands thereof................................ <ref>359</ref></p>
<p>An act to incorporate the town of Springfield.................. <ref>360</ref></p>
<p>An act to amend the second section of an act for the incorporation of the town of Paris, the county seat of Lamar county, approved February 3d, 1845..................................................... <ref>361</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution for the relief of J. W. E Wallace............... <ref>362</ref></p>
<p>An act to establish the University of Eastern Texas............... <ref>362</ref></p>
<p>An act for the relief of Ann Terrell, widow and relict of George W. Terrell, deceased................................................ <ref>365</ref></p>
<p>An act to amend the several acts incorporating the city of Houston.. <ref>366</ref></p>
<p>An act incorporating the Houston Mechanics&#8217; Institute.......... <ref>369</ref></p>
<p>An act to establish the Galveston and Red River Railway Company.. <ref>370</ref></p>
<p>An act to incorporate Montgomery Academy................... <ref>373</ref></p>
<p>An act for the relief of James Stewart................................ <ref>375</ref></p>
<p>An act for the relief of Moses Evans, surviving administrator of H. S. Williamson, deceased................................. <ref>375</ref></p>
<p>An act for the relief of Isaac Delany ................................ <ref>376</ref></p>
<p>An act to incorporate the city of Lavaca............................... <ref>376</ref></p>
<p>An act to authorize Jacob F. Winfree to adopt Zachary Taylor Long as his lawful child.................................... <ref>379</ref></p>
<p>An act for the relief of Kisiah Taylor, whose maiden name was Kisiah Cryer.............................................. <ref>379</ref></p>
<p>An act to incorporate the town of Palestine, in the county of Anderson.. <ref>380</ref></p>
<p>An act to legalize the marriage of Eli Gray with Ann Eliza Gray... <ref>381</ref></p>
<p>An act to incorporate Williamson Academy, in the county or Hays.. <ref>381</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution for the relief of Louis Sanchez.................. <ref>382</ref></p>
<p>An act authorizing and requiring the transfer of the succession of Alexander Jordan, deceased, from the county of Nacogeoches to the county of Rusk.................................<ref>383</ref></p>
<p>An act for the relief of J. Harris Catlin........... <ref>383</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution auditing and acknowledging the claims of Stuart Perry, against the late Republic of Texas.............. <ref>384</ref></p>
<p>An act for the relief of James P. Wallace and Robert M. Williamson.. <ref>385</ref></p>
<p>An act for the relief of Christopher Columbus Browning........ <ref>385</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution authorizing the transfer of one-half a certain lot in the city of Austin, on certain conditions.................... <ref>386</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution confirming a certificate for one league and one labor of land, issued to John vaanderworth,by the Board of Land Co<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mmissioners of Austin county...................................... <ref>387</ref>.</p>
<p>Joint resolution to validate the election of mayor and aldermen for the city of New Braunfels.......... <ref>387</ref></p>
<pb n="438" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="vi" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Joint resolution authorizing the Comptroller of Public Accounts to transfer to S. L. Johnson, an Austin city lot.......... <ref>388</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution for the relief of Henry M. Smith.......... <ref>389</ref></p>
<p>An act to be entitled an act to incorporate the city of Nacogdoches.. <ref>389</ref></p>
<p>An act for the relief of Thomas J.Stell.................... <ref>392</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution for the relief of Robert H. Beale, who was perma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nently disabled in the service of the country............. <ref>393</ref></p>
<p>An act to incorporate the town of Goliad, in the county of Goliad.. <ref>393</ref></p>
<p>An act to incorporate the Republican Academy, in the couny or Har<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rison................................... <ref>396</ref></p>
<p>An act to incorporate the Western Texas Orphan Asylum............. <ref>397</ref></p>
<p>An act to incorporate the Huntsville Male Institute............... <ref>398</ref></p>
<p>An act for the relief of Alfred Brigance........................... <ref>4000</ref></p>
<p>An act, supplementary to an act to regulate the Public Printing, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved, March 8th, 1848....................... <ref>401</ref></p>
<p>An act for the relief of Alfred Johnson..................... <ref>401</ref></p>
<p>An act to authorize John H. Reagan and his associates to open and construct a turnpike road from the town of Buffalo, on the Trin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ity river, across the bottom to the high land, on the west side, in the direction of the town of Corsicana...................... <ref>402</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution for the relief of Garrison Greenwood.......... <ref>404</ref></p>
<p>An act to incorporate Cherokee Academy, in the town of Rusk, in the county of Cherokee................................. <ref>404</ref></p>
<p>An act to incorporate the town of San Augustine............... <ref>405</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution to authorize the Comptroller of the State of Texas, to settle with R. S. Neighbors.......... <ref>408</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution for the relief of the legal heirs of Mark Noble, de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceased ................................. <ref>408</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution authorizing and requiring the Comptroller of public accounts to issue warrants, paying A. B. Gray for services, in running and marking the Eastern Boundary Line of Texas.......... <ref>409</ref></p>
<p>An act to incorporate the Milam Liberal Institute................... <ref>410</ref></p>
<p>An act for the relief of Michael Short................... <ref>411</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution for the relief of Theodore D. Maltby, John Hervey, and Nathaniel R. Mallon, who were disabled for life in the service of the country......................................... <ref>411</ref></p>
<p>An act to incorporate the Houston Lyceum................. <ref>412</ref></p>
<p>A Joint resolution for the relief of Luis Thurner.......................... <ref>413</ref></p>
<p>An act for the relief of Seth Marvin...................... <ref>413</ref></p>
<p>An act to incorporate the town of Mount Pleasant, in the county of Titus............................................ <ref>414</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution for the relief of E. B. Cogswell.................. <ref>414</ref></p>
<p>An act to amend the eighteenth section of &#8220; an act to incorporate the city of Austin,&#8221; passed 11th May, A. D. 1846.................. <ref>415</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution for the relief of Ford &#38; Cronican.............. <ref>415</ref></p>
<p>An act to incorporate the town of Jefferson......................... <ref>416</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution authorizing the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue a patent to Edward Hall................. <ref>419</ref></p>
<p>An act to incorporate the German Texian Friendship Association, of Galveston................................................................. <ref>419</ref></p>
<p>An act to incorporate the Galveston Steam Ferry, Freight and Tow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Boat Company................................................. <ref>420</ref></p>
<p>An act to incorporate the Goliad Statistical Society................. <ref>422</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution for the relief of Allen Kellough...................... <ref>423</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution authorizing M. M. Potter to draw the mileage and per diem pay of the Hon. Bichard Bache, Senator from Galves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton. deceased........................................... <ref>424</ref></p>
<p>Joint resolution granting leave of absence to James B. Shaw, Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller of Public Accounts................................ <ref>424</ref></p>
<p>An act supplementary to an act to incorporate the town of Refugio.. <ref>424</ref></p>
</div3>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>