<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="1285" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">LAWS <lb/>OF <lb/>THE FOURTH LEGISLATURE <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS <lb/>SECOND SESSION.</head>
<byline>AUSTIN. 1853</byline>
<pb n="1286" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" />
<pb n="1287" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" />
<head type="sub">GENERAL LAWS</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Concerning certain Lands in Austin&#8217;s Second Colony, and the Colony of Austin and Williams.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, some doubts have arisen as to the true line of the West<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ern boundary of the Colonies known as Austin&#8217;s second Colony, and the Colony of Austin and Williams, and the rights of many citizens may be iujuriously affected unless said doubts are re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />moved, or the said rights otherwise protected; therefore, Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of</p>
<p>Texas, That all grants made by Commissioners of Austin&#8217;s second Colony, or Austin and Williams&#8217; Colony, and lying in a triangular tract of country south of the upper road from Bexar to Nacog<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />doches, and between lines drawn north-east and north-west from the western source of the Lavaca river to said road, be and are hereby declared to be as valid as if situated within the undoubted limits of said Colonies, and the State hereby releases her claim to the same; provided, that the provisions of this act shall not be so con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />strued as to apply to any grant for a greater amount of land than one league and one labor, nor to any others than those made to Colonists for their headrights, or for premium lands to the Em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />presario.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 25, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1288" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Supplementary to an Act concerning certain Lands in Austin&#8217;s second Colony, and the Colony of Austin and Williams.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the aforesaid act passed at the present session of the Legislature, shall take effect and be in force from and after its pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age, and this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 26, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act reinstating Joseph F. Smith as an Attorney and Counsellor at Law.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Joseph F. Smith, a citizen of the county of Victoria, be, and he is hereby reinstated into all the rights privileges and immunities of an Attorney and Counsellor at Law, from which he was stricken by a rule of the District Court of Travis county; and the said Joseph F. Smith is hereby authorized to do and transact all business which he might, could, or ought to do as an Attorney and Counsellor at Law, the same as if no rule of said court had been made against him, until the writ of error, now pending to said judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the District Court of Travis county, shall have been de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cided by the Supreme Court.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 2, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1289" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To apportion the Senators and Representatives of the Legislature among the several Counties of this State, according to the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quirements of the Constitution.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the State of Texas shall be divided into thirty-three Senatorial Districts, which shall be severally entitled to one Sen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ator, and formed as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>No. 1. Rea River and Bowie shall elect one senator;</p>
<p>No. 2. Lamar and Hopkins one senator;</p>
<p>No. 3. Fannin and Hunt one senator;</p>
<p>No. 4. Collin, Grayson, Denton, Kanfman and Cooke one senator.</p>
<p>No. 5. Dallas, Tarrant and Ellis one senator;</p>
<p>No. 6. Upshur and Wood one senator;</p>
<p>No. 7. Cass and Titus one senator;</p>
<p>No. 8. Harrison one senator;</p>
<p>No. 9. Rusk one senator;</p>
<p>No. 10. Smith and van Zandt one senator;</p>
<p>No. 11. Cherokee one senator;</p>
<p>No. 12. Anderson and Houston one senator;</p>
<p>No. 13. Nacogdoches and Angelina one senator;</p>
<p>No. 14. Shelby and Panola one senator;</p>
<p>No. 15. San Augustine, Newton, Jasper and Sabine one sen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ator;</p>
<p>No. 16. Jefferson, Liberty, Polk, Trinity, Orange and Tyler one senator;</p>
<p>No. 17. Galveston one senator;</p>
<p>No. 18. Harris one senator;</p>
<p>No. 19. Montgomery, Walker, Madison and Grimes one sena<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tor;</p>
<p>No. 20. Washington one senator;</p>
<p>No. 21. Leon, Robertson, Brazos and Burleson one senator;</p>
<p>No. 22. Freestone, Limestone, Navarro and Henderson one senator.</p>
<p>No. 23. McLennan, Falls, Bell, Williamson and Milam one sen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ator;</p>
<p>No. 24. Matagorda, Wharton, Brazoria and Fort Bend one sen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ator;</p>
<p>No. 25. Bastrop, Travis and Burnett one senator;</p>
<pb n="1290" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>No. 26. Calhoun, Victoria, Jackson, Goliad, De Witt and La<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vaca one senator.</p>
<p>No. 27. Gonzales, Guadalupe, Caldwell, Hays and Comal one senator;</p>
<p>No. 28. Cameron and Hidalgo one senator;</p>
<p>No. 29. Starr, Webb, Nueces, San Patricio, Refugio and Kin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ney one senator;</p>
<p>No. 30. Bexar one senator;</p>
<p>No. 31. Gillespie, Bexar, Medina and Uvalde one senator;</p>
<p>No. 32. Fayette, Colorado and Austin one senator;</p>
<p>No. 33. El Paso and Presidio one senator.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The chief-justice of Red River shall receive the returns, and give the certificate of election to the Senator elect of the first senatorial district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Lamax county for the second district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Fannin for the third district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Collin for the fourth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Dallas for the fifth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Upshur for the sixth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Cass county for the seventh district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Harrison county for the eighth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Rusk county for the ninth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Smith county for the tenth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Cherokee county for the eleventh district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Anderson for the twelfth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Nacogdoches for the thirteenth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Shelby county for the fourteenth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of San Augustine county for the fifteenth dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Liberty county for the sixteenth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Galveston county for the seventeenth dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Harris county for the eighteenth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Grimes county for the nineteenth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Washington county for the twentieth dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Robertson county for the twenty-first dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Navarro county for the twenty-second dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Bell county for the twenty-third district;</p>
<pb n="1291" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>The chief-justice of Brazoria county for the twenty-fourth dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Travis county for the tweny-fifth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Victoria county for the twenty-sixth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Guadalupe county for the twenty-seventh district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Cameron county for the twenty-eighth dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Nueces county for the twenty-ninth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Bexar county for the thirtieth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Bexar county for the thirty-first district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Colorado county for the thirty-second dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of El Paso county for the thirty-third district;</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the State shall be divided into Representative Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tricts, and the Counties and Representative Districts shall elect members of the House of Representatives as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>No. 1. Bowie shall elect one representative;</p>
<p>No. 2. Red River one representative;</p>
<p>No. 3. Lamar two representatives;</p>
<p>No. 4. Fannin one representative;</p>
<p>No. 5. Grayson one representative;</p>
<p>No. 6. Collin one representative;</p>
<p>No. 7. Denton, Collin and Cooke one representative;</p>
<p>No. 8. Dallas one representative;</p>
<p>No. 9. Hunt one representative;</p>
<p>No. 10. Hopkins one representative;</p>
<p>No. 11. Hopkins, Fannin and Red River one representative.</p>
<p>No. 13. Titus one representative;</p>
<p>No. 13. Cass one representative;</p>
<p>No. 14. Cass and Titus one representative;</p>
<p>No. 15. Harrison three representatives;</p>
<p>No. 16. Upshur one representative;</p>
<p>No. 17. Smith two representatives;</p>
<p>No. 18. Wood and Van Zandt one representative;</p>
<p>No. 19. Kaufman and Henderson one representative;</p>
<p>No. 20. Anderson two representatives;</p>
<pb n="1292" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>No. 21. Cherokee three representatives;</p>
<p>No. 22. Rusk four representatives;</p>
<p>No. 23. Panola one representative;</p>
<p>No. 24. Shelby one representative.</p>
<p>No. 25. Shelby, Panola and San Augustine one representative;</p>
<p>No. 26. San Augustine one representative.</p>
<p>No. 27. Nacogdoches two representatives;</p>
<p>No. 28. Houston one representative;</p>
<p>No. 29. Polk and Trinity one representative;</p>
<p>No. 30. Sabine, Jasper and Newton two representatives;</p>
<p>No. 31. Angelina and Cherokee one representative;</p>
<p>No. 32. Jefferson and Orange one representative.</p>
<p>No. 33. Liberty one representative;</p>
<p>No. 34. Tyler one representative;</p>
<p>No. 35. Galveston two representatives;</p>
<p>No. 36. Harris two representatives;</p>
<p>No. 37. Montgomery one representative;</p>
<p>No. 38. Walker one representative;</p>
<p>No. 39. Grimes one representative;</p>
<p>No. 40. Walker, Madison and Grimes one representative;</p>
<p>No. 41. Leon one representative;</p>
<p>No. 42. Freestone, Limestone and Falls one representative;</p>
<p>No. 43. Navarro one representative;</p>
<p>No. 44. Ellis and Tarrant one representative;</p>
<p>No. 45. Bell and McLennan, one representative;</p>
<p>No. 46. Robertson and Milam one representative;</p>
<p>No. 47. Burleson and Brazos one representative;</p>
<p>No. 48. Williamson and Burnett one representative;</p>
<p>No. 49. Washington two representatives;</p>
<p>No. 50. Austin one representative;</p>
<p>No. 51. Fort Bend and Austin one representative;</p>
<p>No. 52. Brazoria one representative;</p>
<p>No. 53 Matagorda and Wharton one representative;</p>
<p>No. 54. Colorado one representative;</p>
<p>No. 55. Fayette one representative;</p>
<p>No. 56. Bastrop one representative;</p>
<p>No. 57. Travis one representative;</p>
<p>No. 58. Fayette, Bastrop and Travis one representative;</p>
<p>No. 59. Jackson and Calhoun one representative;</p>
<p>No. 60. Victoria and Goliad one representative;</p>
<p>No. 61. Lavaca and De Witt one representative;</p>
<p>No. 62. Gonzales one representative;</p>
<p>No. 63. Guadalupe one representative;</p>
<pb n="1293" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>No. 64. Caldwell and Hays one representative;</p>
<p>No. 65. Nueces, San Patricio and Refugio one representative;</p>
<p>No. 66. Webb one representative;</p>
<p>No. 67. Starr one representative;</p>
<p>No. 68. Cameron one representative;</p>
<p>No. 69. Cameron and Hidalgo, one representative;</p>
<p>No. 70. Bexar three representatives;</p>
<p>No. 71. Bexar, Uvalde, Gillespie, Medina, Kinney and Comal one representative;</p>
<p>No. 72. Comal and Gillespie one representative.</p>
<p>No. 73. El Paso and Presidio one representative.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That in the several Representative Districts composed of more counties than one, the chief-justices of the following named counties shall receive the returns and give the certificates of election to the person receiving the highest number of votes for representative, to wit:</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Denton county for the seventh district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Hopkins county for the eleventh district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Cass county for the fourteenth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Wood county for the eighteenth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Henderson county for the nineteenth dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Shelby county for the twenty-fifth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Polk county for the twenty-ninth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Sabine county for the thirtieth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Angelina county for the thirty-first district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Jefferson county for the thirty-second dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Grimes county for the fortieth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Limestone county for the forty-second dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Ellis county for the forty-fourth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Bell county for the forty-fifth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Milam county for the forty-sixth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Burleson county for the forty-seventh dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Williamson county for the forty-eighth dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Fort Bend county for the fifty-first district;</p>
<pb n="1294" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>The chief-justice of Matagorda county for the fifty-third dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Bastrop county for the fifty-eighth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Jackson county for the fifty-ninth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Victoria county for the sixtieth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Lavaca county for the sixty-first district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Caldwell county for the sixty-fourth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Nueces county for the sixty-fifth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Cameron county for the sixty-ninth district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Bexar county for the seventy-first district;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of Comal county for the seventy-second dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict;</p>
<p>The chief-justice of El Paso county for the seventy-third dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That at elections hereafter for Senators and Represen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tatives in the Legislature of this State, they shall be elected for the Districts herein designated; Provided, That the chief-justice of Nueces county, the returning officer for the twenty-ninth Sena<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />torial District, shall, on the thirtieth day after the day of the elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion in the several counties of said twenty-ninth Senatorial Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict, open and examine said returns and give the certificate of election as in other cases provided for by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That whenever a new county shall be created, it shall vote in the Senatorial and Representative District or Districts from which it is taken.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>February 2, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to create the County of Madison.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all that portion of territory comprised within the following limits shall be erected into a new county, to be called the county of Madison.</p>
<pb n="1295" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. Beginning at the mouth of Bedias creek on the Trinity river, and running up the main Bedias to a point where the line between the counties of Grimes and Walker crosses the same; thence by a direct line to the north-west corner of a tract of land in the name of B. Q. Hadley, on the Navasoto river; thence up said stream to where the San Antonio road crosses the same; thence running with the south boundary of Leon county to the south-west corner of Alce Garrett&#8217;s survey; thence on a direct line to the north-east corner of Hiram Walker&#8217;s survey on the west bank of the Trinity river, and thence down the river to the place of beginning.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That it shall be, and is hereby made the duty of the Chief Justice of Grimes county to organize the said county of Madison on the first Monday in April next, by ordering an election for county officers, and conducting the same in all respects in con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formity to law.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That so soon as the said county of Madison has been organized as aforesaid, and the officers of the same qualified ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cording to law, they shall enter upon the discharge of their re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spective offices; and all courts in and for the county, shall be held at the house of James Mitchell, Junr., until the county seat of said county shall be permanently located by the citizens thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That so soon as the county shall have been organized as aforesaid, it shall be the duty of the Chief-Justice of said county to receive proposals as inducements, and issue an order for an elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, to be held for the permanent location of the county seat of said county; which proposals shall be in the shape of penal bonds, and made payable to the Chief-Justice aforesaid, and his successors in office.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That a majority of the votes polled shall determine the location, and in the event no place receives such majority in the first election, the Chief-Justice shall order a new election, putting in nomination the two places having received the highest number of votes in the first election, and the point which shall receive the highest number of votes in the said second election, shall be the lawful county seat of said county of Madison, and shall be known by the name of, and called Madisonville; provided, the said county seat to be located shall, in no event, be more than five miles from the centre of the said county.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 27, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1296" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Making appropriations to defray the expenses of three Companies of Volunteers, called into the service of the State for the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tection of the frontier.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the following sums be, and the same are hereby ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated to defray the expenses of the companies of volunteers commanded by Captains Shaw, Lewis and Davis, respectively, which were called into the service of the State by His Excellency, the Governor, for the protection of the frontier, viz:</p>
<p>For pay and mileage of said companies, forty-eight thousand one hundred and forty-six dollars.</p>
<p>For subsistence and forage of the same, as per contracts now on file in the office of the Adjutant-General, twenty-nine thousand five hundred dollars and ninety-two cents.</p>
<p>For purchase of Quarter-master&#8217;s stores, ordnance stores, camp and garrison equipage, medicines, etc., four thousand five hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For pay of three Surgeons, one thousand eight hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For expenses incurred by Col. J. S. Gillett, Adjutant General, in organizing said force, three hundred dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Governor be, and he is hereby authorized to appoint some suitable person, who shall, upon giving bond and se<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curity in such sum as the Governor may require, be authorized to draw from the Treasury of the State, the sum above appropriated for the pay and mileage of the said three companies, and shall re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pair at such time, and to such place or places as the Governor may direct, and there, at the expiration of their respective terms of serv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ice, pay to said companies the amounts which may be due them, making a proper return thereof to the Comptroller; and it shall be the duty of said person thus appointed, to receive and receipt for all articles of public property which may be turned over to him by the officers of the said companies, and to dispose of the same for the benefit of the State, according to such directions as may be given to him by the Governor, making a due return thereof to the Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the Paymaster thus appointed shall, in paying <pb n="1297" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the troops assigned to him by this act, recognize all sums placed on the muster-rolls of said companies by their respective officers, as due by them for arms or supplies furnished, and that the said amounts shall be deducted from the sums due by the State, and paid to the parties furnishing them.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the sum of five hundred dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated to carry into effect the above section, No. 2.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the Comptroller is hereby authorized and required to settle the accounts of the contractors for the supply of forage, and subsistence, as per contract now on tile in the office of the Ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jutant-General, so far as they may appear, by proper vouchers, to have been performed; and, upon his warrant, the Treasurer is au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized to pay the amounts found due.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the Comptroller is hereby authorized to examine and allow such accounts for quarter-master&#8217;s stores, camp and gar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rison equipage, ordnance stores, transportation, medicines, etc., as may be presented in proper form, duly certified to by the respect<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ive commanders of companies; provided, that no account, or item in any account, shall be allowed or paid, which are not allowed by the regulations of the United States&#8217; Army.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the Comptroller shall issue his warrant upon the Treasurer for the compensation of medical services rendered the above named companies, upon the presentation of the usual con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tracts in due form.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 29, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To authorize the Clerk of the District Court of Houston County to transcribe certain Records.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Clerk of the District Court of Houston county be, and he is hereby authorized and required to transcribe into a well bound book, to be furnished by the County of Hous<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton for that purpose, the minutes of the District Court of said <pb n="1298" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>county, contained in book &#8220;A.&#8221; and when the same shall have been examined and approved by the County Court of said county, the same shall have ail the force and effect in law and equity that the original could or should have; and all certified copies taken from the same shall be as valid, and have the same force and effect as if taken from the original.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the said Clerk shall receive such compensation for his services as shall be allowed by said Court, not to exceed fifteen cents for each hundred words so transcribed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be of force from its pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 31, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act concerning offences committed by Negroes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That if a free negro plot or conspire the murder of a white person, or maliciously shoot, stab, cut or wound, or by any means cause bodily injury to a white person with intent to kill, he shall be punished at the discretion of the jury, either with death, or by confinement in the Penitentiary, not less than three nor more than ten years.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That if a free negro carnally know a white female of the age of twelve years or more, by force or fraud, or carnally know a white female child under that age, or attempt by force or fraud to have carnal knowledge of a white female, he shall be punished with death.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That if a free negro take away or detain against her will a white female, with intent to marry or defile her, or cause her to be married or defiled by another person, or take from any person having lawful charge of her, a white female child under twelve years of age, for the purpose of prostitution or concubinage, he shall be punished with death.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That if a free negro commit any other offence not speci<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fiecl in this act, he shall be punished as a free white person.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That if a slave plot or conspire to rebel or make in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />surrection, or commit an offence for the commission of which a free negro is punishable with death, or by confinement in the <pb n="1299" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>penitentiary for not less than three years, he shall be punished with death.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That if a slave commit an offence for which a free negro, if he had committed it, might be punished by confinement in the penitentiary for a period less than three years, such slave shall be punished by stripes, not exceeding fifty, at the discretion of the jury.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That if a slave commit an offence, the commission of which, by a free person, is punishable as a misdemeanor, he shall be punished by stripes not exceeding thirty-nine.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That a negro shall be punished with not exceeding thir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty-nine stripes, for the commission of the following offences: first, if he use provoking language or menacing gestures to a white per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son; if he punish a slave, without the consent of his owner or man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ager, any pass, permit or token of his being from home with au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thority; if he keep or carry fire-arms, sword, or other weapon, or balls, or ammunition, besides forfeiting to the county any such articles in his possession; fourth, if he be guilty of being in a riot, rout, unlawful assembly, or of making seditious speeches; fifth, if he sell or attempt to sell, or prepare, or administer any medicine, except where a slave administers medicine by his master&#8217;s order, in his family, or in the family of another with the consent of such other, and except also, when a free negro administers medicine in his own family, or in the family of another person with the consent of such other.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That the word negro, in this or any other statute of this State, shall also be construed to mean mulatto, and every person who has one-fourth part or more of negro blood, shall be deemed a mulatto.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That the punishment of a negro by stripes, when as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sessed by a jury, shall be at their discretion, so as not to affect life; and when assessed by a justice, shall not exceed fifty lashes.</p>
<p><i>Of criminal proceedings against Negroes and Slaves</i>.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That the trial of negroes charged with felonious homi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cide, or any offence punishable with death, shall be in the District Courts, where the proceedings shall be as in the case of white per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That on any indictment of a negro in the District Court, the accused may be found not guilty of the offence charged, but guilty of any offence of which, a free white person <pb n="1300" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>might be found guilty on such indictment, and the jury may find and assess such punishment against him as the offence would justi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fy, if the negro had been charged therewith in the county court as is hereinafter provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That the county courts of each county, to consist of the Chief-Justice and two Commissioners, at least, or of three Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners at least, in case of disability or absence of the Chief<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Justice or vacancy in that office, shall be a criminal tribunal for the trial of negroes and slaves charged with felony, except in the cases provided for in the two preceding sections.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That such trials in the county courts shall be on sworn information, or charge in writing entered of record, stating the of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fence and verified by affidavit, but without a. grand jury, or a pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentment or indictment.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. That free negroes charged with any offence in the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty courts, and slaves charged with offences punishable by death, shall be entitled to trial by a jury of twelve good and lawful men, freeholders of the county, summoned for the purpose, and shall have the same right of challenge allowed by law to white persons.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. That no one interested in a slave charged with crime shall sit on his trial as a member of the court, or as a juror.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. That in all criminal cases before the county court, if no counsel be employed to prosecute by private persons, the court may employ some competent attorney to perform that duty, who shall be entitled to such compensation as may be agreed on, to be paid out of the county treasury.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. That on trial of slaves for felony, the court shall assign counsel to defend, if none be employed, and allow him such fee, not to exceed one hundred dollars, which shall he paid by the owner of the slave.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. That a regular term of the county court for the trial of negroes, may be had on the first Monday in every month, when the court shall deem it necessary, and any such term may continue until all business of the court be disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. That the clerk of the county court shall be the clerk of the tribunal established by this act, shall issue all process or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dered to enforce the jurisdiction conferred, and keep a correct rec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ord of all the proceedings of the court in a separate book provided for that purpose, and shall be entitled to receive the same fees and compensation that the clerk of the district court would be entitled to receive for similar services.</p>
<pb n="1301" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 21. That for good and satisfactory cause shown and veri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied by affidavit in open court, the trial of negroes may be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinued from term to term not exceeding two continuances.</p>
<p>Sec. 22. That on a charge against a negro tor felony, the court or jury may find the accused not guilty of the offence charged, but guilty of any offence for which a free white person might be found guilty on an indictment for such felony, and may assess the punishment therefor where it is not fixed by law, and give judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment accordingly.</p>
<p>Sec. 23. That if a slave or negro condemned to death escape before his or her execution, and be retaken, the jailor or sheriff of the court by which the slave was condemned, shall promptly in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />form the said court of the fact, and the court on being satisfied of his or her identity, shall cause the sentence to be carried into ef<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fect on a day appointed by it.</p>
<p>Sec. 24. That a slave shall be tried for a misdemeanor by a jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tice of the county in which the offence is committed.</p>
<p>Sec. 25. That a free negro shall be tried by such justice for a misdemeanor punishable by stripes. For any other misdemeanor he or she may be tried in the county court, but a justice before whom a free negro is charged with a misdemeanor punishable by fine and imprisonment, or either, may try him or her and inflict such punishment as he would inflict on a slave for the same of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fence, or commit or recognise him for trial at the next court of the county.</p>
<p>Sec. 26. That in the case of a negro convicted of a misdemeanor by a justice, the decision may be removed by certiorari to the county court by the negro, if free, or if he be a slave, by his owner; such negro shall, unless let to bail, be committed by the justice to jail, until the next term of such court, and the witnesses shall also be recognized to appear at the same time.</p>
<p>Sec. 27. That every such, certiorari shall be tried in the county court without pleadings in writing, and without a continuance, except for good cause shown, and the court shall hear all the evi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dence on either side, and give such judgment as seems to it prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />er, and enforce the execution thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 28. That the chief justices of the several counties shall have power to issue writs of certiorari in any case arising under this act.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 3, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1302" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IX. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To amend an act to create the County of Hidalgo.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of the act entitled &#8220;an act to create the county of Hidalgo,&#8221; approved January 24, 1852, be so amend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the territory embraced within the following limits, to wit: beginning at the south-east corner of a tract of land called the &#8220;Llano Grande,&#8221; at a point on the Bio Grande where the east<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erly line of said Llano Grande strikes the said river; and running thence northerly along the easterly line of said land, and extending said line until it strikes the southerly line of Nueces county; thence, in a north-westerly direction, along the southern line of Nueces county to the north-eastern corner of Starr county; thence, in a south-westerly direction, along the lower or easterly line of Starr county to the Rio Grande; thence down the meanders of the Bio Grande to the place of beginning, shall be constituted into a new county and shall be called Hidalgo.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 4, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the County Court, of Comal county to levy and collect a Special Tax.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the County Court of Comal County be, and they are hereby authorized and empowered to cause to be levied and col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lected upon all the citizens and taxable property of the county, a special tax upon the same, not to exceed the State tax, for five years; provided, that the chief justice of said county shall first or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der an election, by giving at least twenty days notice thereof, whether a majority of the electors of said county are in favor of levying such tax.</p>
<pb n="1303" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Section 2. That if the citizens of said county should dissent from the provisions of this act, at the first election, the Chief Jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tice of said county may order a new one at the next regular elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion for county officers, and if at any of such elections a majority of all the qualified electors shall vote in favor of levying and collect<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing said special tax, then the County Court of said county shall di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rect the Assessor and Collector of the county to collect said special tax, under the law regulating the collection of county taxes, so far as the same is applicable.</p>
<p>Section 3. That the County Court shall apply the money, so collected, to the building of a Courthouse and Jail, and for no other purpose whatever.</p>
<p>Section 4. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 4, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XI. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To amend the 99th, 130th and 131st sections of An Act to regulate proceedings in the District Court, approved May 13th, 1846.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the 99th, 130th and 131st sections of the act recited in the title of this act, be, and are so amended as to read as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows, viz:</p>
<p>Sec. 99. No plaintiff shall be permitted to suffer a nonsuit after the jury retire from the bar; but after the argument of a cause, and before the jury retires, the Judge may deliver a charge to them on the law of the case, under the following restrictions, viz:</p>
<p>He shall not in any case, civil or criminal, charge or comment on the weight of the evidence; he shall so frame his charge so as to submit questions of fact solely to the decision of the jury, deciding on and instructing them as to the law arising on the facts, distinctly separating questions of law from questions of fact; he shall not charge or instruct the jury in any case, unless the charge shall have been by him first reduced to writing, and signed, and every such, charge or instruction, shall be <pb n="1304" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>given in the precise words in which it shall have been written; all charges or instructions, whether given by the Judge of his own ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cord, or upon request of counsel or parties, may be carried from the bar by the jury in their retirement; and no Judge shall in any case make any further charge, unless on the application of the jury, or a party, or his counsel.</p>
<p>Sec. 130. In cases where a sole plaintiff, or one of the several plaintiffs shall die after judgment, it shall be the duty of the Clerk to issue execution on such judgment, in the name of the legal rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives of such deceased sole plaintiff, or in the name of the surviving plaintiffs, and the legal representatives of the deceased plaintiff, as the case may require, without further notice to the de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fendant, upon an affidavit of such death being entered of record or filed with the Clerk by such legal representative or the attorney of record of such plaintiff, together with a certificate of the appoint<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of such representative under the hand and seal of the Clerk of the court where the same was made, and in cases where an executor, administrator or guardian is plaintiff, and shall die or cease to be such executor, administrator or guardian after judgment, execution shall be issued on each judgment in the name of the person suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeding him in the administration or guardianship, upon such suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessor filing of record with the Clerk, a certificate of his appoint<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment and qualification as such, under the hand and seal of the court where such appointment was made.</p>
<p>Sec. 131. In cases where a sole defendant dies after judgment for money against him, the plaintiff may proceed to establish his claim against the estate, by presenting a certified copy of such judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment to the executor or administrator of such decedent as directed by law for the settlement of estates of deceased persons, and where there are two or more defendants, one or more of whom die after judgment, for money, leaving one or more surviving, then the plaintiff shall be entitled to execution against such survivor or sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vivors, by filing an affidavit of such death with the Clerk of the court, and may also proceed to establish his claim against the estate of the party deceased in the mode directed by law. In all cases of judgments, other than money judgments where the sole defendant, or one or more of several joint defendants shall die after judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, the plaintiff shall be entitled to have execution thereon against the legal representatives of such deceased party or parties, without being required to revive the same by scire fracias, or otherwise, upon an affidavit of such death being filed with the Clerk of the court; provided, that no defendant <pb n="1305" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>shall be deprived of the right to quash or enjoin such execution by showing satisfaction of the same.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 5, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XII. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To give certain Civil and Criminal jurisdiction to the Mayor of the town of Washington, in Washington county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Mayor of the town of Washington, in the county of Washington, shall hereafter have and exercise all the powers and jurisdiction, both civil and criminal, of a justice of the peace with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />in and throughout the limits of said town, and shall be governed in the exercise of such powers and jurisdiction by all laws enacted, or to be enacted for the government of justices of the peace in similar cases.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That before the Mayor shall enter upon the discharge of any of the duties and powers granted in the preceding section, he shall execute a bond with two or more sufficient securities, in the sum of one thousand dollars, payable to and approved by the chief-justice of Washington county, conditioned as in cases of justices of the peace, and shall take the oath of office prescribed by law, before some officer authorized to administer oaths, which shall be endorsed on his bond, together with the certificate of the officer who administered the same, which bond and oath shall be endorsed and recorded as in cases of justices of the peace.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act shall take effect and be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 5, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making appropriations for the improvement of the Rivers of the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of thirty-three thousand dollars be, and <pb n="1306" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the same is hereby appropriated to the improvement of the navi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gation of the Sabine river;</p>
<p>That the sum of thirty-seven thousand five hundred dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated to the Trinity river;</p>
<p>That the sum of thirty-seven thousand five hundred dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated to the Brazos and Little riv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers, and toward the completion of the canal now in progress of con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struction under the direction of the Galveston and Brazos Navi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gation Company;</p>
<p>That the sum of thirty-seven thousand five hundred dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated to the Colorado river;</p>
<p>That the sum of twenty-three thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated to the Neches and Angelina rivers;</p>
<p>That the sum of twenty-one thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated to the Guadalupe river;</p>
<p>That the sum of eleven thousand five hundred dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated to the San Antonio river;</p>
<p>For Ferry Lake, from the Louisiana line to Jefferson, twelve thousand dollars;</p>
<p>For Cypress Bayou, from Jefferson to Watson&#8217;s Ferry, two thousand dollars;</p>
<p>For Little Cypress, two thousand dollars;</p>
<p>For Sulphur Fork of Red Rive, eight thousand dollars;</p>
<p>For Jim&#8217;s Bayou, one thousand dollars;</p>
<p>That the sum of seventeen thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated to Red River;</p>
<p>That the sum of four thousand dollars be, and the same is here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by appropriated to Buffalo Bayou.</p>
<p>That the sum of four thousand dollars be, and the same is here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by appropriated to the San Jacinto river;</p>
<p>That the sum of three thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated to the San Bernard river;</p>
<p>That the sum of three thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated for the Lavaca and Navidad rivers;</p>
<p>That the sum of five thousand dollars be, and the same is here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by appropriated for the Nueces river; and,</p>
<p>For the Mission and the bay at its mouth, the sum of three thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That a board of Internal Improvements, consisting of three members, shall be elected for each of the following rivers: Sabine, Trinity, Brazos, Colorado, San Jacinto, San Bernard, Navidad, Sulphur Fork of Red River and Nueces; and one board, consisting of three members, shall be elected <pb n="1307" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>for the Neches and Angelina rivers; and a board, consisting of three members shall be elected for the San Antonio, and one for the Guadalupe; and a board, consisting of three members, shall be elected for Ferry Lake and Cypress Bayou and Jim&#8217;s Bayou; and a board, consisting of three members, shall be elected for the Mis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion river and the bay at its mouth, which said boards shall be elected by both Houses of the Legislature, in joint session; and each member of said boards, before entering on the duties of his office, shall enter into bond, with sufficient security, in the sum of ten thousand dollars, payable to the Governor and his successors in office, for the faithful discharge of the duties which may be as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />signed them, which said bond shall be approved by the Governor and filed with the Secretary of State, upon which suit may be brought, from time to time, and not to be void upon the first recov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ery, for a forfeiture thereof; and each member shall also take and subscribe the following oath, before any person legally authorized to administer the same: &#8220;I do hereby solemnly swear, (or affirm, as the case may be), that I will well and truly discharge all the duties as a member of the board of Internal Improvements to which I have been elected, which may be imposed upon me, by the Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature, from time to time;&#8221; and said members of the board shall receive two dollars per day for each and evry day they may be ne<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessarily engaged in the discharge of their duties.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the several boards shall lay off the work to be done in sections of convenient size, let out the work to the lowest bidder, who shall enter into bond in double the amount of his bid, for the faithful performance of his work, with securities to be approved by the board; they shall superintend the work, and see that it is done in conformity with the contracts, but neither of them shall either directly or indirectly be interested in any bid or contract.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the said respective hoards shall elect one of their number President of the same, who shall preside at all the meetings of the board, should he be present; and he shall have the power to convene the board, with the concurrence of one other member, whenever he may deem it necessary to do so; and two members of said board shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business; and the said board shall keep a record of their proceedings touching all their transactions in the discharge of their duties, a copy of which shall be by them transmitted, once in every three months, to the Governor, for his inspection, and which shall by him be filed in the office of <pb n="1308" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the Secretary of State, for the inspection of all who may desire to see it; and the said board shall, from time to time, draw drafts on the Treasury, in favor of the contractor, for such sums as they may think necessary and proper, to enable such contractor to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress with his work: Provided, That in no case shall they draw for more than two-thirds of the work actually done and performed, until the whole of the contract shall have been completed.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That all the proceedings of the respective hoards touch<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing their duties, shall be by them laid before the next session of the Legislature, after they are had; also, all the proceedings of the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor, touching his duties and transactions with the said boards, shall be by him laid before the next session of the Legislature, after they are had; and in the case of a vacancy in the board during the recess of the Legislature, it shall be filled by the two remaining members of the board, should there be two remaining members, which appointment shall be in force until the meeting of the next Legislature; and in the event that there shall be at any time only one member of the board, or no member of the board, it shall be the duty of the Governor to fill the vacancy or vacancies, which appointments shall, in like manner, continue in office until the next session of the Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That each member of the board may make out his ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />count, every three months, for his services, which shall be signed by each member of the board, and submitted to the Governor for his approval, and if by him approved, the Treasurer shall pay the same; but should the Governor disapprove the same, he shall, return it to the said board with his reasons for his disapproval.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the Governor shall cause this act to be submitted to the qualified electors, at the next general election to be held in August next; and if there are more votes cast in favor of than against the adoption of this act, then it shall take effect and be in force, and not otherwise.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to give the right of appeal in cases on Habeas Corpus.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the judgment of a Supreme or District Judge on <pb n="1309" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Habeas Corpus entered of record, shall be conclusive, unless re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />versed on appeal; and no person remanded by such judgmert to custody while the same continues in force, shall be at liberty to obtain another Habeas Corpus for the same cause, or by any other proceeding to bring the same matter again in question, unless by appeal to the Supreme Court, under the regulations made for such appeal in criminal cases, which appeal any party aggrieved by such judgment may prosecute.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The ninth section of an act to prescribe the method of proceeding to obtain the benefit of the writ of Habeas Corpus of January 14, 1840, is hereby repealed</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 5, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XV. JOINT RESOLUTION</head>
<opener>
<salute>Instructing our Senators and requesting our Representatives in Congress, to call the attention of the Government of the United States to the necessity for a further treaty with the Republic of Mexico.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That our Senators be instructed and our Representatives in Congress be requested, to call the attention of the Government of the United States to the necessity now existing for a further treaty with the Republic of Mexico, and that they urge our Government to make a treaty restoring to the citizens of the United States, all slaves belonging to them and which now are within the said Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public, as well as all which may hereafter escape thereto; and, also, for the prompt restoration of any other property of American citizens which may have been carried or taken against the will of the respective owners thereof into the said Republic.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That a copy of these Resolutions be forwarded to each of our Senators and Representatives in Congress.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1310" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to regulate the election of District Surveyors.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That whenever an election is held in any land district in this State, for District Surveyor of such district, and the same shall be composed entirely of one county, the returns of said elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion shall be made to the chief-justice of such counties, in the same manner as returns are now by law required to be made for county officers, and such chief-justices shall in the same manner as in other cases of election, examine such returns and issue cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates of election; but when such land districts embrace more than one county, then the return of the votes given in such elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions shall be made to the chief-justices of those counties in which such votes are given, in the same manner as now provided for coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty officers, and the several chief-justices to whom such returns are made, shall open and examine the same on the tenth day, exclusive of the day of election, and shall immediately certify and send the result of said election to the chief-justice of that county from which the land district takes its name, which certificate shall be sealed up and the name of the officer forwarding it written across the seal, and the package marked on the outside &#8220;election re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turns;&#8221; which package may be sent by mail: the chief-justices to whom the certificates are so forwarded shall, upon the twentieth day after the election, which shall be the return day for such elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, open and examine said certificates, together with the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turns of said election, made from his own comity, and after esti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mating the result and recording the same, give a certificate of election to the candidate or person for whom the greatest number of votes shall have been polled.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That whenever a vacancy shall occur in the office of District Surveyor, for any land district in this State, and such district be composed entirely of one county, it shall be the duty of the chief-justice of such county to order an election to fill such vacancy, in the same manner as now provided for county officers; but when such land district shall embrace more than one county, then it shall be the duty of the chief-justice of the mother county, or that from which the land district takes its name, to issue a notice to the chief justices of those counties which are embraced in whole or in part in such land district, which notice may be sent by mail, shall set forth the vacancy and office to be filled, and shall name the day on which said <pb n="1311" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>election is to be held, and such day shall be uniform throughout said district, and shall not be less than twenty days after the issu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance of such notice. Immediately on the receipt of such notice, the chief-justice to whom the same shall be directed, shall issue orders of election, and notice thereof shall be given in the same manner as provided now for county officers.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That whenever the election of any person to the office of district surveyor may be contested, like notice shall be given and proceedings had as in case of contested elections for county officers.</p>
<p>When the district is composed of one county, the county Court of that county shall be the proper tribunal to try the contest; but where the district is composed of more than one county, then such contest shall be tried in the County Court of the mother county.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVII. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Explanatory of An Act entitled an Act for the relief of certain persons formerly prisoners in Mexico, approved Feburary 9th, 1850.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the intent of said act was to pay alike all who were taken prisoners, killed or died while under enlistment in said ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pedition.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVIII. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To define the time of holding the District Courts in the Tenth Judicial District.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of <pb n="1312" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Texas, That the District Court shall be held in each county in the tenth judicial district as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Victoria on the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Calhoun on the second Mondays alter the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Jackson on the fourth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Lavaca on the fifth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Gonzales on the seventh Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of De Witt on the ninth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Goliad on the eleventh Mondays alter the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks, or until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all process in said counties shall be made return<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able in conformity with the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIX. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Relating to lost Certificates of Public Debt of the late Republic of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That in case of the loss of any certificate, issued by the Auditor and Comptroller of the State of Texas, under the provisions of an act entitled &#8220;An Act to provide for ascertain<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the debt of the late Republic of Texas,&#8221; approved March 20th, 1848, and an act entitled &#8220;An Act to provide for ascer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />taining the debt of the late Republic of Texas,&#8221; approved <pb n="1313" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="29" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>February 8th, 1850, for which appropriations have heretofore been made, upon the grantee or assignee of any such lost certificate making oath before any Notary Public, properly certified, to the fact of its loss, and filing with the Treasurer of the State a bond in double the amount of such certificate, with two or more good and sufficient securities, to be approved by said Treasurer, condi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned for the return of the amount of money paid, or to be paid, on such certificate; it shall at any time appear that any other per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son is the proper owner or holder of such certificate, which said bond may be put in suit by any person interested, or having right in said certificate, in the county wherein the seat of Government is situated, in the District Court of said county, it shall be the duty of said Treasurer to pay to such person the amount of money called for by said certificate. And in the event of the loss of a certificate of Public Debt, for the payment of which no appropriation has been made, the Auditor and Comptroller are hereby authorized to issue a duplicate thereof, upon the party claiming filing the same proof and security, as required by this act to be filed with the Treasurer and Comptroller, and complying with all the provisions, of this act, which duplicates when so issued, shall have all the force and effect of the original.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That any one falsely swearing in such case, shall be liable to be presented by indictment, before the District Court of the said county in which the seat of Government is situated, and upon conviction shall, be liable to all the pains and penalties of perjury.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to create the Thirteenth Judicial District.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the following counties shall constitute the Thirteenth Judicial District, viz: Brazos, Robertson, Leon, Navarro, Madison, Limestone, Freestone and Falls.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect from and after its pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 5, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1314" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="30" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act Supplementary to an Act relating to lands in Peters&#8217; Colony, approved February 10th, 1852.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Landoffice be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue patents to all Colo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nists of Peters&#8217; Colony, or their assigns, who have made, or may hereafter make their locations by virtue of their colonial headright certificates, and return the same to the General Landoffice, in the same manner as prescribed by the fourth section of the act to which this is a supplement, for filing with the agent of the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany so soon as the maps of said Company shall be furnished to the Commissioner of the General Landoffice, showing the land the Colonist claims, and the same is found not to conflict with legal surveys previously made; and until patents are issued, all locations by the Company&#8217;s surveys shall be sufficient to maintain an action of trespass to try title.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Colonists of Peters&#8217; Colony who have not made their locations and files, as provided for in the fourth section of the act to which this is a supplement, shall have three months longer time and preference over said Company in which to make their locations; and it shall be lawful for said Colonists to claim by the lines and corners of said Company&#8217;s surveys, or by the map and field-notes of their respective District or County surveyor, cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rectly made out in conformity with the land laws of Texas; which claim or entry, or the field-notes of the District Surveyor shall he filed in the General Landoffice, upon which the Commissioner of the General Landoffice is authorized and required to issue patents not to conflict with legal surveys previously made.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That neither this act, nor the act to which this is sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plemental, shall interfere with any locations or surveys legally made in any part of said Colony since the first day of July, 1848, and prior to the tenth day of February, 1852, which had not been sectionized by the contractors of said Colony.&#8212;The maps and rec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ords relating to the lands in Peters&#8217; Colony, now remaining with the Trustees or Agent of said Texas Emigration Land Company, shall be deposited with the Commissioner of the General Land<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />office and constitute a part of the records and archives of said office, subject to the general laws governing the same.</p>
<pb n="1315" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="31" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 4. That so soon as the legally authorized Trustee or Agent of said Company shall file in the General Landoffice a map of all the surveys made by them in said Colony, and an unqualified re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lease to the State of all their interests whatsoever in and to any and all the sections, half sections, fractional sections, and alternate sections, that is or may be owned, located, claimed or settled upon by any Colonists of said Colony or their assigns, by virtue of Ward&#8217;s certificates, or certificates of the County Courts by virtue of the tenth section of the act to which this is a supplement, they shall have power and authority to locate the lands to which they are en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled, by virtue of the act to which this is a supplement, in said Colony; and when located, shall be patented by the Commissioner of the General Landoffice; provided, they do not conflict with any location or claim of said Colonist, or other legal locations in said Colony; and upon their filing said release, the Commissioner of the General Landoffice is hereby required to make out and furnish to the Agent of said Company quarterly, and as fast as the returns of the Colonists are made in his office, a map of all the locations made by said Colonists at the expense of the Company.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That so much of the act to which this is a supplement, as conflicts with the provisions of this act, be and the same is hereby repealed, and this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXII. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To erect the counties of Cameron, Hidalgo, Starr, Webb, Nueces, San Patricio, and Presidio and El Paso, into separate land dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tricts.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the territories embraced in each of the said counties of Cameron, Hidalgo, Starr, Webb, Nueces, San Patricio and Pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sidio and El Paso, shall constitute and are hereby erected into sepa rate land districts, to be called respectively the land district of Cameron, of Hidalgo, of Starr, of Webb, of Nueces, of San Pa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tricio, and of Presidio and El Paso.</p>
<pb n="1316" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="32" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Section 2. That there shall be elected by the qualified electors of each land district created by this act, on the first Monday in Agust, A. D. 1853, and every two years thereafter, one district sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyor for each land district named and created in this act, whose term of office shall be two years from the date of his election, who shall qualify and discharge the duties of the said office in accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance with the law now in force concerning district surveyors in other districts, and be subject to the same penalties for a violation thereof. There shall be given at least ten days notice of said elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, and in case of a vacancy in said office, the chief-justice of the county in which such vacancy occurs shall order an election for the unexpired term of said office.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the district surveyor of the district of Cameron, shall keep his office at Brownsville. The district surveyor of Hidalgo shall keep his office at Edinburg. The district surveyor of the district of Starr shall keep his office at Bio Grande city. The district surveyor of the district of Nueces, shall keep his office at the town of Corpus Christi. The district surveyor of the district of San Patricio shall keep his office at the town of San Patricio. The district surveyor of the district of Webb shall keep his office at Laredo, and the district surveyor of the district of Presidio and El Paso, shall keep his office at the town of San Elizario, provided; that nothing in this act shall invalidate legal locations or surveys heretofore made in Bexar or San Patricio. And it shall be the duty of all the surveyors to be elected under this act, to apply at San Antonio and Corpus Christi for all certificates and accompanying locations for lands in their respective counties made at San An<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tonio and at Corpus Christi respectively.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That &#8220;an act to create the counties of Cameron, Hidalgo, Starr, Webb, Presidio and El Paso into separate land districts,&#8221; ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved February 16, 1852, be, and the same is hereby repealed, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1317" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="33" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIII. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Supplementary to &#8220;An Act granting to settlers on public domain pre-emption privileges,&#8221; approved, January 22d, 1845.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the provisions of the above recited act, be so modi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied as to read as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>That each and every settler who have availed themselves of the provisions of said law, upon any of the public domain of the State, shall be entitled, not to exceed three hundred and twenty acres of land, upon the conditions and restrictions hereinafter set forth.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That to entitle any settler to a patent not to exceed three hundred and twenty acres of land, he must produce a cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate from the clerk of the county court wherein he resides, that he or his assigns has resided upon and cultivated the same for the space of three years, and complied fully with the provisions of an act to which this is a supplement.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That each and every settler or applicant, at the time he applies for a patent, not to exceed three hundred and twenty acres, shall pay to the Commissioner of the General Landoffice the usual fees, and additional sum of twenty dollars for the use and benefit of the State, for every patent thus issued.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That each and every patent issued under the provisions of this act, for any less number than three hundred and twenty acres, shall pay the usual fees, and ten dollars for each and every patent so issued.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That to entitle the party to a certificate from the Coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty Clerk of the County Court, he must prove by two respectable citizens, known to the County Clerk, that he has fully complied with the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That all laws and parts of laws that conflict with the provisions of this act, be and the same are hereby repealed, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1318" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="34" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act relating to the Fiscal Affairs of the late Republic of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall be the duty of the Comptroller of Public Ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />counts, as soon as practicable, to prepare a statement of the ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />counts of such of the collectors of public revenue of the late Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public, as appear by the books of his office to be unsettled, and transmit the same for collection to the District Attorney of the District wherein such collector resided or exercised the functions of his office at the time such indebtedness was incurred.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the several District Attorneys shall have power and authority in all cases where a receiver of public moneys as aforesaid shall be in arrears to the late Republic, and is unable to settle the account with which he is charged, to grant an extention of time to such officer for the payment of such amount; provided, that such officer shall secure the State by bond, payable to the State of Texas, with three or more securities to the satisfaction of the District Attorney charged with the collection of the amount, in double the sum of such officer&#8217;s liability, and in case the amount found to be due by said officer, with eight per cent. interest per annum, at the time stipulated in said bond, which shall not exceed three years from the date of settlement, the same shall be placed in the hands of the Attorney General, whose duty it shall be to cause the necessary legal steps to be taken for the recovery of the amount actually due the State, with interest as aforesaid, from the date of the settlement to that of recovery, and all costs, damages and other expenses incurred in the prosecution of such suit.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That when any officer as aforesaid shall have ren<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dered service, purchased supplies, or advanced money for the use and benefit of the late Republic of Texas, under the sanc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the law, the District Attorney shall authorized in such events to allow the same as a credit in settlement, retaining proper vouches therefor, which claim or claims shall be filed by said Attorney in the office of Comptroller of Public Accounts; provided, that no allowance shall be made for any claim or account where the services rendered, advances made or supplies furnished, were by any other person or persons than the officer himself who presents them as offsets to his indebted<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness; provided, that no amount shall be allowed as an offset as <pb n="1319" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="35" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>provided for in this section, until the same shall have been ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved by the Comptroller.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That said District Attorneys in settling with the sheriffs as ex-officio tax collectors, shall be authorized to make allowances for insolvent and delinquent tax payers, requiring the officer claim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing such credit to verify under oath the correctness of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That whenever said District Attorneys are unable to settle with any revenue officer of the late Republic as aforesaid, they shall immediately institute suit against said officer for the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />covery of the amount due, as shown by the account furnished by the Comptroller; and in all eases where suits are commenced against a defaulting officer, after having been called upon to settle by the District Attorney, the right of said official to plead offsets as provided for in a preceding section of this act, or any other benefits by this act extended, shall be by said officer forfeited.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That in all cases of delinquences, where suit has or shall he instituted against a collector of public revenue, a certificate from the books of the Comptroller, duty certified to by him and au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thenticated under the seal of his office, stating the amount due, shall be admitted as evidence, and the court trying the cause may grant judgment and award execution accordingly. When suit is brought upon a bond or other sealed instrument, and the defendant shall plead non est factum, upon motion to the court, such plea or motion being verified by the oath or affirmation of the defendant, the court may take the same into consideration, and if it shall ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pear to be necessary to the attainment of justice, may require the production of the original bond, or other paper specified in such affidavit; when a receiver of public moneys as aforesaid, shall have allowed interest on any public liability issued to bear interest, the amount of interest so allowed by said officer to the party from whom he received such security, shall be allowed to him, the officer, as a credit in settlement.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That when any officer as aforesaid, or any person, is in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />debted in the treasury notes of the late Republic of Texas, it shall be lawful for him to discharge said indebtedness by the payment of twenty-cents in gold or silver for every dollar such officer or per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son is indebted in the Treasury notes aforesaid, either to the Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict Attorney of the District in which he resides, or at the Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer&#8217;s office in the city of Austin.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That the several District Attorneys shall report and pay over the amounts by them collected to the Comptroller <pb n="1320" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="36" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>at least every six months, or oftener if said Comptroller shall re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quire it, and it shall be the duty of the said Comptroller to furnish such instructions to the said District Attorneys as may tend to carry out efficiently the intention of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That the said District Attorneys shall receive as com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pensation under this act, ten per cent, on the amount by them collected by suit, and five per cent. on amount by them arranged, and the said District Attorneys&#8217; interest shall be in the debts ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cording to the manner of settling them.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That the act approved February 11th, 1850, to provide for the settlement of the Fiscal Affairs of the late Republic of Texas, be and the same is hereby repealed, and this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXV. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Supplementary to An Act entitled &#8220;An Act to restore lands sold for taxes and purchased by the State, to the former owners, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved January 28th, 1852.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the time allowed to former owners of land sold for taxes, to discharge their liability, and have said lands restored to them, by the act to which this is a supplement, be, and the same is hereby extended to the first day of January, eighteen hundred and fifty-four, and all such lands are hereby restored to the said former owners, upon their complying with the terms prescribed in the act to which this is a supplement.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1321" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="37" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVI. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To create the County of Hill.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all the territory comprised in the following limits, to wit: beginning on the south-west line of Ellis county, at a point twenty-two miles from its west corner; thence with the south-west line of said county of Ellis to its south corner; thence to the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />treme north corner of Limestone county; thence with the bound<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />aries of Limestone and McLennan counties, as now defined, to the Brazos river; thence up that river, with its meanders, to a point south seventy five degrees west from the place of beginning, thence north, seventy-five degrees east, to the beginning, be and the same is hereby constituted a new county, by the name of the county of Hill.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the chief-justice of Navarro county shall, within six months after the passage of this act, order an election for four commissioners and a chief-justice, one sheriff and one clerk of the county court, which election shall be advertized at three public places in said county, stating the time and place, which shall be at some suitable place nearest the centre of said county, and shall be conducted in all other respects, in accordance with the general laws governing elections; and it shall be the duty of said chief-justice of Navarro county, to qualify said officers of said county when elected, and organize said new county in accordance with an act to provide for organizing new counties, approved March the 20th, 1848.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That it shall be the duty of the county court of said new county, so soon as they are duly qualified, to proceed to locate the county-seat of said county, by selecting at least three eligible sites, not exceeding five miles from the centre of said county, having respect for any donation of land that may be made for that purpose, and when so selected the chief-justice shall order an election, which shall be conducted according to the general laws governing elections for county officers; and if at the first election neither of the sites so selected shall receive a majority of all the votes cast, the place receiving the smallest number of votes shall be thrown out; and the chief-justice shall order another election as before, and so con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue to do, throwing out the site receiving the smallest number of votes, until some one of the sites selected shall receive a majo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1322" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="38" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>rity of all the votes cast, which shall be declared the county-seat of said county, and be called Hillsborough.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the county court of said county shall have power to purchase, if necessary, three hundred and twenty acres of land for the use of the county, and shall lay the same off into suitable lots for a town; and after selecting and setting apart such suitable lots as may be necessary for a court-house, jail, clerk&#8217;s offices, churches, school-houses and burying ground, they shall proceed to sell the remainder or such portion thereof as they may deem neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary, at public auction, at such time and upon such terms as will most conduce to the interest of said county, and shall apply the proceeds thereof to the erection of necessary public buildings for the use of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the chief-justice of Navarro county shall be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled to two dollars per day for every day he is employed or de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained in holding said elections and organizing said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That all that territory situated north of the county hereby created, and which was heretofore included within the limits of Navarro county, be attached to and form a part of the territorial limits of the said new county; and for all county and general purposes shall form a part of the same after the organiza<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the same, and the location of the seat of justice thereof; and the county hereby created shall be attached to and form a part of the thirteenth judicial district.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 1, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution concerning the Public Archives of Bexar County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, there are in the office of the County Clerk of Bexar, rec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ords written in the Spanish language, which are of great his<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />torical value, extending over a period of more than a century, and which should be translated into the English language, and such translation filed in the office of Secretary of State, for fu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture use; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor he authorised to employ some <pb n="1323" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="39" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>suitable person or persons to translate and arrange all such Span<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ish documents of historical value to be found among said archives, of a date anterior to the evacuation of San Antonio by the Mexican troops in 1836, and file said translation in the Department of State, for future use, and the sum of one thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, is hereby appropriated to pay for the same.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution relating to the Volunteers called into the service by the Governor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, in the opinion of the Governor of this State, emergen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cies have existed which required the services of the citizen sol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diers of the State during the past summer, on a portion of the Rio Grande; and whereas, the Governor, to meet such emergency, has called into service the companies commanded respectively by Captains Shaw, Lewis and Daws; and whereas, the services of the said companies have not been recognized by the Govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the United States, and that the United States should not hesitate to re-imburse the State the amount thus paid; there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore,</p>
<p>Sec. 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall be the duty of the Governor, upon a final settlement being made between the State and the companies above mentioned, to forward the evidences of such settlement to the President of the United States, with the request that he will take such measures as will tend to the speedy re-imbursement of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That our Senators and Representatives in the Congress of the United States, be requested to urge the passage of an appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priation at the earliest moment for the re-imbursement of the State of the amount thus paid.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the Governor be requested to forward a copy of this Joint Resolution to each of our Senators and Representatives in the Congress of the United States.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1324" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="40" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIX. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To limit the Boards of Land Commissioners, and more clearly to define their duties.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Boards of Land Commissioners of the different counties of the State shall continue to issue unconditional cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates until the thirty-first day of December, 1853, to such original grantees of conditional certificates as shall appear in per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son before any of said Boards, take the oath and make all the other proof now required by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That any person applying for an unconditional cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate under the provisions of this act, shall make application for the same either in the county where the original conditional was issued, or in the county in which the applicant shall reside at the time of his application.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the Boards of Land Commissioners are hereby pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />hibited from issuing an unconditional certificate to any person who shall not fully comply with the first and second Sections of this act, and the individual members of any Board of Land Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners who shall concur in issuing any certificate contrary to the provisions of this act, shall be deemed guilty of a high mis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />demeanor, and upon conviction thereof, before any Court of com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />petent jurisdiction, shall be fined in a sum not less than five hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred nor more than one thousand dollars for each and every such of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fence, and shall be dismissed from office; and the Boards of Land Commissioners before issuing any such unconditional certificate, shall cause public notice to be given at the expense of the claimant, setting forth the object of the application of the claimants.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That from and after the 31st December, 1853, the func<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions of the various Boards of Land Commissioners of the State shall cease.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That all laws and parts of laws contravening the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act, are hereby repealed; and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1325" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="41" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXX. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To provide for the erection of a fire-proof building, for a Treasury Department and Comptroller&#8217;s Office of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of twenty thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby set apart out of any money in the Treasury of the State not otherwise appropriated, to be expended in the erection of a fire-proof building on the north-east corner of capitol square in the city of Austin, for a Treasury Department and Comptroller&#8217;s Office, which said fire-proof building shall, as near as practicable, in its appearenee, plan and style of architecture, conform to that of the General Land Office: Provided, That no part of the fore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />going appropriation shall be drawn from the Treasury until the amount thereof shall have been realized from the sale of city lots, as provided for in this act, over and above the cost of sales and collections.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Treasurer and Comptroller of public Accounts of the State act as Commissioners for the erection of said fire-proof building; and shall, at the earliest practicable period after the passage of this act, determine the plan of said fire-proof building, and cause an advertisement to be inserted in one of the public newspapers printed in the city of Austin, for three suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessive weeks, and let out, to the lowest bidder, in the said city of Austin, on a day to be fixed in said advertisement, the building of said fire-proof house, in one or more contracts, as shall seem to them best, requiring the said contractor or contractors to enter into bonds, with two or more good and sufficient securities, to be approved by them, in double the amount of their respective con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tracts, conditioned for the faithful performance of the same, within the time prescribed in said contract or contracts, not beyond the first day of July, eighteen hundred and fifty-four, which said bonds shall be made payable to the State of Texas, and shall be filed in the Comptroller&#8217;s Office, and may be put in suit against the obligors whenever the conditions of the same shall have been violated.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the Comptroller and Treasurer shall give bond and security, in the sum of twenty thousand dollars, for the faith<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ful discharge of their duties under this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the said Commissioners shall have the power <pb n="1326" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="42" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>to aid the several contractors to facilitate the execution of their said contracts, by paying to them such sums of money as may be necessary for that purpose, in no ease going beyond the amount of work actually done, or material furnished by them, the said con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tractors.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That said Commissioners present to the next regular session of the Legislature, a full report of the expenditures under this act, with the progress of the work, and such other items touch<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the erection of said building as may he necessary for its in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formation.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the money disbursed from the Treasury under the provisions of this act, shall he charged against the unsold lots and outlots in the city of Austin, and reimbursed to the Treasury out of the sale of the same; and the Comptroller is hereby required to make sale of a sufficient number of lots, from time to time, as shall be sufficient to carry into effect the intent of this section.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXI. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Supplementary to an Act entitled an Act to provide for the erec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of a State Capitol, approved February 14th, 1852.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That he sum of fifty thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated in addition to the amount appropriated by the act to which this is a supplement, to be employed by the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners elected under said act, in providing for changing the orig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />inal interior plan of said State Capitol, so as to provide a Supreme Court room, thirty by sixty feet, to be taken off of one of the two principal rooms of the upper story, and to meet the expenses of such other changes as have been made in the style and archi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tecture of said building, from the contract entered into with Messrs. McGehee &#38; Moore on the day of, and for any other work which may be necessary to be done on said building.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the said sum of fifty thousand dollars shall be <pb n="1327" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="43" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>paid by the Treasurer of the State out of any money in the State Treasury not otherwise appropriated, upon the draft of said Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners as provided for in the act to which this is a supple<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, provided, that no part of this appropriation shall be drawn until the contractors for the erection of the Capitol enter into a new bond, with ample security, for the faithful compliance with their contract, under the new plan adopted, and that no further appropriation shall be made for any extra work or change of plan.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXII. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To amend an Act entitled &#8220;An Act authorizing the County Court of El Paso county to appoint the place of holding the District Courts in said county, and defining the time of holding the Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict Courts in the Eleventh Judicial District,&#8221; approved De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cember 24th, 1851.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the second section of the act to which this act is amendatory, be, and the same is hereby amended, so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>That the District Courts of the Eleventh Judicial District shall commence in the county of El Paso, on the third Monday of April, and on the first Monday of September in each year, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session as long as the business may require.</p>
<p>Section 2. That all laws and parts of laws conflicting with the provisions of this act, be and the same are hereby repealed, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1328" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="44" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIII. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To define the times of holding the District Courts in the Third and Thirteenth Judicial Districts.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the District Courts in the Third Judicial District, shall commence in the county of Washington on the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Burleson on the fourth Mondays after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Milam on the fifth Mondays after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in April and October, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of McLennan, on the sixth Mondays after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Bell, on the seventh Mondays after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of, on the eighth Mondays after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>The county of Williamson shall be included in the Third Judi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cial District, and the District Courts shall be held in Williamson county on the twelfth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all laws and parts of laws, heretofore enacted, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lating to the time of holding the several Courts in said Third Ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicial District be, and the same are hereby repealed; and that all process which has been issued, and made returnable to the several Courts of said District, shall be, and are hereby made returnable to the said Courts respectively, at the periods of their sessions, as specified in this act; and that all recognizances and bonds entered into by any person or persons in said Courts, with reference to the period of their respective sessions, under the laws heretofore in force, shall be, and the same are hereby made obligatory upon the parties, with reference to terms of said Courts respectively, as pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the Spring terms for the year 1853, of the Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1329" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="45" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>trict Court, held in the Thirteenth Judicial District, shall be held as are herein provided, to wit:</p>
<p>In Leon county, on the first Monday in May, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In Madison county, on the third Monday in May, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session one week.</p>
<p>In Brazos county, on the fourth Monday in May, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session one week.</p>
<p>In Robertson county, on the first Monday after the fourth Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />day in May, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In Falls county, on the second Monday after the fourth Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />day in May, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In Limestone county, on the third Monday after the fourth Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />day in May, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>in freestone county, on the fourth Monday after the fourth Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />day in May, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In Navarro county, on the fifth Monday after the fourth Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />day in May, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In Hill county, on the seventh Monday after the fourth Monday in May, and may continue in session until the business of the Court is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the terms of the District Court of the aforesaid District, shall, after the proviions of the second section of this act, be held as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>In Leon county, on the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In Madison county, on the third Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In Brazos county, on the fourth Mondays of April and October, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In Robertson county, on the first Mondays after the fourth Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in April and October, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In Falls county, on the second Mondays after the fourth Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in April and October, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In Limestone county, on the third Mondays after the fourth Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In Freestone county, on the fourth Mondays after the fourth Mondays of April and October, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In Navarro county, on the fifth Monday after the fourth <pb n="1330" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="46" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In Hill county, on the seventh Mondays after the fourth Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in April and October, and may continue in session until the business of the session is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That all writs and process that have been, or may here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after be issued from any of the District Courts of the Third Judi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cial District, embraced in the Thirteenth Judicial District, shall be considered as returnable, and shall be returned to the terms as es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tablished by this act, and shall have the same force and effect as if the same had originally been so returnable; and that all laws con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />flicting with the provisions of this act, be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIV. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Supplementary to an Act entitled An Act authorizing the issuing of duplicate Land Warrants, Discharges and Headrights, on cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain conditions, and providing for the loss of Land Scrip.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That any person who has lost, or who may hereafter loose Land Scrip be, and they are hereby included in the act authorizing the issuing of duplicate land warrants, discharges and headrights on certain conditions, approved January 14th, 1840, by complying with the conditions specified in the same; provided, that the owner of said land scrip or claim, shall, previous to applying for a dupli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate of the same, cause the publication required by said act to be made for sixty days, in some newspaper in the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the provisions of said act to which this is a sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plement, shall apply and be in force in all cases as to the parties applying for and obtaining under this act such duplicate land scrip.</p>
<pb n="1331" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="47" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3. That when headright certificates, land scrip, land war<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rants, discharges or other claims to land owned by two or more parties may be lost, it shall be lawful for the parties owning the same, to make jointly or severally the affidavit Required by the third section of the act to which this is a supplement.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXV. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Granting the use of certain portions of Galveston Bay, to the Gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veston Dry Dock company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the right of so much of the Bay opposite the city of Galveston, on the North side of the Channel, as may be necessary for the erection of a Dry Dock, and the other necessary buildings and convenience be, and the same is hereby granted to the Galves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton Dry Dock Company; provided, that said company shall not in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jure or unreasonably obstruct the Channel, Harbor, or anchorage of said Bay.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVI. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To define the time of holding the Dictrict Courts in the Ninth. Judicial District.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the District Court in the Ninth Judicial District <pb n="1332" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="48" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>of this State, shall be held in the several counties composing the same, at the times herein specified, to wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Houston, on the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county oi Anderson, on the third Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Henderson, on the first Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Van Zandt, on the second Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Kaufman, on the third Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Ellis, on the fourth Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Tarrant, on the fifth Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Dallas, on the sixth Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continne in session two weeks.</p>
<p>Section 2. That all writs and process of every kind that have been or may hereafter be issued from any of the District Courts of the Ninth Judicial District, shall be considered returnable, and shall be returned to the terms established by this act, and all such writs and process shall have the same force and effect as if they had originally been issued and made so returnable. And that all laws and parts of laws, conflicting with the provisions of this act, be, and they are hereby repealed, and this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act confirming the acts of J. H. Raymond, State Treasurer.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the acts of J. H. Raymond, Treasurer of the State, <pb n="1333" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="49" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>in disbursing the five per cent. United States bonds at three per cent. premium be, and the same are hereby confirmed; and this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVIII. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To prescribe the time of holding the District Courts in the Second Judicial District of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the terms of the District Courts of the second Judi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cial District, shall be held in each county in the District twice in each year, as follows:</p>
<p>In the county of Travis on the first Mondays in March and Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Hays on the fourth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Comal on the fifth Mondays after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Guadalupe on the sixth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Caldwell on the seventh Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Fayette on the eighth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Bastrop on the tenth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Burnet on the twelfth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. All process returnable to, and all cases triable at the <pb n="1334" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="50" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>regular terms of the District Courts of the Second Judicial Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict, as now provided for by law, shall be returnable to and triable at the regular terms herein prescribed. That all laws and parts of laws conflicting with the provisions of this act be, and they are hereby repealed, and that this act be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIX. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Supplementary to An Act to prohibit Assessors and Collectors of Taxes from exercising Official functions before they are duly qualified, approved September fifth, eighteen hundred and fifty.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the act to which this is supplementary shall apply to Assessors and Collectors who are in arrearages to the county, as well as to those who are in arrearages to the State, upon notice of the fact to the Secretary of the State or Comptroller, from the Chief Justice or County Court of the County where said delinquent Assessor and Collector resides.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XL. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Making appropriations for the purposes therein named.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the following sums be and the same are hereby ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated:</p>
<p>To W. C. Gould, for expenses on the transporting of public <pb n="1335" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="51" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>arms from Galveston to Austin, one hundred dollars and thirty-six cents.</p>
<p>For stationery for next Legislature, five hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For fire-proof safe for Land Office, five hundred dollars,</p>
<p>For translating and interpreting to Commissioners to examine land titles west of the Nueces, (to be paid on final settlement of the account of said Commissioners with the Comptroller), seven hundred and forty-five dollars.</p>
<p>To W. H. Parsons, Associate Justice of the Supreme Court, one hundred dollars.</p>
<p>To three Presidential Electors, for their mileage ana per diem pay, one hundred and seventy-seven dollars.</p>
<p>For repairing Treasurer&#8217;s Office, two hundred and fify dollars and eighty cents.</p>
<p>For repairing Secretary of State&#8217;s Office, two hundred and eighty-four dollars and eighty-four cents.</p>
<p>For copying the laws and resolutions of the last Legislature, for public printer, two hundred and sixty-six dollars and forty-four cents.</p>
<p>For land scrip heretofore surveyed, one thousand dollars.</p>
<p>To R. J. Jones, sheriff of Bexar county, for transporting con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />victs to the Penitentiary, forty-six dollars.</p>
<p>For contingent fund of both Houses of the Legislature, five thousand dollars.</p>
<p>To Executive Office for translating the laws of last and present session of the Legislature in the German language, five hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For clerk&#8217;s hire to Land Office for making abstract of land ti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tles, one hundred dollars.</p>
<p>To J. W. Hampton, for printing and binding, one hundred and five dollars.</p>
<p>To expenses incurred by James B. Shaw, in connection with the sale of eight hundred thousand dollars United States bonds, five per cents., eleven thousand one hundred and sixty-six dollars and sixteen cents.</p>
<p>For costs clue the clerk of the Supreme Court of the United States, incurred in two suits instituted by the State of Texas to establish the illegality of the fraudulent certificates, one hundred dollars.</p>
<p>To the members and officers of the Legislature of this session, for their per diem pay and mileage, the unexpended balance of the appropriation made at the last session of the Legislautre, to be drawn for as formerly in such cases.</p>
<p>Ninety-six dollars, annually, to David F. Wells, for two <pb n="1336" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="52" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>years, as a pension, commencing from the expiration of the last appropriation for his benefit.</p>
<p>For expenses incurred by John Dusenberry, in bringing the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mains of the decimated Mier prisoners from the place of their mas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sacre to LaGrange, three hundred and fifty dollars.</p>
<p>To E. Dougherty, late assessor and collector of the county of Cameron, for taking and returning the census of 1851, one hundred and forty-three dollars.</p>
<p>To M. B. Irwin, the balance due to him for distributing Hart<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ley&#8217;s Digest, the laws and journals, three hundred and fifty-one dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars and twenty-two cents.</p>
<p>To James B. Shaw, eleven hundred and fifty dollars, claim pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sented last session.</p>
<p>For translating and printing laws of present session, in the Span<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ish language, two hundred and fifty dollars.</p>
<p>For pension, commencing January 1, 1853, and payable quarter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ly, to Henry Tierwester. a disabled soldier of the Texas revolu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, per annum, one hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For Samuel Yerger and Robert C. Campbell, special Associate Justices of the Supreme Court in the ease of Morrell, wife, et al, vs. Haynie, from Grimes county, each, one hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For a second assistant draughtsman for the General Land Office, per annum, seven hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For salary of one district judge for the thirteenth judicial dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict, seventeen hundred and fifty dollars.</p>
<p>For salary of one district attorney for the thirteenth judicial dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict, five hundred dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The above amounts shall be paid out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, arising from the interest accruing on the bonds of indemnity issued by the United States Government to the State of Texas, and the same shall be drawn for and paid out in conformity with existing laws regulating the payment of money out of the Treasury of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Nineteen hundred and fifty dollars of United States five per cent, indemnity bonds, for amount of interest due the General School Fund on State bonds, issued December 2, 1850, under the act for the safe and profitable investment of the School Fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. And this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1337" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="53" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLI. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To change the Northern Boundary of the County of Williamson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the northern boundary line of Williamson county be, and the same is hereby established, to begin at the point where the said northern boundary line crosses the Salado Cheek, thence in a straight line to the most eastern corner of Burnet county; thence following the boundary line of Burnet county to its nearest junc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion with the present boundary of Williamson county, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLII. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Relating to Appeals and Writs of Error from the Thirteenth Judi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cial District.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all cases taken by appeal, writ of error, or other pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cess by law provided, from any District Court within the Thir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teenth Judicial District to the Supreme Court of the State, shall be returnable to the said Supreme Court at the city of Austin, from and after the passage of this act.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution proposing an amendment to the Constitution.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the following be proposed as an amendment to the amendment to the Constitution of the State of Texas, to be added to such <pb n="1338" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="54" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>amendment, as section 3; which, when ratified as provided for by the thirty-seventh section of the seventh Article of said Constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, shall be valid to all intents and purposes as a part of said Constitution:</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That in case a vacancy shall from any cause occur in any of the offices mentioned in the first section of the amendment of the Constitution, the Governor shall appoint some suitable person to fill such vacancy, who shall continue to discharge the duties of such office until the time of the next general election established by law for the election of State or County officers, and until his successor shall have been elected and qualified.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIV. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To extend the provisions of an act entitled an act to provide for ascertaining the debt of the late Republic of Texas, approved March 20th, 1848.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the time within which it shall he necessary for the creditors of the late Bepublic of Texas to present their claims for personal services, civil or military, and for supplies, to the Auditor and Comptroller be, and the same is hereby extended for the term of eighteen months from the passage of this act; and all claims not presented by that time shall be barred; provided, that nothing in this act contained shall authorize the Auditor and Comptroller to acknowledge any class of claims not heretofore by law provided for.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Auditor and Comptroller shall immediately cause a notice of this extension to be published for three months in some weekly newspaper printed in Austin, and in two papers printed in Eastern, and in two in the Western Congressional Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tricts; and in other respects the said officers shall be required to perform the same duties as required of them by an act to provide for ascertaining the debt of the late Republic of Texas, approved March the 20th, 1848.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1339" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="55" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an additional appropriation for a Contingent Fund.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of two thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be, and the same is hereby appropriated, as an addition to the fund heretofore set apart to defray the contingent expenses of the present extraordinary session of the Legislature, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to regulate Railroad Companies.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all railroad companies which have been heretofore incorporated, or which shall hereafter be incorporated, or relieved from the performance of any act required of them, or which shall accept of any donation or loan from this State, or which shall ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cept of the subscription of any county of this State, shall have all the powers and privileges, and be subject to all the duties, liabili<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties and provisions contained in this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. If the directors of any such company shall declare and pay any dividend when the company is insolvent, or any dividend, the payment of which would render it insolvent, they shall be jointly and severally liable for all the debts of the company then existing, and for all that shall be thereafter contracted, so long as they shall respectively continue in office; provided, that if any of the directors shall be absent at the time of making the dividend, or shall object thereto, and shall within thirty days thereafter, or after his return, if absent, file a certificate of their absence or objection in writing with the clerk of the company, and with the clerk of the county in which the principal office of said company is located, they shall be exempt from said liability.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. If any certificate or report made, or public notice <pb n="1340" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="56" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>given by the officers of any such company, in pursuance of the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act, shall be false in any material representation, all the officers who shall have signed the same, shall be jointly and severally liable for all the debts of the company contracted while they are officers or stockholders thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Such corporation shall, as soon as convenient after its organization, establish a principal office at some point on the line of its road, and change the same at pleasure, giving public notice in some newspaper of such establishment and change; and all pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cess against such company shall be served on the President or Secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary, or by leaving a copy at the principal office of the corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. No bridge or other obstruction shall be erected across, in or over any navigable stream, so as to prevent or unreasonably impede the navigation thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Such, corporation shall erect at all points where its road shall cross any public road at a sufficient elevation from such pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic road, to admit of the free passage of vehicles of every kind, a sign with large and distinct letters placed thereon to give notice of the proximity of the railroad, and warn persons of the necessity of looking out for the cars; and any company neglecting or refusing to erect such sign shall be liable in damages for all injuries occur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ring to persons or property from such neglect or refusal.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Every conductor, baggage-master, engineer, brakeman or other servant of any such railroad corporation, employed in a pas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />senger train, or at stations for passengers, shall wear upon his hat or cap, a badge which shall indicate his office, and the initial letters of the style of the corporation by which he is employed. No con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ductor or collector without such badge shall demand, or be entitled to receive from any passenger, any fare, toll, ticket, or exercise any of the powers of his office, and no other of the said officers or ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vants, without such badge, shall have any authority to meddle or interfere with the passengers, their baggage or property.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. If any passenger shall refuse to pay his fare or toll, it shall be lawful for the conductor of the train and the servants of the corporation, to put him out of the cars at any usual stopping place which the conductor may select.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Every such corporation shall start and run their cars for the transportation of passengers and property at regular times, to be fixed by public notice, and shall furnish sufficient accommodations for the transportation of all such passengers and property as shall within a reasonable time previous there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1341" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="57" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>to, offer or be offered for transportation at the place of starting, and the junctions of other railroads, and at sidings and stopping places established for receiving and discharging way-passengers and freights, and shall take, transport, and discharge such passengers and property at, from and to such places, on the due payment of the tolls, freight or fare legally authorized therefor.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. In case of refusal by such corporation or their agents so to take and transport any passenger or property, or to deliver the same or either of them at the regular or appointed time, such corporation shall pay to the party aggrieved, all damages which shall be sustained thereby, with costs of suit.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. A check shall be affixed to every package or parcel of baggage, when taken for transportation by the agent or servant of such corporation, and a duplicate thereof giving to the passenger or person delivering the same on his behalf; and if such check be refused on demand, the corporation shall pay to such passenger the sum of ten dollars to be recovered in an action of debt; and, further, no fare or toll shall be collected or received from uch pas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />senger; and if such passenger shall have paid his or her fare, the same shall be refunded by the conductor in charge of the train; and on producing said check, if his or her baggage shall not be delivered to him or to her, he or she may, himself or herself be a witness in any suit brought by him or her to prove the contents and value of said baggage.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. In forming a passenger train, baggage or freight or merchandize or lumber cars shall not be placed in rear of pas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />senger cars; and if they or any of them shall be so placed, and any accident happen to life or limb, the officer or agent who so directed, or knowingly suffered such arrangement, and the conductor and en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gineer of the train shall each and all be held guilty of intentionally causing the injury, and be punished accordingly.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. A bell, of at least thirty pounds weight, or a steam whistle shall he placed on each locomotive engine, and the bell shall be rung, or whistle blown, at the distance of at least eighty rods from the place where the railroad shall cross any road or street, and be kept ringing or blowing until it shall have crossed such road or street, or stopped, under a penalty of fifty dollars for every neglect, to be paid by the corporation owning the railroad; one half therof to go to the informer, and the other half to the State, and also be liable for all damages which shall be sustained by any person by reason of such neglect.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That if any person shall, while in charge of a loco<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1342" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="58" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>motive engine, running upon the railroad of any such corporation, or while acting as the conductor of a car, or train of cars on any such railroad, be intoxicated, he shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and be punished by fine or imprisonment, or both.</p>
<p>Sec. 15, It shall be lawful for the legislature at any time, to prescribe the rates to be charged for the transportation of persons and property upon any such road, should they be deemed too high; and may exercise the same power every ten years; provided, that no reduction shall be made, unless the nett profits of the company for the previous ten years, the expenditures of the company, being bona fide, and not with a view to defeat the operation of this sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, shall amount to a sum equal to twelve per centum per annum upon its capital stock, and then so as not to reduce the future probable profits below the said per centum.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. Every such company shall at all reasonable times, and for a reasonable compensation, draw over their road the passengers, merchandize and cars of any other railroad corporation which may enter and connect with their railroad; and if the respective com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />panies cannot agree upon the compensation aforesaid, it shall be the duty of the President of each company to select one man as a commissioner, and the two commissioners so selected, shall choose a third in case of disagreement, neither of whom shall be a stock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holder in either road, or interested therein, and they shall fix the rates, which shall not be changed for one year from the time of going into effect; the said commissioners shall also fix the stated periods at which said cars are to be drawn as aforesaid, having ref<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erence to the convenience and interest of said corporations and the public who shall be accommodated thereby; the right or power is specially conferred on any railroad company to enter and connect with any other railroad within the scope of its designated route and branches.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. If the Legislature of this State shall at any time make provision by law, for the repayment to any such company of the amount expended by them in the construction of said road, together with all monies for permanent fixtures, ears, en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gines, machinery, chattels and real property, then in use for the said road, with all monies expended for repairs or otherwise, and interest on such sums at the rate of twelve per centum per annum after deducting the amount of tolls, freights, passage mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ey, and all monies received from the sale of lands donated by the State to said company, with twelve per centum per annum inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1343" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="59" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>est on all such sums, then the road with all its fixtures and appur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tenances aforesaid, and all the lands donated to the same by the State and remaining unsold, shall vest in and revert to this State; provided, that the State shall not be required to pay, or allow a greater rate of interest on any amount of the money so expended by any company which shall have been borrowed from this State, than the State shall have received for the same from such comnany.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. Every such, corporation shall make an annual report to the Comptroller of Public Accounts of this State of the opera<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions of the year ending on the first clay of October, which report shall be verified by the oaths of the Treasurer and acting superin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tendent of operations, and filed in his office by the twentieth of October in each year, and shall state<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />&#8212;</p>
<p>1st. The capital stock ana the amount actually paid in.</p>
<p>2nd. The amount expended for the purchase of land for the construction of the road, for buildings and for engines and cars, respectively.</p>
<p>3rd. The amount of nature and its indebtedness, and the amount due the corporation.</p>
<p>4th. The amount received for the transportation of passengers, of property, of the mail, and from all other sources.</p>
<p>5th. The amount of freight, specifying the quantity in tons, of the product of the forest, of animals, of vegetable food, other agri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cultural products. manufactures, merchandize anrl other articles.</p>
<p>6th. The amount paid out for repairs, engines, cars, buildings and salaries respectively.</p>
<p>7th. The number and amount of dividends and when made.</p>
<p>8th. The number of engine houses, and shops, of engines and cars, and their character.</p>
<p>9th. The number of miles run by passenger, freight and other trains, respectively.</p>
<p>10th. The number of men employed and their occupations.</p>
<p>11th. The number of persons injured in life or limb, and the cause of such injuries.</p>
<p>12th. Whether any accidents have arisen from carelessness or negligence of any person in the employment of the corporations, and whether such person is retained in the service of the corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>
<p>13. The sales of lands donated by the State, and the quantity remaining unsold.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. Any such corporation, which shall neglect to make such report, shall be liable to a penalty of two hundred and fif<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1344" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="60" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ty dollars, to be sued tor in the name of the State. And any cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration so neglecting, which shall neglect to make such report within three months after notice to the President or any director thereof of such failure by the Comptroller, shall forfeit its charter.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. Every such corporation shall, when applied to by the Postmaster General, convey the mail of the United States on its road or roads; and in case such corporation shall not agree as to the rate of transportation therefor, and as to the time, rate or speed, manner and condition of conveying the same, it shall be lawful for the Governor of the State to appoint three commissioners, who, or a majority of them, after fifteen days notice in writing, of the time and place of meeting to the corporation, shall determine and fix the prices, terms and condition aforesaid; but such price shall not be less for conveying said mails in the regular passenger trains, than the amount which such corporation would receive as freight on a like weight of merchandize, transported in their merchandize trains, and a fair compensation for the post office car; and in case the post master General shall require the mail to be carried at other hours, or at a higher speed than the passenger train be run at, the corporation shall furnish an extra train for the mail, and be al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowed an extra compensation for the expenses and wear and tear thereof, and for the services, to be fixed as aforesaid.</p>
<p>Sec. 21. Every such corporation shall within a reasonable time after their road shall be located, cause to be made,</p>
<p>1st. A map and profile thereof, and of the land taken or ob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained for the use thereof, and file the same in the General Land Office of this State, and also like maps of the parts thereof located in different counties, and file the same in the offices of the County Clerk and District Surveyor of the county in which such parts of said road shall be, there to remain as a record forever. Every such map shall he drawn on a scale and on paper to be designated by the Commissioner of the General Landoffice, and certified and signed by the President of the corporation.</p>
<p>2nd. A certificate specifying the line upon which it is proposed to construct the railroad and the grades and curves certified and signed and filed as aforesaid.</p>
<p>Sec. 22. The width of the track or gauge of all roads in the State shall he six feet.</p>
<p>Sec. 23. The Legislature may examine the books of any such company by committee or otherwise, as often as may be deemed expedient.</p>
<pb n="1345" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="61" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 24. Every such company shall have a good and sufficient brake upon the hindmost car on all trains transporting passengers and merchandize, and also permanently stationed there a trusty and faithful brakeman, under a penalty of not exceeding one hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars for each offence, to be recovered by suit in the name of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 25. Every proxy shall be dated within six months previous to the meeting of the stockholders at which said proxy is to he voted on.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVII. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>To facilitate the operations of persons engaged in the United States Coast Survey, in the State of Texas, under proper restrictions.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, according to the provisions of an act of the Congress of of the United States, passed February 10th, 1807, and of acts Supplementary thereto, and in pursuance of the same, the opera<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions of the United States Coast Survey have reached the coast of Texas, and it is important that, such operations should be car<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ried on without hindrance or injurys, and that certain privileges should be granted to persons employed in the same, without detriment nevertheless to the citizens of Texas. Therefore.</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That any and every person employed under, and by virtue of an act of the Congress of the United States, passed February 10th, 1807, and the acts supplementary thereto, concerning the United States Coast Survey, may enter upon lands within this State and clear and cut timber upon the same, and may erect thereon any works, buildings, stations, monuments, signals or ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pendages requisite for the purpose of exploring, surveying, triangu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lation, leveling or doing any other act requisite or proper to effect the objects of said acts of Congress, without being considered as a trespasser or trespassers; provided, no unnecessary injury be done thereby.</p>
<pb n="1346" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="62" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. That it the parties interested, namely, the person or per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons acting under or representing the Government of the United States in the said Coast Survey, on the coast of Texas, and the per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son or persons owning or possessing any land so entered upon and to which damage may have been done, cannot agree together upon the amount to he paid for the damages by doing any of the acts aforesaid, either of them may complain in a summary manner to the Chief-Justice of the county in which said land is situated; who shall associate with himself two disinterested free-holders of said county, one to be named by each party interested, and the said Chief-Justice and free-holders shall, upon hearing the parties and their evidence, and with or without view of the premises, as they may determine, proceed to assess, award and adjudge such damages as may have accrued to the owners or possessors of said land; provided, that the said Chief-Justice shall so soon as said complaint is made before him, fix a day and place for the hearing thereof, of which the opposite party shall have at least ten days notice; and provided further, that if said Chief-Justice and free<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holders can not agree as to said damages, the decision of any two of them agreeing shall be their judgment or award.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the Chief-Justice and free-holders, or the two of them agreeing, shall enter up in writing a brief statement of the matters in controversy before them, and also their judgment or award, which shall be signed by them or the two agreeing, and shall be within ten days thereafter, filed in the office of the Clerk of the District Court of the same county, and upon satisfaction and payment of the said amount of damages, the same shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clusive evidence of the assent of said owners or possessors in the premises; provided, that either party shall have the right within ten days after the filing of such judgment or award in the office of said clerk, to file objections to said judgment or award, of which a copy shall be issued by said clerk and served upon the opposite party, whereupon the said judgment or award shall be suspended, and an issue shall be made up and a trial had, at the first succeeding term of said District Court; as in other cases; and provided further, that unless said objections be filed within the said ten days, or satisfaction made of said judgment or award, execution may issue thereon by the clerk of said court as in other cases.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That any person or persons so entering upon any land as aforesaid, for the purposes aforesaid, may tender to the party injured sufficient amends for any damage done upon said <pb n="1347" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="63" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>lands, and if upon examination before said Chief-Justice and free<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holders as aforesaid, or upon the trial before the District Court as aforesaid, the damages finally assessed shall not exceed the amount so tendered, the person or persons so entering and mak<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing tender of amends shall recover his or their costs.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the costs on any proceedings by virtue of this act, shall be by analogy to the compensation for like services, performed by the same officers, the said free-holders to be allowed two dollars per day each, for every day of necessary service they may perform.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That all complaints and actions against any person or persons, entering on any land as aforesaid, shall be forever barred, unless prosecuted with one year from the time the cause of such complaint or action occurred.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That if any person or persons shall wilfully or wantonly injure, deface or remove any signal, monument, work, building or appendage to any of them used or constructed within the State of Texas, under and by virtue of the acts of Congress aforesaid, he and they shall be liable to indictment for the same, under this statute, for each and every such offence, and upon conviction there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />of, shall be sentenced to pay a fine of not less than fifty nor more than five hundred dollars, one half of which shall go to the prose<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cutor, and the remainder to the State of Texas, or shall be im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prisoned not less than one month, nor more than six months, or both at the discretion of the jury, and shall also be liable for all damages sustained by the United States of America, by reason of any such injury, defacement or removal, to be recovered by action in any court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1348" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="64" /><fw type="header" place="top">Certificate.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">STATE OF TEXAS.</head>
<p>I, THOMAS H. DUVAL, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, certify that the second session of the Fourth Legislature of said State commenced its session at the City of Austin, on Monday, the tenth day of January, in the year one thousand eight hundred and fifty-three, and adjourned on Monday, the seventh day of February, in the year one thousand eight hundred and fifty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />three.</p>
<p>And I further certify, that the Acts and Joint Resolutions con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained in this Volume, are true copies, taken from the original rolls deposited in the Department of State, with which they have been carefully compared.</p>
<p>[L. S. Given under my hand and Official Seal, at the City of Austin, the seyenteenth day of March, in the year one thousand eight hundred and fifty-three.</p>
<closer>
<signed>THOMAS H. DUVAL.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1349" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="i" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX TO GENERAL LAWS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">A</head>
<p>Page</p>
<p>APPORTIONMENT of Senators and Representatives among the sev several counties in the State, <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>APPROPRIATIONS&#8212;For defraying the expenses of three companies of volunteers called into the service of the State, for the protection of the frontier, <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; For the improvement of the rivers of the State, <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; For the purposes therein named, <ref>60</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; Additional, for a contingent fund, <ref>55</ref></p>
<p>APPEALS AND WRITS OF ERROR from the 13th Judicial District, act relating to, <ref>53</ref></p>
<p>ASSESSORS &#38; COLLECTORS OF TAXES&#8212;Supplementary to an act prohibiting, from exercising official functions before they are quali<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied, <ref>50</ref></p>
<p>AUSTIN&#8217;S SECOND COLONY and the Colony of Austin &#38; Williams, concerning lands in, <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; &#8220; and the Colony of Austin &#38; Williams, supplementary to an act concerning certain lands in, <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>ARCHIVES PUBLIC, of Bexar county, concerning, <ref>38</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">B</head>
<p>BEXAR COUNTY, concerning Public Archives of, <ref>38</ref></p>
<p>BOARDS OP LAND COMMISSIONERS limited and their duties more clearly defined, <ref>40</ref></p>
<pb n="1350" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="ii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">C</head>
<p>Page CAPITOL OP THE STATE&#8212;Supplementary to an act to provide for the erection of <ref>42</ref></p>
<p>COAST SURVEY-To facilitate the operations of persons engaged in, <ref>61</ref></p>
<p>COMAL COUNTY&#8212;County Court of, authorized to levy and collect a special tax, <ref>18</ref></p>
<p>COUNTY OF MADISON&#8212;Created, <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; HILL, <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; HIDALGO, act creating amended, <ref>18</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; CAMERON&#8212;Erected into a separate land dist.. <ref>31</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; STARR. &#8220; &#8220; &#8220; &#8220; <ref>31</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; WEBB &#8220; &#8220; &#8220; &#8220; <ref>31</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; NUECES &#8220; &#8220; &#8220; &#8220; <ref>31</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; SAN PATRICIO &#8220; &#8220; &#8220; <ref>31</ref></p>
<p>COUNTIES OF PRESIDIO AND EL PASO erected into a separate land district, <ref>31</ref></p>
<p>COUNTY OF WILLIAMSON, northern boundary of changed, <ref>53</ref></p>
<p>CERTIFICATES of Public Debt lost, relating to, <ref>28</ref></p>
<p>CAMERON COUNTY erected in a separate land district, <ref>31</ref></p>
<p>CLERK of the District Court of Houston county authorized to tran<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribe certain records.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">D</head>
<p>DISTRICT SURVEYORS&#8212;Election of regulated, <ref>26</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; JUDICIAL&#8212;Thirteenth, created. <ref>29</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; COURT of 10th Judicial District, time of holding defined, <ref>27</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; in the 3d and 13th Judicial Districts, times of holding defined, <ref>44</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; in the 9th Judicial District, times of holding de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fined, <ref>47</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; in the 2d Judicial District, times of holding pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed, <ref>49</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; &#8212;99th, 130th and 131st sections of an act to regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />late proceedings in, amended. <ref>19</ref></p>
<p>DEBT of the late Republic of Texas&#8212;to extend the provisions of an act, relating to the, <ref>54</ref></p>
<p>DUPLICATE LAND WARRANTS, Discharges and Headrights&#8212;Sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plementary to an act authorizing the issuing of, on certain conditions, and providing for the loss of land scrip, <ref>46</ref></p>
<pb n="1351" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">E</head>
<p>EL PASO COUNTY&#8212;Aet authorizing Eioimty Court of, to appoint the place of holding the District Court in said County, and defining the time of holding the District Courts in the 11th Judicial District, amended, <ref>48</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">F</head>
<p>FISCAL AFFAIRS of the late Republic of Texas, relating to, <ref>34</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">G</head>
<p>GALVESTON BAY&#8212;The use of certain portions of, granted to the Galveston Dry Dock Company, <ref>47</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H</head>
<p>HOUSTON COUNTY&#8212;Clerk of the District Court of, authorized to transcribe certain records, <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>HABEAS CORPUS&#8212;Right of appeal given in cases on, <ref>24</ref></p>
<p>HILL COUNTY&#8212;Created, <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>HIDALGO COUNTY&#8212;Act creating amended, <ref>18</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; &#8212;Erected into a separate land district, <ref>31</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">L</head>
<p>LANDS IN PETERS&#8217; COLONY&#8212;Supplementary to an act relating to, <ref>30</ref></p>
<p>LAND COMMISSIONERS&#8212;Boards of, limited and their duties more clearly defined, <ref>40</ref></p>
<p>LANDS IN AUSTIN&#8217;S SECOND COLONY, and the Colony of Austin &#38; Williams, concerning certain, <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>LANDS IN AUSTIN&#8217;S SECOND COLONY, and the Colony of Austin &#38; Williams, supplementary to an act concerning, <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>LAND WARRANTS, Discharges and Headrights, supplementary to an act authorizing the issuing of, on certain con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ditions and providing for the loss of land scrip, <ref>46</ref></p>
<p>LANDS SOLD FOR TAXES, supplementary to an act relating to, <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>MADISON COUNTY&#8212;Created, <ref>10</ref></p>
<pb n="1352" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iv" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">N</head>
<p>NEGROES&#8212;Act concerning offences committed by, Page <ref>14</ref></p>
<p>NUECES COUNTY&#8212;Erected into a separate land district, <ref>31</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">P</head>
<p>PUBLIC DEBT&#8212;To extend the provisions of an act approved March 20 1848. <ref>54</ref></p>
<p>PRESIDIO AND EL PASO COUNTIES erected, into a separate land district, <ref>31</ref></p>
<p>PUBLIC DEBT&#8212;Relating to lost certificates of, <ref>28</ref></p>
<p>PETERS&#8217; COLONY&#8212;Supplementary to an act relating to lands in, <ref>30</ref></p>
<p>PEE - EMPTION PRIVILEGES&#8212;Supplementary to an act granting, to settlers on public domain, <ref>33</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">R</head>
<p>RAILROAD COMPANIES&#8212;An act to regulate, <ref>55</ref></p>
<p>RAYMOND, JAMES H., State Treasurer, acts of, confirmed, <ref>48</ref></p>
<p>RESOLUTION, instructing our Senators and requesting our Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />&#8220; tives in Congress to call the attention of the Govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />&#8220; ment of the United States to the necessity for a fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />&#8220; ther treaty with the Republic of Mexico, <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; Concerning the Public archives of Bexar county, <ref>38</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; Relating to the volunteers called into the service by the Governor, <ref>39</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; Proposing an amendment to the Constitution, <ref>53</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S</head>
<p>SMITH, JOSEPH F.&#8212;Reinstated as an attorney and counsellor at law, <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>STARR COUNTY erected into a separate land district, <ref>31</ref></p>
<p>SAN PATRICIO COUNTY erected into a separate land district, <ref>31</ref></p>
<p>SURVEYORS, DISTRICT&#8212;Election of regulated, <ref>26</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">T</head>
<p>TREASURY DEPARTMENT and Comptroller&#8217;s Office, providing for the erection of a fire-proof building for, <ref>41</ref></p>
<pb n="1353" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="v" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>TAXES&#8212;Supplementary to an aet to restore lands sold for, and pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chased by the State, to the former owners, <ref>36</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">V</head>
<p>VOLUNTEERS, captured at Mier and Santa Fe, explanatory of an act for relief of, <ref>27</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">W</head>
<p>WASHINGTON, Mayor of town of, certain civil and criminal jurisdic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion given to. <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>WILLIAMSON COUNTY, northern boundary of, changed, <ref>53</ref></p>
<p>WEBB COUNTY erected into a separate land district, <ref>31</ref></p>
<pb n="1354" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="vi" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
</div3>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>