<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="829" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">LAWS <lb/>OF <lb/>THE THIRD LEGISLATURE <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS</head>
<byline>VOLUME III. &#8212; PART IV.</byline>
<byline>PUBLISHED BY AUTHORITY.</byline>
<byline>AUSTIN. 1850</byline>
<pb n="830" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" />
<byline>*<sub>*</sub>* For more convenient reference, the laws contained herein are severally designated by chapters and numbers in regular series.</byline>
<byline>*<sub>*</sub>* The laws of the regular session of the third. Legislature, heretofore published, are divided into two parts&#8212;the first em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bracing the general, and the second the special laws. Those of the extra or second session, are published as Part III of volume III. Those of the second extra, or third session, contained herein, are therefore published as Part IV of volume III.</byline>
<byline>*<sub>*</sub>* Those laws signed by the Governor, are designated by the word Approved &#8212; and those not signed by him, are said to be Passed.</byline>
<pb n="831" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" />
<head type="sub">VOLUME III.&#8212;PART IV. GENERAL AND SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to legalize the acts of the County Surveyors of the County of Cass.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas the County Court of the County of Cass failed or neg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lected to comply with the requirements of an act entitled &#8220;an act to give to each corporate county in this State its own County Surveyor, map and records,&#8221; approved March 20, 1848, but pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeded to order elections for the office of County Surveyor: and whereas the Surveyors so elected have proceeded to do a great deal of surveying, which, if not legalized, will operate greatly to the prejudice of the citizens of said County&#8212;Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all the acts of the said surveyors of the county of Cass, elected as aforesaid, be and the same are hereby rendered as legal, valid and binding in all respects as though the said act had been fully complied with.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the map of Cass county, drawn by A. F. Halcomb, in 1848, and now in the General Land Office, shall have the same legal force and effect as though the same had been returned to said office in accordance with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of said act of the 20th March, 1848.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>November 25, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="832" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<p>An Act accepting the Propositions made by the United States to the State of Texas, in an Act of the Congress of the United States, approved the 9th day of September, A. D. 1850, entitled &#8220;an Act proposing to the State of Texas the Establishment of her Northern, and Western Boundaries, the Relinquishment by the said State of all Territory claimed by her exterior to said Boundaries and of all her Claims upon the United States, and to establish a Territorial Government for New Mexico.&#8221;</p>
<p>Whereas, said propositions are contained in the first section of said act, in the following words, to wit: &#8220;Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled, That the following propositions shall be, and the same hereby are, offered to the State of Texas, which, when agreed to by the said State, in an act passed by the Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral Assembly, shall be binding and obligatory upon the United States and upon the said State of Texas: provided, the said agreement by the said General Assembly shall be given on or before the first day of December, eighteen hundred and fifty.</p>
<p>First: The State of Texas will agree that her boundary on the north shall commence at the point at which the meridian of one hundred degrees west from Greenwich is intersected by the parallel of thirty-six degrees thirty minutes north latitude, and shall run from said point due west to the meridian of one hundred and three degrees west from Greenwich; thence her boundary shall run due south to the thirty-second degree of north latitude; thence on the said parallel of thirty-two degrees of north latitude to the Rio Bravo del Norte; and thence with the channel of said river to the Gulf of Mexico.</p>
<p>Second: The State of Texas cedes to the United States all her claim to territory exterior to the limits and boundaries which she agrees to establish by the first article of this agreement.</p>
<p>Third: The State of Texas relinquishes all claim upon the United States for liabilty of the debts of Texas, and for compensation or indemnity for the surrender to the United States of her ships, ports, arsenals, customhouses, customhouse revenue, arms and mu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nitions of war, and public buildings with their sites, which became the property of the United States at the time of the annexation.</p>
<p>Fourth: The United States in consideration of said estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="833" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>lisliment of boundaries, cession of claim to terrritory, and relin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quishment of claims, will pay to the State of Texas, the sum of ten millions of dollars in a stock hearing five per cent, interest, and redeemable at the end of fourteen years, the interest payable half yearly at the Treasury of the United States.</p>
<p>Fifth: Immediately after the President of the United States shall have been furnished with an authentic copy of the act of the General Assembly of Texas accepting these propositions, he shall cause the stock to be issued in favor of the State of Texas, as provided for in the fourth article of this agreement: Provided also, That no more than five millions of said stock shall be issued until the creditors of the State holding bonds and other certificates of stock of Texas, for which dirties on imports were specially pledged, shall first file at the Treasury of the United States, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />leases of all claim against the United States for or on account of said bonds or certificates, in such form as shall be prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury and approved by the President of the United States: Provided, That nothing herein contained, shall be construed to impair or qualify anything contained in the third article of the second section of the joint resolution for annexing Texas to the United States, approved March first, eighteen hundred and forty-five, either as regards the number of States that may hereafter be formed out of the State of Texas, or otherwise:</p>
<p>Therefore, 1st. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the State of Texas hereby agrees to and accepts said propositions; and it is hereby declared that the State shall be bound by the terms thereof, according to their true import and meaning.</p>
<p>2d. That the Governor of this State be, and he is hereby, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quested to cause a copy of this act, authenticated under the seal of the State, to be furnished to the President of the United States by mail as early as practicable; and also a copy thereof certified in like manner, to be transmitted to each of the Senators and Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of Texas, in Congress; and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>November 25, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="834" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate Fayette Academy, in the Comity of Fay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ette.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That T. D. Fisher, G. A. Kerr, U. Gregory, John R. B. Bay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lor, J. M. Hill, J. Izzard, S. S. Hunger, P. J. Shaver, John An<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />derson, A. P. Manly, and D. Myers, be, and they are hereby incor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porated a body politic, under the name and style of the Trustees of Fayette Academy, capable of suing and being sued, of plead<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing and being impleaded, of holding property, either real, personal or mixed, of selling and conveying the same at pleasure, of having a common seal, and of changing the same at pleasure, and of do<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing and performing whatever else that may be proper and neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary to be done for the advancement of said institution, not con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trary to the constitution and laws of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this charter and privilege shall extend to said trustees and their successors in office, as long as they confine the benefit of the same to the advancement of the sciences, and the promotion of useful knowledge to the rising generation, which institution shall be accessible alike to all, without regard to opin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ions of religion or politics.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the said trustees, and their successors in office, shall have full power to enact by-laws, rules and regulations for the government of said academy as may seem to them necessary for that object, to fill all vacancies which may occur in said board of trustees, to elect such officers as may be necessary for the effi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cient discharge of their duties, and that six members shall form a quorum for the transaction of business.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>November 26, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to permanently locate the Seat of Justice of Denton County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the seat of justice of Denton county be permanent<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="835" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ly located at the residence of Alexander E. Cannon, on Hickory Creek, in said county, and that all courts which by law are to be held at the county seat, shall be held there, and that the clerks and other officers, who by law are to keep their offices at the county seat, shall remove them to said seat of justice, and said seat of justice shall be called Alton; and that this act take effect from and after the first day of February next.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>November 26, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate Rising Star Chapter, Number Nine.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the officers and members of Rising Star Chapter, Number Nine, of San Augustine county, Texas, and their success<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ors be, and they are hereby declared to be a corporate and body politic, by the name and style of the Rising Star Chapter, Number Nine, of Royal Arch Masons, and by that name they and their successors shall and may at all times hereafter be capable in law to have, receive, and retain any estate, real and personal, by gift, purchase, devise, or bequest, or such estate at their pleasure to transfer and dispose of in such manner as they may think proper: provided that said corporation shall not at any time hold, or pos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sess real estate exceeding in value the sum of twenty thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The corporation by the name and style aforesaid, shall be capable in law to sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />swer and be answered unto, defend and be defended, in all or any courts of this State, and before all or any judge, officers and per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons whatsoever, in all and singular actions, matters and things whatsoever.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The said corporation may have a common seal for their use, and the same at their will and pleasure to change, alter and make anew from time to time, as they may think best, and in gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral have and exercise all such rights, privileges and immunities as by law are incident to, and necessary for corporations of a similar character; and that this act shall take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>November 26, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="836" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to be entitled an Act to legalize a Copy of the Records in the Office of the County Surveyor of the County of Washing<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the chief justice and any two county commissioners of Washington county, are hereby authorized and required to ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />amine a copy of the records in the office of the surveyor of said county, made by D. Parker, county surveyor, and if they find the same correctly transcribed, they shall certify to the fact in the back of the book, under their hands and the seal of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said book so examined and certified to, and cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tified copies therefrom, shall be received in evidence by the courts of the country, and have all the force and effect that the original conies therefrom would have.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>November 27, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize and require the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue a Patent to William Shipp, of Sabine Coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty, for one League of Land.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and is hereby authorized and required to issue a patent to William Shipp, of Sabine county, for one league of land, upon the payment of all government dues thereon, in accordance with the provisions of law heretofore made; and that this act take effect from its pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>November 27, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="837" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the Relief of Lorenzo D. Henderson, and the Heirs of William Donoho, deceased, and Charles Ames.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue an unconditional certificate to Lorenzo D. Henderson for six hundred and forty acres of land; also, a certificate for one league and labor of land to the heirs of William Donoho, deceased; and a certificate to Charles Ames for eleven hundred and fifty-six acres of land, to be located upon any of the vacant and unappropriated land of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>November 28, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to repeal in Part, an Act entitled an Act to incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rate the Trinity Plank Road Company, approved September 4, 1850.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the proviso in the second section of said act, which reads as follows: &#8220;That said road shall be constructed above high<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />water mark,&#8221; be and the same is hereby repealed; and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>November 28, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the Relief Reuben R. Brown.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a certificate <pb n="838" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>for one league and labor of land, the same being his headright; and also, a certificate for twelve hundred and eighty acres of land, for his military services in the army of Texas, in 1835 and 1836, to Reuben R. Brown.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That said certificates may be located upon any of the vacant and unappropriated land of this State, and that the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby required, upon the return of the field notes, to issue patents to the said Brown, or his legal representatives, upon his paying the legal fees and government dues thereon.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>November 30, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act appropriating Ten Thousand Dollars, or so much as may be necessary for the Payment of the Mileage and per diem Pay of the Members and Officers of the Second Extra Session, Third Legislature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of ten thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, be appropriated for the payment of the mileage and per diem pay of the members of the second extra session of the third Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture, and the per diem of the officers attendant thereon; and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>November 30, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the second and seventh Sections of an Act en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled &#8220;an Act to organize the Supreme Court of the State of Texas,&#8221; approved the 12th of May, 1846.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the second section of the act entitled, &#8220;an act to or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganize the Supreme Court of the State of Texas, approved the <pb n="839" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>12th May 1846, be amended so as to read as follows; &#8220;Section 2nd. Be it further enacted, That the Supreme Court shall hold its sessions, once in every year at the city of Austin, in the county of Travis; once in every year at the city of Galveston, in the county of Galveston; and once in every year at the town of Ty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ler, in the county of Smith. That the causes decided in the district courts of the second, third, fourth, and eleventh judicial districts, when taken up, by appeal or otherwise, to the Supreme Court, shall be returnable to the Supreme Court sitting at the City of Austin. That the causes decided in the district courts of the first, seventh, tenth and twelfth, judicial districts, shall be returnable to the Supreme Court, holding its session in the city of Galveston. That the causes decided in the district courts of the fifth, sixth, eighth and ninth judicial districts shall be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turnable to the Supreme Court holding its session at the town of Tyler, in the county of Smith: Provided, That the parties, or their attorneys may on filing an agreement for that purpose, with the clerk of any district court, in either of the judicial districts, direct the record, accompanied by a certified copy of the agreement, to be transmitted to the Supreme Court, holding its session, either in the City of Austin, the city of Galveston, or at the town of Tyler: Provided further, That all cases where land titles are involved, taken up from the district courts to the Supreme Court, when the State of Texas is a party, shall be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turnable to the Supreme Court holding its session at the City of Austin. That the Supreme Court shall hold its session at the City of Austin on the second Monday in November in each and every year, and may continue in session six weeks, or until the business before the court is disposed of. At the city of Galves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton, on the first Monday in January, and may continue in session ten weeks, unless the business before the court is sooner disposed of. At the town of Tyler, on the first Monday in April, and may continue in session until the first day of July, unless the business before the court is sooner disposed of. That all causes remain<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing on the docket, undisposed of, when this act goes into effect, which have been decided in the counties, included in the first, seventh, tenth, and twelfth judicial districts, shall be by the Clerk of the Supreme Court, transmitted to the Supreme Court holding its sessions at the city of Galveston. That the causes remaining on the docket, undisposed of. which were decided in the fifth, sixth, eighth and ninth judicial districts, shall be trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitted to the Supreme Court holding its sessions at the town of Tyler, unless the parties or their attorneys agree that the same <pb n="840" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>may be decided by the Supreme Court holding its sessions at the City of Austin.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the seventh section of the act entitled &#8220;an act to organize the Supreme Court of the State of Texas,&#8221; approved the 12th of May, 1846, be amended so as to read as follows: &#8220;Section 7th. Be it enacted, That the Clerk of the Supreme Court shall keep an office at the City of Austin, at the city of Galveston and at the town of Tyler.&#8212;That said Clerk Shall have power to appoint deputies under him, from whom he may require bonds for the faithful discharge of the duties of his office by written appointment under the seal of the court, which shall be filed in the records of the court, to whom he shall admin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ister an oath faithfully to discharge the duties of his office, and for whose official acts he shall in all cases be responsible. That the Clerk of the Supreme Court shall appoint a deputy residing in the first, seventh, tenth, or twelfth judicial districts, who shall reside at the city of Galveston, and attend at the office of the Clerk of the Supreme Court. That he shall also appoint a deputy residing in fifth, sixth, eighth or ninth judicial districts, who shall reside at the town of Tyler, and attend at the office of the Clerk of the Su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />preme Court, and attend to, and discharge the duties of his office during the absence of the Clerk of the Supreme Court, or when the clerk is present, under his direction. That the Clerk of the Supreme Court, and his deputies shall have power to administer oaths in all cases incident to the discharge of the duties of his office.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>November 30, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorise the Clerk of the County Court of Navarro County, and the County Clerk of Tyler County, to transcribe into a hound Book, severally to be procured by them for that Purpose, all the Records and title Papers herein after men<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned, registered by the said County Clerks.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the clerk of the county court of Navarro county be required to transcribe all deeds of conveyance, and other <pb n="841" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>instruments of writing, recorded by him in his official capacity from the 17th day of August, 1846, to the thirty-first day of De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cember, 1847, in a well bound book, to be furnished by him for that purpose.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, When said record is transcribed by them, or either of them, and approved by the county court respectively, shall have the same force and effect that the original record had, both in law and equity, and shall be preserved, and considered the record in his office of such documents recorded by him in the time above sprcified.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That when said record is made in accordance with the first section of this act, and approved by the county court, the said clerks shall be paid out of any money in the county Treasury, of the counties of Navarro and Tyler re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spectively, not otherwise appropriated, ten cents for every hundred words so transcribed, to be transcribed, and this act to be in force from and after its approval by the Governor.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Brazos and Bernard Railway and Plank Road Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas. That a body politic and corporate, be, and the same are hereby created and established, under the name and style of the Brazos and Bernard Railway and Plank Road Company, with ca<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pacity to make contracts, to have succession, and a common seal, to make by-laws for its government, and in its corporate name to sue and be sued, to grant, and to receive, and generally to do and perform such acts and things as may be necessary and proper for, or incident to the fulfilment of its obligations, or maintenance of its rights under this act, and consistent with the provisions of the constitution of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said company be, and is hereby established with the right of making, owning, and maintaining, a Railway or Plank Road from the Town of Brazoria, in Brazoria county, to the Ber<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nard River.</p>
<pb n="842" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3. That E. J. Towns, William McMaster, Chesley String<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fellow, Patrick MaGreal, Charles Leonard, John Sweeney, Senr., McNeil, Lumbert Mims, Joel Spencer, Manuel McCormic, Week<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ley, Weems, S. T. Alexander, Philip Dargin, and such other per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons as they may associate with them for the purpose, are hereby appointed commissioners and invested with the right and priv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ilege of forming and organizing the said company, of obtaining subscriptions to the capital stock, and distributing the shares there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />of, and generally of taking such lawful measures to secure the ef<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fectual organization and successful operation of said company as they may deem expedient.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the capital stock of said company shall not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed one hundred and fifty thousand dollars, and said stock shall be divided into shares of fifty dollars each, and the holders of said shares shall constitute said company, and each member shall be entitled to one vote, in person or by proxy, for each and every share he may own, and such shares of stock shall be transferable alone upon the books of the company, which books shall be kept open for the inspection of any stock holder who may wish to ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />amine them at the office of the company in prpoer business hours.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the affairs and business of the said company shall he conducted and managed by a board of directors, not less than seven, nor more than eighteen, who shall be elected by the company at such time as the said commissioners may appoint, and annually thereafter: provided, that in case of failure so to elect at the stated time, the board of directors incumbent shall continue in office until there be an election, the time for which may be fixed by said board, whereof reasonable notice shall be given.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That no person shall be eligible as a director, unless he be the owner of five shares of the capital stock. The said board shall elect a President from their number, fill vacancies, appoint from their number such officers as they may deem ne<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessary, and require security for the faithful performance of their duties, also, to prescribe the time for the payment of instalments or assessments upon the stock and the amount of such instal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments or assessments, to declare the forfeiture of such stock for non-payment, and to do, or cause to be done all other lawful acts, or things which they may deem necessary or proper in conduct<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the business of said company&#8212;a majority of said board of di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rectors shall constitute a quorum for doing business. All instru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments in writing, executed by the President and Secretary, under <pb n="843" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the seal of the company, with the consent of the hoard of directors, shall be valid and binding.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That if any person shall negligently or designedly in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jure or destroy any of the fixtures, buildings, machines, materials or improvements of the company, he shall be subject to indict<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment therefor, and on conviction may be punished by fine and im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prisonment, and shall also be liable to said company in a civil ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion for damages.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That the said board shall have power to elect an agent, who shall be a member of said company, and whose name as such shall be made known to the public, and by whom the business of the corporation may be conducted under the powers given.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That said company shall have three years to commence said Railway or Road, and if it is not completed within six years from the passage of this act, this act shall be null and void at the expiration of said time.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the Benefit of certain Persons therein named.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Auditor and Comptroller be, and they are hereby required to issue duplicates of the following described certificates: One certificate number 18, 2d class, issued to Clark L. Owen, for one hundred and two dollars, dated October the 18th, 1848; one certificate number 1035, 1st class, issued to James D. Owen, for six thousand and ninety dollars, Treasury Notes, (red backs) the par value of which amounted to one thousand five hundred and twenty-two dollars and fifty cents, and dated November the 9th, 1849; one certificate issued to William P. Smith, 2d class, number 283. for sixty dollars, and dated November the 12th, 1849.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Comptroller be, and he is hereby required to <pb n="844" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>issue a duplicate of Treasury Warrant, number 3,335, issued to William J. Bussell, on the sixth day of September, 1850, for forty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />three dollars and twenty cents.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Settlers in Peters&#8217; Colony to intervene in Suit, or Suits, in reference to any Matters connected with said Colony Contracts, where they have an Interest.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That any person or persons to whom certificates have been been, or may hereafter be issued by the commissioner, appointed under the provisions of an act, approved on the twenty-first day of January, 1850, entitled &#8220;an act to secure to all actual settlers within the limits of the colony granted to Peters and others, com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />monly known as Peters&#8217; Colony, the land to which they are entitled as colonists;&#8221; shall have the right to intervene, and make them<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />selves parties to any suit, or suits, heretofore instituted, or that may hereafter be instituted, either by the contractors of said col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ony, their trustees, assigns, or legal representatives, or the State, in reference to the said colony contracts, or any interest connected with, or growing out of said contracts, and that the rights of any of said colonists, or persons to whom certificates have been issued as aforesaid, so intervening, shall be considered and adjusted, if the same are in any manner connected with the subject matter of the suit, and settled with the least delay compatible with the rights of the other parties, plaintiff and defendant.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. And be it further enacted, That in any suit, or suits, such as are mentioned in the first section of this act, if it can be ascertained that the rights of the parties intervening, can be ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />justed and determined, without reference to the final question of right as between the original parties to the action, the court shall proceed to act upon the rights of said interveners, without await<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the final hearing of the cause.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. And be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="845" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act requiring the Commissioners appointed by an Act entitled &#8220;An Act creating the County of Hunt,&#8221; approved, April 11th, 1846, to deliver up certain Documents and Moneys therein men<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioners appointed to locate the County Seat of Hunt County, by the aboft recited act, approved April 14th, 1846, be, and they are hereby required to deliver up to the chief justice and county commissioners of said county, at the February term of the County Court, in the year 1851, or as soon thereafter as practicable, all the records,, papers, documents and moneys in their hands relative to lots in the town of Greenville, in Hunc eouytv.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That said chief justice, county<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />commissioners, and Bounty clerk of said county of Hunt, or their successors in office, shall proceed to sell the remaining lots in said town of Greenville, and to do and perform whatever may he necessary in finally settling the outstanding business of said town of Greenville, for which services the said chief justice, county commissioners and county clerk, shall be entitled to the same fees as in other similar cases are established by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the chief justice shall have power to institute suit on all notes heretofore drawn and payable to said commissioners for lots in said town of Greenville, as fully as though such notes had been executed to him; and that this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an Act entitled an Act to Incorporate the City of New Braunfels.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the seventh section of the before recited act, shall henceforth be as follows: That a majority of the whole number of the city council shall form a quorum, with power to act, and <pb n="846" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>that no tax shall be levied by any meeting of the city council, which consists of less than a majority of the whole number elected.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That taxes heretofore levied at any meeting of the city council of the City of New Braunfels, at which a majority of the elected members of the city council were present, are, and shall be binding and valid.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted. That the seventh section of the act to which this is amendatory, is hereby repealed; and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the Relief of John Beeman, John S. Beeman and James J. Beeman.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office of this State be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to the following named persons, patents to the following described sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veys of land, made in the county of Dallas, and State aforesaid, upon the filing of the field-notes of said surveys, together with the certificates upon which said surveys were made, to wit: Survey number one, letter A, of three hundred and twenty acres of land, to John Beeman; survey number four, letter A, of three hundred and twenty acres of land, to John Beeman; survey number two, letter A, of three hundred and twenty acres of land, to John Bee<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man; survey number six, letter B, of three hundred and twenty acres of land, to John Beeman; survey number eight, letter A, of three hundred and twenty acres of land, to John Beeman, assignee of Henry C. Long; survey number five, letter A, of six hundred and forty acres of land, to James J. Beeman; survey number three, letter A, of three hundred and twenty acres of land, to John S. Beeman, and survey number six, letter A, of three hundred and twenty acres of land, to John S. Beeman.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="847" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the Relief of Laanner Ward.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized to issue a certificate to Laanner Ward, for one league and one labor of land, as a headright to which said Laanner Ward is entitled, by virtue of her emigration to the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public of Texas with her family, previous to the first day of March, A. D., 1836.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said certificate may be located, surveyed and pat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ented, according to the laws regulating first class claims for head<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rights to lands; and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Incorporate the Shelby University.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Robert G. Cartright, Nicholas H. Darnell, Archibald W. O. Hicks, William S. Smith, J. D. Norton, Amon Lewellen, Leonard Straw, John L. Bridges, J. Grady, M. Sinclair, H. Cozart, Robert Turner, J. T. Booth, Robert McWilliams, James Truit, Harrison Davis, Nathan Davis, J. R. R. Graves, A. M. Truit, A. McLemore, Thomas Carroll, W. A. Holland, J. J. Straw, J. J. Cravens, M. K. Withers, W. P. Landrum, James Baird, William Hall, C. T. Hilliard, Samuel Farrer, and their associates, are hereby constituted a body politic and corporate, under the name and style of the Trustees of the Shelby University, to be located in the town of Shelbyville, in Shelby county, capable of suing and being sued, pleading and being impleaded, of holding property real, personal and mixed at pleasure, and of doing and performing all things whatsoever that they may deem beneficial to said institution not contrary to the constitution and laws of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this charter and privilege shall extend to each individual who may hereafter subscribe the sum of fifty dollars to said institution.</p>
<pb n="848" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the sum of fifty dollars shall constitute a share holder in said institution, for which a receipt shall be issued by the Treasurer, who may be elected by the share holders, and which shall be transferable by said individual, and the name of the person transferring his share, shall be erased and the name of the purchaser inserted in the record of the Secretary of said institution, when the purchaser of said share shall be enti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tled to all privileges, rights, and immunities of other members.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That there shall be twelve Trus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tees of said institution elected annually by the shareholders of said institution, at such time as they may designate by a majority of the shareholders, each share of fifty dollars entitling the holder to one vote, and the officers of the same shall consist in a President, a Secretary and a Treasurer: Provided, That if from any cause any of said officers and Trustees shall not be elected at the annual meeting, that the old Trustees shall perform their functions until their successors shall be elected, which may be done in that case at any time that the said Trustees may elect, after having given notice to the share-holders, and it shall be competent for said board to fill vacancies at any time after they occur.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the President of the board shall have power to call a special meeting of the Trustees, when he may deem it necessary, and a majority of said board shall constitute a quorum to transact business, and a majority of the Trustees shall have power to adopt any resolution or measure, and in case the President, or any other officer shall be absent, the vacancy or vacancies shall be filled for the time being by the Trustees present from their own number.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the board of Trustees, or a majority of them according to section fifth of this act, shall have power to transact all business properly belonging to corporate bod<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ies, and within the purview of this act of incorporation, to pass all bye-laws for the regulation of this institution, and for the gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment of the board, not inconsistent with the laws of the State and provisions of this act; but they shall not have power to alien<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ate the property belonging to the corporation, unless by the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sent of a majority of the share-holders.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That said institution shall be forever free from the control of any particular denomination of <pb n="849" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Christians or sectarian doctrines, and shall be open for the use and benefit of all, as an institution of learning.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution refunding to Major W. S. Henry the Fine im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed upon him by Sentence of a Court Martial in the 9th Mili<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary Department of the United States Army.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, it appears that Major W. S. Henry, of the United States army, was required by a sentence of a Court Martial, convened in the 9th Military Department, to pay a fine of ten dollars for the courtesies extended by him to R. S. Neighbors, Commissioner of the State of Texas while in the exercise of his official duties. Therefore,</p>
<p>Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the thanks of the State are due, and are hereby tendered to Major W. S. Henry, for his attention and courtesy to said commissioner, and that the Treasurer is duly authorized and required to refund and pay to Major W. S. Henry the fine imposed upon him by the sen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tence of said Court.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That the Secretary of State be required to furnish a copy of this joint resolution on parchment, under the Great Seal of the State, to said W. S. Henry.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to locate the Seat of Justice of Kaufman County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the chief justice of Kaufman county be, and he is hereby required to hold an election for the county seat of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the chief justice of said <pb n="850" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>county, so soon as he shall receive a certified copy of this act, shall put in nomination for said county seat, the donation known by the name of Kingsborough, and the donation at the geograph<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ical centre of said county, and none others; he shall give public notice of the time of holding the election, in writing, posted up at the different precincts in said county, at least ten days before the day of election.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the propositions submitted as inducements, in favor of the place which may be elected, shall be in the shape of penal bonds, and may be collected at the suit of said chief justice, or his successors in office, in the district court, for the use of said county, and the proceeds applied to the erection of public buildings for said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the election for said county seat, shall be conducted in conformity with the existing laws regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lating elections, and the returns made in ten days to the chief jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stice of said county, who shall declare the place receiving the high<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />est number of votes, to be the legal seat of justice of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That John S. Damron, J. L. Aus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tin, James Love, Sterling R. Barns and J. W. Terrell shall be, and they are hereby appointed commissioners to lay out, sell and trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fer lots, and to superintend the carrying out such propositions as may have been made in favor of the location selected, and report to the chief justice whether or not the bond, or bonds, containing propositions in favor of the place selected, have been strictly com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plied with, by the makers and obligors thereof.</p>
<p>Sec 6. Be it further enacted, That the Secretary of State be, and he is hereby required to transmit by mail, to the chief justice of Kaufman county, a certified copy of this act, under the seal of the State, within ten days after the adjournment of the present called session of the Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec 7. Be it further enacted, That all laws and parts of laws conflicting with the provisions of this act be, and the same are hereby repealed; and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="851" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the Relief of Stephen J. Sparks, Assignee of Samuel W. Wilds.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a patent to Stephen J. Sparks, assignee of Samuel W. Wilds, upon certificate number one hundred and eighty-four, for six hundred and forty acres of land, issued by the board of land commissioners of Nacogdoches county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That an act for the relief of Wil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liam C. Sparks, assignee of Samuel W. Willis, approved February 1st, 1850, be, and the same is hereby repealed; and that this act be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the Relief of John Edmonds.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a certificate for one league and labor of land to John Edmonds, which may be located on any vacant and unappropriated public land in the State of Texas, and on the return of the field notes, and payment of gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment dues, a patent or patents, shall issue according to law in such cases provided, and this act shall take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the Relief of John McLennan, Jr.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a certificate for <pb n="852" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>one league of land to John McLenan, jr., which may be located on any of the vacant and unappropriated public domain in the State of Texas, and on the return of [the] field notes and payment of government dues, patents to issue as in other cases provided for by law; and this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing the Governor to employ Counsel in the Su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />preme Court of the State, in Cases where the present Attorney General has been employed.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor be, and he is hereby required to appoint some suitable person to represent the State in all cases where the present Attorney General has been employed adversely.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the Relief of Mary Alexander.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Mary Alexander a certificate for twelve hundred and eighty acres of land, the same being her headrisht.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That said certificate may be located on any vacant and unappropriated land in this State, and that the said Commissioner be, and he is hereby required upon the return of the field notes, to issue a patent thereon, upon the payment of the fees and government dues, according to the requirements of law; and that this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="853" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to require the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue Patents for Lands therein named.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue patents for six hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and forty acres of land, embraced in survey number 16, in sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion number 15, in Bexar land district, made by virtue of headright certificate number 444, second class, issued to Andrew Flores, by the board of land commissioners of Bexar county; also for six hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and forty acres of land embraced in survey number 38, in sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion number 15, in Bexar land district, made by virtue of headright certificate number 169, issued to Simon Prado, by the board of land commissioners of Bexar county; also, for one league and one labor of land embraced in survey num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber &#8212;, in section number 15, in Bexar land district, made by virtue of a judgement rendered by the district court of Bexar county, at the fall term of said court, A. 1)., 1847, in favor of Elizano Pizana; also, for one league and one labor of land embraced in survey number-, in section number 15, in Bexar land district, made by virtue of certificate number 771&#8212;870, issued by the Commissioner of the General Land Office, in favor of Eaymond Sunegas; also, for one third of a league of land, em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />braced in survey number&#8212;, in section number &#8212;, in Bexar land district, made by virtue of certificate number 1034, second class, issued to Gabrel Long, deceased, by administration, by the board of land commissioners of Harrisburgh county; also, for six hundred and forty acres of land, embraced in survey number&#8212;, in section number 15, in Bexar district, made by virtue of headright certificate number 116, issued to James W. Mchols by the board of land com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners of Gonzales county; also, for one league and labor of land, embraced in surveys numbers 34 and 35, in section number 13, in Bexar land district, made by virtue of certificate number &#8212;-, issued to John McMullen as assignee of Maria Rodrigues, by the board of land commissioners of Bexar county; the State hereby relinquishing all its right, title and interest in and to the lands embraced in said surveys to said grantees of said certificates and judgments, their heirs and assigns; provided said relinquishments and patents shall not operate to the prejudice of any existing in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dividual rights.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act to take effet and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="854" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Executive Board of Managers of the Ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonic Female Institue at Marshall, Harrison county, to confer Degrees, and for other Purposes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Executive Board of Managers of [the] Masonic Female institute, shall have full power and authority by the faculty of instruction, to grant and confer upon any students of said In<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute, by them deemed worthy such degrees, in the arts, sciences, as are usually granted and conferred in collegiate institutions; also, to give diplomas, signed by them and sealed with the common seal of the said institute, to authenticate and perpetuate the memory of such graduations.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the Executive Board of Man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />agers shall have a common seal, with such device as they choose, with liberty to alter the same at pleasure.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the first section of an Act entitled an Act to in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corporate the Galveston and Brazos Navigation Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of the act entitled &#8220;an act to incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rate the Galveston and Brazos Navigation Company,&#8221; be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 2. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That there shall be established a company under the name and style of the Galveston and Brazos Navigation Company, with a capital stock of three hundred thousand dollars, with the privi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lege of increasing the same to six hundred thousand dollars, to be divided into shares of ten dollars each, for the purpose of cut<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ting a canal from Sabine Bay, or Lake, on the waters thereof to Galveston Bay, on the waters thereof; also, from San Luis, or West Galveston Bay, to the waters of the Brazos River; and also, with the privilege of connecting by canal, the waters of the <pb n="855" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Brazos River with the San Bernard, Peach Creek [and] Colorado River: Provided, however, said canal shall not commence or termi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nate at the Brazos River, nor cross the said stream at a point more than five miles from its mouth, without the consent of the Brazos and Galveston Canal Conrpanv.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue patents to the Heirs of Simon Gillam and the heirs of John Smith.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Simon Gillain and John Smith, having emigrated to the Republic of Texas, under the law donating lands to emigrants, &#38;c., and having obtained conditional certificates as required, &#38;c., and having died in said Republic before obtaining unconditional certificates; Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized to issue patents to the heirs of Simon Gil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lam, and John Smith, upon the conditional certificates, without the production of the unconditional certificates; Provided, the sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veys have been made in accordance with the laws heretofore passed, and in operation at this time, so far as relates to Surveying, record<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, &#38;c.; and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the Relief of Stockely D. Shoate.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That upon the filing in the General Land Office, by Stocke<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ly D. Shoate, or his agent, of the field notes of a survey for six hundred and forty acres of land, appearing on the map of Leon county in the name of J. Chambers, and upon the depository of the bond of transfer made by said Chambers to Thomas C. <pb n="856" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Swalem, attested by Charles Reagan and Charles Gayson, dated September 7th, 1847, for said headright of six hundred and forty acres, it shall thereupon be the duty of the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue letters patent for said tract to said Stockely D. Shoate, as assignee of said Chambers, upon said Shoate paying the customary fee as provided by law in such cases; and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Town of Shelbyville in Shelby County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the citizens of the town of Shelbyville in Shelby county, be, and they are hereby declared a body politic and cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate, under the name and style of the Corporation of the town of Shelbyville, and by that name shall have power to sue, and be sued, plead and be impleaded, and to hold and dispose of real and personal property; Provided, such real property is situated within the limits of said, corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the citizens of said corporation to elect a Mayor, eight Aldermen, a Collector and a Constable; and a Treasurer, and Secretary shall be selected by said Aldermen from their own body; the Treasurer and Collector being required to give bond, with security, to be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved by the presiding officer for the faithful performance of their duties, and to make reports when required by the Mayor or board of Aldermen; and the Mayor shall have power when neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary, to suppress riots and disturbances, and to call out the citizens of said corporation for the purpose of restoring order.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, Ihat the first election shall be held under the direction of the chief justice of said county, after haidng given ten days notice thereof, and annually afterwards, under the direction of the Mayor, at least ten days before the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />piration of his term of office, and that in case of death or resigna<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, the vacancy, or vacancies shall be filled by new elections, to be ordered by the Mayor, and in case the office of Mayor shall be vacant, then the Aldermen shall elect one of their own body to act as Mayor until the next annual election.</p>
<pb n="857" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="29" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That no person shall be eligible to any office under the provisions of this charter, who is not a citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zen of this State, and a resident within the limits of the incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration; nor shall any person have a right to a vote for officers, who is not a citizen and resides within its limits.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the Mayor and board of Aldermen of said corporation, shall have power to pass such rules and ordinances as may be necessary for the regulation of the police, and the preservation of order within the corporation limits; to levy taxes for the removal of nuisances and keeping the streets in good order, and to prescribe penalties for the violation of the ordinances and by-laws of the corporation: Provided, that in no case such nenalties shall exceed one hundred dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the limits of said corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion shall extend one-half mile in every direction from the court<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />house on the public square of said town of Shelbyville, in the cen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tre of said corporation limits.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That the Mayor with, [a] majority of said Aldermen, shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, and shall enact and enforce such rules and regulations as they may deem necessary for the government of said corporation: Provided, the same do not conflict with the constitution and laws of this State.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the Relief of Berry Merchant.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby required and authorized to issue to Berry Merchant a certificate for one-third of a league of land, which may be located as now provided by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="858" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="30" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the Relief of James Chesher, Sen&#8217;r.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized to issue a patent or patents to James Ches<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />her, senior, under and in virtue of his headright certificate, num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber one hundred and eighty-one, issued to him by the Board of Land Commissioners, in and for the county of Jasper, the said Chesher having complied with the requisitions annexed to the ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proval of his said certificates.</p>
<p>Sec. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act amendatory of &#8220;an Act to create the County of Freestone.&#8220;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of the above recited act read as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows: Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, that all that territory comprised within the following limits, to wit: beginning at the North East corner of Leon county; thence run<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ning with the North West boundary of said county, twenty-nine miles; thence North 30 degrees West, to the South East boundary of Navarro county; thence with the same North 6 degrees East to the Trinity river; thence down the channel of the same to the place of beginning, shall be constituted into a new county, and be called Freestone.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the following addition be made to said act, to wit: that it shall be the duty of the chief justice of Limestone county to order an election for county offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers in said county of Freestone, on the first Monday in January, 1851, and the vote polled in Freestone county, shall [be] returned to the chief justice of Limestone county, who shall issue certificates of election to the officers elect of Freestone county, <pb n="859" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="31" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and said officers, when so elected and qualified according to law, shall enter upon the discharge of their several duties.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the commissioners ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed in the 2d section of the above recited act, shall be allowed and paid out of the county treasury of Freestone county, the sum of one dollar per day each, for every day they may be necessarily employed in the discharge of the duties therein assigned them; that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>November 30, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the Relief of John C. Walling.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That John C: Walling is hereby authorized to sell and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vey his San Jacinto donation claim for six hundred and forty acres of land, all laws to the contrary notwithstanding; and that this joint resolution be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to &#8220;an Act to secure to the German Emi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gration Company, and their Colonists, the Lands to which they are entitled, and to adjust the liabilities of said Company,&#8221; ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved January 21, 1850.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commisioner appointed by virtue of the above re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cited act, be authorized to cancel such certificates as may have been issued erroneously by the former Commissioner, and issue other certificates in lieu thereof, and that the certificate of the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner of the General Land Office, of certificates erroneously issued, shall be sufficient evidence to authorize the canceling of the same.</p>
<pb n="860" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="32" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That persons who are entitled to receive certificates for lands as emigrated under the above recited act, where the survey made by the German Emigration Company shall have been exhausted, may proceed to locate their certificates on any unappropriated territory in said colony, and the surveys made under said certificates, shall be in conformity with the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structions from the district surveyor, so as to secure to the State each alternate section so surveyed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That patents shall be issued under the provisions of this act, and the act to which this is a supple<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, within said colony.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it farther enacted, That this act shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XL.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act concerning the Book or Register of Land Certificates, is<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sued for the County of Harris, which was at one time mislaid, but the Book has subsequently been found, and identified as genuine and unaltered.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the clerk of the county court of Harris he, and he, is hereby authorized and required to transmit to the Commissioner of the General Land Office, the book or register of land certificates issued by the board of land commissioners for the county of Har<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ris, usually known as the lost book; that the said clerk shall annex to said book a certificate, under the seal of the county court, that the book transmitted is the lost book, and known and recognized in his office as a genuine record of his office.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, on the receipt of said hook, shall cause the same to be filed as one of the hooks or archives of his office; and he is hereby authorised to issue patents on the certificates mentioned and described as issued in said hook, in all cases when the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land Office shall he satisfied, from the evidence contained in said hook, that the several certificates are genuine and the parties entitled.</p>
<pb n="861" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="33" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That if any certificate men<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned or described in said book has been obtained by fraud or misrepresentation, the patents that may be issued thereon, shall be void, as well as every survey made under the same.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the Belief of Lewis Monroe Mays, a Minor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Lewis Monroe Mays, a miner, and a married man, be, and he is hereby declared to be, entitled to all the rights, privi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />leges, liabilities and immunities, that he would upon arriving at the age of majority.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the safe and profitable Investment of the School Fund.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller is hereby authorised and empowered to issue in the name of the State, State bonds, signed by the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor and countersigned by the Comptroller, to the amount of thirty-six thousand dollars, bearing five per cent, interest from date of issue.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said bonds shall be deposited in the Treasury of the State, and remain as a charge against the State, passed to the credit of the free common school fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the Treasurer of the State is hereby authorised and instructed to disburse the aforesaid amount of thirty-six thousand dollars out of the school fund in his charge, to meet the current expenses of the State, as provided for by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="862" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="34" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the Relief of Peter Lopez and Henry Tierwester.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Landoffiee be, and he is hereby authorised and required to issue to Peter Lopez a cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate for nine hundred and sixty acres of bounty land, for his services in the army of Texas in the years 1835 and 1836.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the said Commissioner be and he is hereby re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to issue to Peter Lopez a certificate for six hundred and forty acres of land, on account of his participation in the attack on San Antonio in 1835, and for his participation in the battle of San Jacinto on the 21st of April, 1836; and that said certificates, when issued, may be located upon any public and unappropriated domain, of this State; and upon the return of the same to the Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral Landoffiee, with the field-notes of survey, the Commissioner of the General Land Office is hereby required to issue patents thereon.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the Commissioner of the General Landoffice he also required to issue to Henry Tierwester a certificate for two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds of a league and labor of land.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act take [effect] and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making Appropriations.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the following sums be, and the [same] are hereby appropriated for the purposes named, viz: for copying and print<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the laws and journals of the second extra session of the Third Legislature, convened November 18, 1850, twelve hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars; for distributing the same, two hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For balance due for copying and printing laws and journals of second [first] extra session, third Legislature, fifty-three dollars and ninety cents.</p>
<p>For distributing Hartley&#8217;s Digest and Reports of Supreme Court, five hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For contingent expenses of second extra session of third legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature, a sufficient amount of unexpended balance of appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="863" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="35" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>priation for expenses of second [first] extra session is hereby trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred and appropriated.</p>
<p>For the payment of special messengers, who are employed to circulate the proclamation of the Governor, recommending an elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion on the question of selling a portion of our northwestern terri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tory, four dollars per day each, for the time they were so employed, to be paid upon a proper showing made to the Comptroller.</p>
<p>For reimbursing Mr. Wiley Marshall, one of said special mes<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sengers, such amount as may be shown to the satisfaction of the Comptroller to have been paid by said Marshall, to agents em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ployed by him to aid in distributing the Governor&#8217;s proclamation as above.</p>
<p>For payment to said Wiley Marshall for a horse lost in said ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vice, eighty-five dollars.</p>
<p>For printing laws ot second session of the third legislature in Spanish, two hundred dollars, or as much thereof as may be neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary.</p>
<p>For amount due De Cordova &#38; Co. for printing Governor&#8217;s pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clamation, in hand-bill form, in English and German, submitting the ten million proposition to the people, one hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For amount due De Cordova &#38; Co. for publishing report of Au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ditor and Comptroller, in relation to public debt, in Southwestern American, twenty dollars.</p>
<p>For amount due De Cordova &#38; Co. for publishing list of Notaries Public in accordance with act of 30th April, 1846, thirty-seven dollars.</p>
<p>For amount due De Cordoya &#38; Co. for publishing act for the liquidation of the public debt, sixty dollars.</p>
<p>For amount paid by Wm. F. Evans for copies of map of Fisher&#8217;s and Miller&#8217;s colony, for public use, sixty dollars, to be paid to order of said Evans.</p>
<p>Also, two hundred dollars, or so much thereof as may be suffi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cient, to defray the contingent expenses of the branches of the Su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />preme Court, at Galveston and Tyler, to he drawn hy the Chief Justice of said court.</p>
<p>Also, for pay of A. J. Hamilton, two hundred and fifty dollars; John E. Cravens, one hundred and fifty dollars, and J. M. Ardrey one hundred and fifty dollars for services as Special Judges of the Supreme Court.</p>
<p>For pay of Benton &#38; Price, for publishing proclamation of the Governor, ninety-six dollars.</p>
<pb n="864" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="36" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>For pay of George Robinson, for printing proclamation of Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor, in Huntsville Item, twenty-five dollars.</p>
<p>For pay of Benton &#38; Price, for publishing proclamation of Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor, and the escape of Cheshire from jail, twenty dollars.</p>
<p>For compensation to Logan &#38; Sterne, for publishing Governor&#8217;s proclamation, twenty-five dollars.</p>
<p>For compensation to Jasper Starr, editor of the Wonder, for pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lishing the proclamation of the Governor, on the Pearce proposi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, thirty-five dollars.</p>
<p>For compensation to Brown &#38; Tarbox for conveying the remains of Samuel H. Walker, from Houston to La Grange, one hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For compensation to W. H. Cushney, for publishing Governor&#8217;s proclamation, fortyfour dollars.</p>
<p>For compensation to editor of the Dallas Herald, for publishing the Governor&#8217;s proclamation, forty-four dollars.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 3, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the Relief of Alanson Furgerson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby, required to issue to Alanson Furgerson a certificate for one league and one labor of land, it being the quanity of land to which he is entitled by virtue of his emigration to the country and his marrying within the time prescribed by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The said certificate may fie located and surveyed, and patented in accordance with existing laws governing the same character of claims, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 3, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Zachariah N. Morrell.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a certificate <pb n="865" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="37" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>for one league and labor of land to Zachariah N. Morrell, which may be located on any of the vacant and unappropriated land in this State; and on the return of field-notes, and payment of gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment dues, patents shall issue, as in other cases provided for by law, and that this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 3, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the heirs of Martin W. B. Armstrong.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas. That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby required to issue a certificate for one-third of a league of land to the heirs of Martin W. B. Armstrong, it being the amount to which he was entitled as a headlight, by virtue of his emigration to Texas as a colonist.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said certificate may be located, surveyed, and pat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ented, according to the laws regulating first class claims; and this<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />act take effect and he in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 3, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of William A. Burns.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a certificate for one league and labor of land, the same being his headright, to William A. Burns.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the said certificate may be located upon any of the vacant and unappropriated land of this State, and that the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby required, upon the return of the field-notes, to issue a patent to said William A. Burns upon his paying the same fees and government dues required of colonists who emigrated pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vious to the second day of May, 1835, according to the require<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments of law.</p>
<pb n="866" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="38" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3 Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 3, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Benjamin Burke, of Tyler County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Adjutant General be, and be is hereby requested to issue to Benjamin Burke, of Tyler County, a bounty warrant for three hundred and twenty acres of land, for serving a three months&#8217; tour in the army of Texas, in the year 1836.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That said certificate shall be lo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cated, surveyed, and patented, according to the laws governing claims of a similar character, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 3, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER L.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Ad Act for the relief of David B. Kent, Bosmor Kent, Mary Ann Bias, and Lonisa Billings, heirs of Andrew Kent, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That David B. Kent, Bosmor Kent, Mary Ann Bias, wife of William Bias, and Louisa Billings, wife of James Billings, chil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dren of Andrew Kent, deceased, are hereby made and constituted the legal heirs of Joseph Kent, deceased, late of De Witt county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the estate of the said Joseph Kent, deceased, shall descend and pass, in parcenary, to the said David B. Kent, Bosmor Kent, Mary Ann Bias, and Louisa Billings, in the same manner as though they were the legitimate children of the said Joseph Kent, deceased.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the administrator of the estate of Joseph Kent, deceased, is hereby authorized and required to deliver over to the said David B. Kent, Bosmor Kent, Mary Ann Bias, and Louisa Billings, the residue of said estate, after the payment of the debts of the same, in such manner and form <pb n="867" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="39" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>as the law requires inheritances to be delivered to legal heirs in other cases of intestacy.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the provisions of this act shall not be construed to divest any right which any other person may have by law to inherit said estate in any manner whatever.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 3, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Martha McMillan.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office he, and he is hereby authorized and required, to issue a certificate to Martha McMillan, for six hundred and forty acres of land, it being the quantity of land to which she is entitled by virtue of her emigration to Texas, which certificate may be located on any of the public and unappropriated domain of the State, in con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formity with the laws regulating third class claims, and that this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 3, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to repeal an act entitled, &#8220;An act to reserve one of the Pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic Buildings in the city of Austin, for the Supreme Court.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the above-recited act, approved January 1, 1848, be, and the same is hereby repealed; and that the house reserved by said act for the use of the Supreme Court be subject to the disposi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the Comptroller of Public Accounts, in the same manner as other public buildings in the city of Austin, and that this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 3, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="868" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="40" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of Robert Shaw, assignee [of] Wil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liam Morrow.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioner of Mercer&#8217;s colony be, and he is hereby required to issue to Robert Shaw, assignee of William Mor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />row, a colony certificate for six hundred and forty acres of land, which shall be located and patented according to &#8220;An act for the relief of the citizens of Mercer&#8217;s colony,&#8221; approved February 2, 1850, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 3, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to regulate the pay of Volunteers in the service of Texas, in the year 1842.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the volunteers who served in the year 1842, in the expedition of General Burlerson, and those who served under Colonel Clark L. Owen, and those who served under said Owen and General James Davis, at Corpus Christi and Lepanticlan, shall receive the same compensation for their term of service, and upon the same terms and conditions, so far as they are applicable, as have been granted by previous enactments to the volunteers cap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tured at Mier and at Santa F&#233;.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 3, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act better to regulate the Election of Judges of the Supreme Court.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That in the election of Judges of the Supreme Court, there shall be elected one Chief Justice and two Associates, to hold their offices under, and in accordance with the provisions of the constitution of the State: provided, that should there be a <pb n="869" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="41" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>tie between two or more persons for the office of Chief Justice, or between three or more persons for Associate Justices, the Governor shall immediately order a new election, giving thirty days notice, to fill the places left vacant by such tie.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That it shall be the duty of the Governor whenever a vacancy shall occur in the office of chief Justice, or Associate Judges, to order an election for such vacancy or vacancies, which election, when so ordered, shall be held in accordance with the laws regulating elections; and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 3, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Peter Gallagher and the legal representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives of Archibald Fitzgerald and Thompson Robinson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller and Auditor of Public Accounts, are hereby authorized and required to audit and allow to Peter Gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lagher, and to the legal representatives of Archibald Fitzgerald and Thompson Robinson, Santa F&#233; prisoners, the same pay allowed by law to volunteers mustered into the service of Texas and cap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tured at Santa Fe, and that a certificate for the amount of said pay, be issued to the said Peter Gallagher, and to the legal repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the said Archibald Fitzgerald and Thompson Robin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from ana after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 3, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to incorporate the Waco Male and Female Academy in the County of McLennan.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Darius Gregg, John M. Stephens, George B. Erath, Shapley P. Ross, William B. Walker, John T. Eubanks, John S. Blair, and their associates and successors, are hereby created a body corporate in deed and in law, in the name and style of the Waco Male and Female Academy, and by that name may have <pb n="870" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="42" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>perpetual succession, and be capable in law of bolding, by purchase or donation, property both real and personal, in fee for years, so long as they confine their operations to the promotion of educa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, provided, that the capital stock shall not exceed fifty thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted that hooks shall be open to receive subscriptions in sums not less than five dollars, and any person who shall subscribe the sum of five dollars, shall be considered a portion or stockholder of said Academy, may have the right to sell or transfer their stock at pleasure, and shall have the privilege of voting in person or by proxy in all elections necessary for the gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment of said Academy, provided, no one stockholder shall own more than twenty shares, and provided, also, that no teacher in said Academy shall be a stockholder in the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The stockholders may have the power to disfranchise any of their members by a vote of two thirds, provided, they pay to such stockholder the amount ef his subscription.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The stockholders shall elect from their number not less than five nor more than seven trustees, who shall hold their office as such for the term of one year, whose duty it shall be to procure teachers, regulate prices of tuition, and govern generally the oper<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ations of the institution, and shall have power to elect from their number a President, Secretary, and Treasurer, who shall hold their offices for the term for which the trustees are elected.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The trustees shall have power to make such by-laws as they deem necessary for their own government and the manage<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the Institution, provided, they do not conflict with the constitution and laws of the State, and may alter and amend them at pleasure, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 3, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the sixth Section of an Act entitled &#8220;An Act con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cerning Slaves,&#8221; approved 5th February, 1840.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sixth section of an act entitled &#8220;an act con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cerning slaves,&#8221; approved 5th February, 1840, be amended so as to read as follows: Section 6. Be it further enacted, That any <pb n="871" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="43" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>slave who may be found beyond and away from the premises of his owner, overseer or employer, on Sunday, or after the hour of ten o&#8217;clock, P. M., or any other day, without a written permit from his master, mistress, overseer, or employer, or with such written per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mit, at places other than are described in said permit, or away from the route usually travelled in going to and returning from the places to which the permit extends, the said negro-slave shall be liable to be taken up by any patrol, justice of the peace, or any in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dividual, and in case said slave is taken up by the patrol, the said patrol shall inflict on said slave as a punishment any number of lashes, at his discretion, not exceeding ten; should the patrol, or any other individual, taking up a slave under the circumstances above specified, deem that more than ten lashes should be inflicted, under the circumstances, he shall take the slave before some jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tice of the peace, who on notice to the master, if residing within ten miles, and having the facts proved before him, shall adjudge the number of stripes which shall be inflicted, not exceeding nine, and order their infliction; should the master be unknown, or, if known, should he reside at a greater distance from the place where the said justice of the peace resides than it is to the nearest county jail, the said justice shall commit the slave to the said county jail, and cause notice thereof to be given in writing to [the] master, over<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />seer, or employer, if known, the master, overseer, or employer, to be entitled to the possession of the negro-slave, on payment of all reasonable costs and charges not exceeding ten dollars; that it shall not be lawful for any slave to own firearms of any description; and every owner, overseer, or employer, who shall, knowingly, permit any slave owned by him, under his control, or in his employment, to carry firearms of any description, or other deadly weapons, at other places than on the premises of the owner, overseer, or em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ployer, shall be fined not less than twenty-five dollars, nor more than one hundred dollars, and all costs, the firearms to be forfeit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed to the use of the county, and the negro to receive not less than thirty-nine nor more than fifty lashes, to be adjudged by any dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict court or justice of the peace before whom, the charges may be preferred; that any slave found with any articles of trade or traffic in his possession offering the same for sale without a writ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ten permit to sell, describing the articles, shall be adjudged by any justice of the peace before whom he may be taken to receive not more than thirty-nine lashes, at the discretion of the justice of the peace, and the articles of trade and traffic shall be forfeited and sold to pay the costs, the excess to be paid into the county treasury: provided, that the articles taken from the possession of <pb n="872" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="44" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the slave may be claimed at any time within six months by the owner thereof making proof of ownership; that any slave attempt<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing to take the life of any white person or slave by means of poison or otherwise, shall be delivered over to the civil authority by the owner, overseer, or employer, if the slave is within their power or control, and every owner, overseer or employer who shall refuse to so deliver such slave, or send off, assist or con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nive at the escape of such slave, he shall be fined not less than one hundred nor more than five hundred dollars, in addition to the penalties imposed on accessories before or after the fact: pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that nothing herein contained shall be so construed as to in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terfere with or in anywise affect the right of incorporated towns and cities in this State from making and enforcing their own police regulations, except so far as relates to the carrying of firearms.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 3, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the Heirs or Legal Representatives of John W. R. Tildon, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to issue an unconditional headright certificate for one third of a league of land to the heirs or legal representatives of John W. R. Tildon, deceased, he having served as a volunteer in the army of the Republic of Texas, to be located, surveyed, and patented according to law as other headright certificates.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That his act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 3, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="873" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="45" />
<pb n="874" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="46" /><fw type="header" place="top">Certificate.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">THE STATE OF TEXAS.</head>
<p>I, James Webb, Acting Secretary of State, do certify that the third session of the third Legislature of said State, commenced its session at Austin on Monday, the eighteenth day of November, in the year one thousand eight hundred and fifty, and adjourned on Tuesday the third day of December, of the same year.</p>
<p>And I further certify, that the Acts and Joint Resolutions con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained in this Volume, are true copies taken from the original laws deposited in the Department of State, with which they were care<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fully compared.</p>
<p>Given under my hand and seal of State, at the City [L.S.] of Austin, the sixth day of January A. D. one thousand eight hundred and fifty-one.</p>
<closer>
<signed>JAMBS WEBB.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>N. B.&#8212;The words in brackets were inserted by the Secretary of State, in comparing the laws with the originals, supposing them to be omissions in enrolling the bills.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="875" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="i" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX TO GENERAL AND SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">THIRD SESSION&#8212;THIRD LEGISLATURE.</head>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">A</head>
<p>AN ACT accepting the Propositions of the United States relative to the boundary of Texas................................ <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>ACADEMY, Fayette, incorporated............................ <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; Waco Male and Female, incorporated.................... <ref>41</ref></p>
<p>ALEXANDER, Mary, relief of ............................... <ref>24</ref></p>
<p>AMES, Charles, relief of............................... <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>ARMSTRONG. Martin W. B., heirs of................... ............. <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>APPROPRIATION for pay of members and officers of the Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture............................. <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; Act making............................ <ref>34</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">B</head>
<p>BRAZOS AND BERNARD Railway and Plankroad Company incor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porated ........................... <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>BROWN, Reuben R., relief of .................................. <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>BEEMAST, John; relief of ............................... <ref>18</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; John S., relief of................................... <ref>18</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; James J., relief of............................. <ref>18</ref></p>
<p>BURNS, William, relief of....................................... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>BURKE, Benjamin, relief of....................................... <ref>38</ref></p>
<p>BIAS, Mary Ann, relief of............................... <ref>38</ref></p>
<p>BILLINGS, Louisa, relief of............................ <ref>38</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">C</head>
<p>COUNTY of Cass, acts of Surveyors of, legalized..................... <ref>1</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Denton, seat of justice of, permanently located.............. <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Kaufman, seat of justice of, located ....................... <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Freestone, act to create amended................... <ref>30</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Navarro, clerk of, authorized to transcribe records...... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Tyler, &#8220; &#8220; &#8220; &#8220; ...... <ref>12</ref></p>
<pb n="876" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="ii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>COUNTY of Hunt, Commissioners of, required to deliver up certain documents and moneys,........................... <ref>17</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Washington, copy of the records in the office of County Surveyor of, legalized ........................... <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Harris, concerning land certificates issued in .......... <ref>32</ref></p>
<p>CHESHER, James, Sr., relief of .................................. <ref>30</ref></p>
<p>COMMISSIONER of the General Land Office required to issue patents for lands therein named..................... <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>COURT, SUPREME, act reserving public buildings; for use of, repealed <ref>39</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">D &#38; E</head>
<p>DONOHO, William, relief of .................................... <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>EDMOND, John, relief of ................................... <ref>25</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">F</head>
<p>FAYETTE ACADEMY, in the county of Fayette, incorporated, ..... <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>FREESTONE COUNTY, act to create, amended,................... <ref>30</ref></p>
<p>FERGUSON, Alanson, relief of ................................ <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>FITZGERALD, Archibald, heirs of, .............................. <ref>41</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">G</head>
<p>GOVERNOR, authorised to employ counsel in Supreme Court, in cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain cases ............................... <ref>24</ref></p>
<p>GALVESTON AND BRAZOS NAVIGATION COMPANY, act in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corporating, amended................... <ref>26</ref></p>
<p>GILLAM, Simon, heirs of, relief of ................................ <ref>27</ref></p>
<p>GERMAN EMIGRATION COMPANY, to secure to Colonists of, their lands, and to adjust the liabilities of, supplement to............................ <ref>31</ref></p>
<p>GALLAGHER, Peter, relief of ................................... <ref>41</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">H</head>
<p>HENDERSON, LORENZO D., relief of ....................... <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>HENRY, Major W. S., fine imposed by U. S. co&#8217;t-mart&#8217;l refunded.... <ref>21</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">I &#38; J</head>
<p>INSTITUTE, Masonic Female, at Marshall, to confer degrees....... <ref>26</ref></p>
<p>JUDGES OF SUPREME COURT, election of, regulated ............ <ref>40</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">K</head>
<p>KENT, David B., relief of ................................... <ref>38</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8212;Bosmer &#8220; &#8220;........................................ <ref>38</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">L</head>
<p>LOPEZ, Peter, relief of ......................................... <ref>34</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">M</head>
<p>M&#8217;LENNAN, John, junior, relief of ................................. <ref>23</ref></p>
<p>MERCHANT, Berry, relief of ....................................... <ref>29</ref></p>
<p>MASONIC FEMALE INSTITUTE, at Marshall, authorosed to confer degrees, etc ..................... <ref>26</ref></p>
<p>MAYS, Lewis Monroe, relief of .................................... <ref>33</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">M</head>
<p>MORRELL, Zachariah N., retief of ............................. <ref>36</ref></p>
<pb n="877" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>M&#8217;MILL0AN, Martha, relief of <ref>39</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">N &#38; O.</head>
<p>NEW BKAUNFELS, City of, act incorporating amended ............... <ref>17</ref></p>
<p>OWEN, Clark L., benefit of............................... <ref>15</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; James D., benefit of ............................... <ref>15</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">P &#38; R.</head>
<p>PROPOSITIONS from the United States relative to the boundary of Texas, accepted......................... <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>PETERS&#8217; COLONY, settlers in, authorized to intervene in suits in reference to any matter connected with said</p>
<p>Colony contracts............................ <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>RECORDS, copy of, in the office of the County Surveyor, legalized... <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>RISING STAR Chapter No. 9, incorporated............................ <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>REGISTER of land certificates in Harris county, concerning of..... <ref>32</ref></p>
<p>ROBINSON, Thompson, heirs of .............................. <ref>41</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">S</head>
<p>SUPREME COURT of the State of Texas, act organizing, amended, <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; &#8212;Judges of, election of, regulated ................. <ref>41</ref></p>
<p>SHOATE. Stockely D., relief of ............................ <ref>27</ref></p>
<p>SPARKS. Stephen J.. &#8220; &#8220; ......................... <ref>23</ref></p>
<p>SHIPP. William, &#8220; &#8220; ......................... <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>SMITH, John., heirs of. &#8220; &#8220; ........................ <ref>27</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8212;William P., benefit of ............................ <ref>15</ref></p>
<p>SHEL BY UNIVERSITY, incorporated ...................... <ref>19</ref></p>
<p>SHELBYVILLE, town of, in Shelby county, incorporated......... <ref>28</ref></p>
<p>SURVEYORS of Cass county, acts legalized .................. <ref>1</ref></p>
<p>SCHOOL FUND, safe and profitable investment of................... <ref>33</ref></p>
<p>SHAW, Robert, relief of ......................................... <ref>40</ref></p>
<p>SLAVES, act concerning, amended .................................. <ref>42</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">T</head>
<p>TRINITY PLANK ROAD COMPANY, incorporated, part repealed, <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>TIER WESTER, Henry, relief of ................................. <ref>34</ref></p>
<p>TILDON, John W. R., &#8220; &#8220; ........................... <ref>44</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">V</head>
<p>VOLUSTTEERS in the service of Texas in the year 1842, pay regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lated ............................ <ref>40</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">W</head>
<p>WARD. Laanner. relief of ......................................... <ref>19</ref></p>
<p>WALLING. John C., relief of .................................. <ref>31</ref></p>
<p>WACO MALE AND FEMALE ACADEMY, incorporated ................. <ref>42</ref></p>
<pb n="878" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iv" />
</div4>
</div3>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>