<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="671" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">SPECIAL LAWS <lb/>OF <lb/>THE THIRD LEGISLATURE <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS</head>
<byline>VOLUME III.</byline>
<byline>PUBLISHED BY AUTHORITY.</byline>
<byline>AUSTIN. 1850</byline>
<pb n="672" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" />
<pb n="673" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" />
<head type="sub">VOLUME III&#8212;PART II. SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend the second section of an act to incorporate the Town of San Augustine, approved March 18, 1848.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the second section of the above entitled act, be, and the same is hereby so amended, as to read thus:</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the bounds of said corporation shall include one square mile, or six hundred and forty acres of land, having the public square of said town in the middle, or centre, of said cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration; and that this act shall go into effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>November 20, 1849</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to change the name of Daniel Richardson Kaufman, per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />manently to Daniel Kaufman Richardson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the name of Daniel Richardson Kaufman, minor son of David S. Kaufman and Jane B. Kaufman of Sabine county, in this State, be, and the same is hereby changed to Daniel Kauf<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man Rchardson.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 20, 1849</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="674" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to incorporate the Austin College.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Daniel Baker, Sam Houston, Robert Smither, J. Car<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />roll Smith, Henderson Yoakum, John Branch, John Hume, Hugh Wilson, James W. Miller, Joseph McCormack, Anson Jones, Abner S. Lipscomb and [Joseph W.] Hampton and their successors in office, be, and they are hereby constituted a Board of Trustees of a college to be established in or near the town of Huntsville, in Walker county, to be incorporated by the name of the Austin Col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lege, by which name it may sue and be sued, plead and be im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleaded, and buy and sell property, real personal, and mixed, and hold the same. The said college shall have a common seal for the transaction of its business, which seal it shall have power to make, break and alter at pleasure.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That a majority of the Trustees shall constitute a quorum to transact all ordinary business for the corporation. They shall have power to make such by-laws as they may think necessary for the government of the college and its finances; Provided, such by-laws are not inconsistent with the constitution and the laws of this State, or of the United States. They shall have power, also, to elect their own officers, to ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />point their own committees, examine into any branch or depart<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of said college and to appoint and dismiss Tutors&#8212;but it shall require the concurrence of two-thirds of all the Trustees to elect or remove the President or any one of the Professors.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the college shall have power to confer the usual degrees upon men distinguished in science and literature; and shall also have power, upon the recommendation of the faculty to confer the usual degrees upon deserving students, and to grant diplomas for the same; Provided, that such diplomas shall be first signed by a majority of the faculty of said college.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted. That said Trustees shall have the power [of] fixing the salaries of all the officers connected with the college, and also, of filling all the vacancies in their own body till regularly filled as herein provided for.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That all vacancies which may occur in the Board of Trustees, shall be regularly filled by the Presbytery of Brazos; but in case this Presbytery should be divided into two or more Presbyteries, this power shall be vested in that Presbytery in whose bounds the college shall be located, and in case of the formation of one or more synods, the power <pb n="675" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>aforesaid shall be transferred to that synod whose bounds shall embrace the college; Provided, that such synod shall be in regular connection with what is now known as the old school General As<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sembly.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That a site, not exceeding ten acres of land, and the college buildings and library, are hereby declared exempt from taxation, while the property of the college.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That no religious test shall be required of any President, Professor, or Tutor in said college; nor shall any student or officer be censured, suspended or ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pelled on account of his opinions, political or religious; Provided, however; that nothing herein contained shall prevent the Trustees of said college from throwing around the instructors and students a proper moral restraint, and inflicting suitable punishment upon all immoral conduct.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the President of the col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lege shall [be] ex-officio President of the Board of Trustees, and shall be allowed such salary as a majority of the Board of Trus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tees, exclusive of himself, may direct; and no other member of the Board of Trustees shall hold any office in said college.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That said college shall have power to established Professorships, and also, Scholarships and Fellow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ships in said institution; Provided, that the beneficiaries be sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ject to the same rules and by-laws as other students.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That the seal of the corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, with the attestation of the President or, in his absence, of the usual majority of the Trustees, shall be sufficient to authenti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate any act of the corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. Be it further enacted. That all donations and bequests to said college shall be good and binding, although the corporate name of said college may not have been properly stated by the person making such donation or bequest.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Be it further enacted, That the Trustees of the college shall be individually liable for such debts as they may contract; Provided that if any Trustees who may be present at the making of any contract, shall protest in writing against the making of such contract, or not being present, shall, within thirty days next thereafter, make such protest, he shall not be personally liable in any manner for, or on account of such contract.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. Be it further enacted. That if the said Board of Trus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tees should hereafter think proper to establish a theological Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fessorship in said college, the Professor thereof shall not be sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ject to the provisions of the first clause of the eighth section of this act.</p>
<pb n="676" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 14. Be it further enacted, That the said college shall not hold property beyond the amount of two hundred thousand dollars, the college buildings excepted; and that the funds belonging, or in anywise pertaining to the institution, shall not be diverted from the primary object for which it was donated.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 22, 1849</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend an act to establish and incorporate Rutersville College, approved February 5th, 1840.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the tenth section of &#8220;an act to establish and incor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate Rutersville College,&#8221; approved February 5th, 1840, be, and is hereby amended, so that it shall hereafter read as fololws:&#8212; Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That whenever any vacancy shall occur in the Board of Trustees, either by death, resignation, or otherwise, such vacancy shall be permanently filled by the Texas Annual Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church South at its next annual meeting thereafter; that any vacancy that may oc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cur in said Board of Trustees shall be temporarily filled by the said Board of Trustees until the next annual meeting thereafter of said Texas Annual Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church South; and that this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Nov. 26, 1849</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of Thomas Ward.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Thomas Ward be paid the sum of four hundred and ninety-eight dollars and ninety-two cents for repairs on public buildings, out of any of the contingent fund not otherwise appropriated.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 1, 1849</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="677" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to permit Mary Gillespie to adopt Susan Lavinia McGuffin, infant daughter of Samuel and Mary E. MeGuffin, both deceased, late of the county of Grimes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Mary Gillespie be, and she is hereby permitted to adopt Susan Lavinia MeGuffin, infant daughter of Samuel and Mary E. McGuffin, both deceased, late of the county of Grimes; the act of adoption to be under the hand and seal of the said Mary Gillespie, executed before, and certified by a Notary Public, and recorded in the recorder&#8217;s office of Grimes county, as in case of other deeds required by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the act of adoption shall vest the said Mary Gillespie with the rights, and impose on her the duties of natural mother, giving the said Susan Lavinia Mc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Guffin the right of inheritance from the said Mary Gillespie, with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />out the said Mary Gillespie having the right to inherit, by opera<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of law, any estate which has descended, or may hereafter de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scend to the said Susan Lavinia McGuffin from, or through her natural father or mother.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 3, 1849</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of Albert Von Ger-Mar.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office is hereby authorized and required to issue to Albert Yon Ger-Mar a head<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />right certificate for three hundred and twenty acres of land.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this joint resolution take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 10, 1849</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to incorporate the Marshall Cemetery Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Samuel Frion, George Lane, James C. Hawley, <pb n="678" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>George Young, James A. Simpson, F. H. Miller, W. R. D. Ward, W. S. Taylor, T. A. Harris and William Evans, and their success<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ors, be a body corporate, by the name and style of the Marshall<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Cemetery Company, and by that name may sue and be sued, and hold, own, sell, and dispose of real estate, not exceeding twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />five acres, for a burying ground.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted. That said body corporate shall have power to establish by-laws, not inconsistent with the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution and laws of this State, the number and character of offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers, with their powers, the manner in which they are to be chosen, their duties, and to make all other necessary and proper regula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That two-thirds of all the mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers of said body corporate shall be necessary to form a quorum to make the by-laws in the preceding section mentioned.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 12, 1849</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of Hugh McClure.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, in the year 1837, Hugh McClure, a citizen of the State of Virginia, advanced and paid to Samuel M. Williams, Commissioner, &#38;c., three hundred and twenty dollars for land scrip No. 260, for six hundred and forty acres of land, which land scrip has been lost:</p>
<p>And whereas, there exists no law by which the said McClure can obtain a duplicate of the same; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office of this State be, and he is hereby required to issue to Hugh McClure a certificate for six hundred and forty acres of land, to be located and patented in the same manner as other land scrip; Provided that the said McClure shall have complied in all respects with the law regulating the issuance of duplicate land certificates, &#38;c., and that this resolution take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 12, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of C. C. Taylor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of four hundred and fifty dollars be, and <pb n="679" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the same is hereby appropriated to the use and benefit of C. C. Taylor, for making and forwarding to the General Land Office a map of Robertson Land District, and that the same be paid out of any money in the treasury not otherwise appropriated.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect, and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 14, 1849</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to incorporate the Brownsville Lyceum.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That J. R. Palmer, P. J. Parker, R. N. Stansbury, E. S. Dougherty, L. A. Bryan, E. B. Scarborough, F. Grancisky, S. Musina, J. J. H. Grammont, E. Basse, I. E. Garey, J. A. Watson and George Dye, and their associates and successors be, and they are hereby constituted a body politic and corporate, for the en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />couragement of scientific and literary pursuits only, by the name and style of the Brownsville Lyceum, and may sue and be sued, prosecute and defend, in any of the Courts of this State; may grant, purchase and receive, by its corporate name, real and personal property not exceeding twenty-five thousand dollars in value; and may have a common seal, with any device upon the same the Ly<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceum may determine, to be altered or changed by the will of said Lyceum; may adopt such a constitution, by-laws and regulations for the management of the affairs of the Lyceum as the regular members thereof may deem proper, not contrary to the constitution and laws of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the library, cabinet and ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />paratus of the Lyceum shall be free and exempt from all taxation, but the balance of the property shall be regularly given in for taxation by such officers as the Lyceum may direct, according to the provisions of the tax laws of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act of incorporation shall be subject to such modifications, extensions and limitations as the Legislature may from time to time provide.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 18, 1849</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="680" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to change the names of Melissa J., James Alexander and Parola Simonds.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the names of Melissa J. Simonds, James Alexander Simonds, and Parola Simonds be, and the same are hereby changed to Melissa J. Mitchell, James Alexander Mitchell, and to Parola Mitchell, respectively.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this Act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 18, 1849</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act authorizing and requiring the Commissioner of the Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral Land Office to issue a head-right certificate to A. S. Cun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ningham.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a certificate for one-third of a league of land, first class, to A. S. Cunningham; which said certificate shall subject the owner thereof to the same liabilities as to government dues and office fees as are imposed on others of the same class.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 19, 1849</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of John Barton.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, John Barton entered the service of Texas previous to the first day of August, 1836, as a volunteer during the war, and afterwards received an honorable discharge from the army of Texas, which rendered him legally entitled to one-third of a league of land, as a head-right; and whereas, he has never re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceived a certificate; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of <pb n="681" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office of this State be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to the said John Barton a certificate for one-third of a league of land, as his head-right, to be located and patented on the same terms, and in the same manner as other first class certificates; and that this resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 20, 1849</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of the heirs and assignees of Ben<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jamin D. Nobles, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller be, and he is hereby authorized to receive the amount due on lots Nos. 1 and 2, in block 67, and lot No. 12, in block No. 55, in the city of Austin, from the legal rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentative of Benjamin D. Nobles, deceased, and upon the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceipt thereof, that he issue the usual certificate for patent.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 31, 1849</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of the heirs of Peter Crudden, de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Peter Crudden entered the army of Texas in Captain Allen&#8217;s company of voluteers, on the fiftenth day of October, in the year eighteen hundred and thirty-six, and served as a member of said company until the twenty-third day of January, in the year eighten hundred and thirty-seven, when, upon a re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />organization of the army, he was attached to Captain Neill&#8217;s company in the first regiment of permanent volunteers, and served in the same faithfully until his death; and whereas, by law he was entitled to a head-right of six hundred and forty acres of land, and the said Crudden died without having re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceived the said land, or any part thereof; and whereas, neither the widow nor heirs of the said Crudden have ever received said land or any part thereof; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of <pb n="682" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorised and required to issue to the heirs of Peter Crudden, a land certificate for six hundred and forty acres of land, and cause the same to be surveyed and patented in the same manner as other first class certificates, by the said heirs paying the fees for the same, as in other cases; and that this resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 31, 1849</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to authorize and require the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue a patent to Robert W. Latimer for six hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and forty acres of land.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Robert W. Lati<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mer a patent for six hundred and forty acres of land, on certi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficate number four hundred and fifty-three, issued to said Latimer by the Board of Land Commissioners for Shelby county, and dated the first day of May, A. D. 1848; Provided that said Latimer shall pay the same fees as required by law on other third class head<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />right certificates.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 31, 1849</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to incorporate the President and Trustees of the Guad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />alupe High School Association.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That William E. Jones, Andrew Neill, Thomas D. John<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, H. C. Fountain, Wm. H. Gordon, Samuel W. Elliott and J. B. Morgan and their associates be, and they are hereby created a body politic and corporate, under the name and style of the President and Trustees of the Guadalupe High School Associa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, and by that name may sue and be sued, in all actions of law and equity, may have a common seal and the same may al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="683" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ter, change or destroy, and they shall be capable of holding and acquiring property, real and personal, either by donation or pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chase, to the amount of thirty thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the annual election for President, Secretary, Treasurer and Trustees, shall be held in Seguin by the members of the Association, on the first Tuesday of January of each year, and the affairs of the Association shall be conducted by said officers as a Board of Trustees under the constitution and by-laws; Provided, the same are not inconsistent or contrary to the constitution or laws of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the location of the institu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion shall be in the town of Seguin, Guadalupe county, and the objects thereof, to promote and advance the cause of education in the higher branches of literature and science.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 31, 1849</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of James M. Manning.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, James M. Manning emigrated to the Republic of Texas, and entered the army thereof previous to the first day of August, in the year eighteen hundred and thirty-six, and served a tour of duty thereafter; and previous to the first day of January in the year eighteen hundred and forty, introduced his family and settled in said Republic; and whereas, said Manning has never received any augmentation of land for the introduction of his family, &#38;c.; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office of this State be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to the said James M. Manning, a certificate for two-thirds of a league and one labor of land, to be located and patented under the same rules and regulations as are provided by law in first class certi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficates; and that this joint resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 31, 1849</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="684" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act supplementary to an act to incorporate Austin College, approved November, 1849.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That A. J. Burke, Daniel D. Atchison and George C. Redd be, and they are hereby appointed Trustees of Austin College, in addition to the Trustees heretofore appointed in the act to which this is a supplement.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the said Board of Trustees of Austin College, and their successors, shall hold and exercise the duties of their office for the term of six years; Provided, how<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever, that the Brazos Presbytery may, at their first regular session, or at a special session called for that purpose, so class the present Board of Trustees, that the term of one-third of their number shall expire at the termination of two years, one-third at the end of four years, and the remaining third at the end of six years.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That all laws and parts of laws in conflict with this supplementary act be, and they are hereby repealed and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Jan. 3, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to authorize James Knight to adopt Lucinda E. Nibbs, daughter of Mary Beckham, deceased, late of the county of Fort Bend.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That James Knight be, and he is hereby permitted to adopt Lucinda E. Nibbs, wife of William B. Nibbs, and daughter of Mary Beckham, deceased, late of the county of Fort Bend; the act of adoption to be under the hand and seal of the said James Knight, executed before, and certified by a Notary Public, and recorded in the county clerk&#8217;s office of Fort Bend county, in the same man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner as other deeds of conveyance.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the act of adoption shall vest the said James Knight with the rights and impose on him the duties of a father, giving the said Lucinda E. Nibbs the rights <pb n="685" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>of inheritance from the said James Knight, without the said James Knight having the right to inherit, by operation of law, any estate which has descended, or which may hereafter descend to the said Lucinda E. Nibbs from, or through her ancestors.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Jan. 8, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to authorize the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue a head-right certificate, first class, for one league and labor of land to James Taylor, and for one-third of a league to the heirs of Wiliam Irving Lewis.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a certificate for one league and labor of land, first class, to James Taylor, and a certi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficate for one-third of a league of land to the heirs of William Ir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ving Lewis, and that the same shall be subject to the same liabili<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties as to government dues and office fees as are imposed by law on others of the same class.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Jan. 10, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to incorporate Rio Grande City.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the citizens of Rio Grande City, in Starr county, be, and they are hereby declared a body politic and corporate, under the name and style of the Corporation of Rio Grande City, shall have the powers of suing and being sued, pleading and being im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleaded, and to hold property, real and personal, within the limits of said corporation, and at their pleasure to dispose of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the corporate limits of said city shall extend one half mile in every direction from the centre of the public square.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the Chief Justice of the county, to order an election to be held as early as practicable after the passage of this act, upon <pb n="686" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>giving ten days notice of the same, for the election of one Mayor and six Aldermen, a Collector or Constable, Treasurer and Secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary, who shall hold their offices for the term of one year from the time of their election. In case a vacancy occurs by death, resigna<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion or otherwise, the vacancy for the unexpired term shall be filled by a new election, as follows: In case of vacancy in office of Mayor, then the election to be conducted by a quorum of Aldermen, but in case of vacancy in the Board of Aldermen, Collector or Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer, then the election shall be conducted by the Mayor. All per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons residing within the corporation shall be entitled to vote for the above named officers, who are eligible to vote for members of Congress.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the Mayor and two-thirds of the Aldermen shall constitute a Board to transact business.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the Collector, Treasurer and Secretary shall give bond to the Mayor and his successors in office, in such sum and with such securities as shall be approved by the Mayor and Board of Aldermen: and that all officers elected by virtue of this act, before entering upon the duties of their office, shall take and subscribe an oath for the faithful performance of the duties of their respective offices.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the Mayor to cause an election to be held annually, at least ten days before the expiration of his term of office, for Mayor, Aldermen, Collector, Treasurer and Secretary, who shall enter upon the duties of their offices respectively upon the expiration of the term of their predecessors.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That the Mayor shall have juris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diction, and exercise the powers of a Justice of the Peace, over all the offences committed against the ordinances and decrees of the Mayor and Board of Aldermen, within the limits of the corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the corporate authorities of said Rio Grande City be, and they are hereby authorized and invested with the sole and exclusive powers to grant licenses to ferrymen upon the Rio Grande River, under such rules and regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lations as they may prescribe, opposite to, and adjoining the said city; and that if any person shall establish any ferry, or shall transport any person or property for hire or reward across said Rio Grande River without such license, such person so ferrying or transporting any person or property, shall in each and every instance be liable to pay to the person having such license the <pb n="687" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>sum of twenty-five dollars, to be recovered before any court of com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />petent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That the Mayor and Aldermen shall have power to pass such ordinances and decrees as they shall deem necessary for establishing schools and for the support of edu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cation; for the regulation of the police and the preservation of order; to prescribe penalties; to levy taxes; for the removal of nuisances; keeping streets in order, and for such other purposes as the Board may deem proper and necessary within the limits of the city; Provided, that such ordinances and decrees shall not con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />flict with the constitution and laws of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That this act shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Jan. 10, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of the heirs of George W. Maine.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a certificate for one league and one labor of land to the heirs of Lieut. George W. Maine, deceased, who was killed at the Alamo with the command of Col. Barrett Travis, on the 6th day of March, 1836, in lieu of a certificate issued by the Board of Land Commissioners for the county of Calhoun to the administrator of the estate of said George W. Maine, dated the seventh day of June, in the year eighteen hundred and forty-seven, which said certificate, when issued by the Commissioner of the General Land Office, shall be valid against the State of Texas, and when located and surveyed, and the field<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />notes returned to the General Land Office, it shall be the duty of the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue a patent thereon.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 10th, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="688" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act supplementary to an act to establish and incorporate the College of DeKalb, approved January 26, 1839.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, by death, removal from the State, and other causes, va<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cancies have occurred in the Board of Trustees of said College, which cannot be filled by said Board according to the provisions of said act, in consequence of not having a quorum for the trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />action of business; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That David Chisolm, Cairo Epperson, John C. Glass, James M. Wise, William A. Boyd, John W. Lee, Warren K. Dolby, Mar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tin Glover, John Fizdale, Stephen H. Ellis, Joseph Burks and Charles Lewis be, and they are hereby constituted and appointed Trustees to fill the vacancies in said Board.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The Board of Trustees of said College appointed by this act shall be divided by lot into three classes, as nearly equal as can be. The seats of the first class shall be vacated at the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />piration of two years, the seats of the second class at the expira<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of four years, and the third class at the expiration of six years. At the expiration of the above periods, the Board shall fill vacancies by elections, and if a vacancy or vacancies should occur in either of said classes before the expiration of their respective terms, the Board shall fill the same by election for the unexpired term.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The persons that may be appointed as Trustees to fill the vacancies that may occur in the original Board, shall be sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ject to the same classification and regulation as those herein con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stituted and appointed to fill vacancies, and that this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Jan. 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to legalize the head-right certificate of Simon P. Barnes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a patent for <pb n="689" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>three hundred and twenty acres of land, on the certificate issued to said Barnes by the Board of Land Commissioners for Shelby county, dated 5th of April, 1843.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Jan. 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of the heirs of William Mockford.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office of the State of Texas be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to the heirs of William Mockford, a land patent for twelve hundred and eighty acres of land, located by virtue of bounty land warrant No. 3,032, issued to William J. Hawkins, under the same rules and regulations governing the issuance of patents on similar certificates, and that this resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Jan. 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of John Balch.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, John Batch, a private soldier in Capt. York&#8217;s company of volunteers, emigrated to Texas and participated in the storm<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing of Bexar previous to the declaration of independence, and also served on a tour of duty in Capt. Wyly&#8217;s company during the campaign of 1836, and participated in the battle of San Ja<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cinto during said campaign; and whereas, said John Balch has never received his head-right land, as guarantied to him by the constitution of the late Republic of Texas; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office of this State, issue a certificate of one-third of a league of land to John Balch, in full satisfaction of all claims to a head-right certificate; Provided the said Balch shall be required to pay the same fees as required upon other first class head-rights.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Jan. 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="690" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of Benjamin F. Fry</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Benjamin F. Fry entered the army of Texas in October, 1835, and aided in the siege of Bexar; was a citizen of Texas at the date of the declaration of independence; participated in the battle of San Jacinto, and has never received his head-right cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate for one-third of a league of land as guarantied to him by the constitution and laws of the late Republic of Texas; there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office of this State be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Ben<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jamin F. Fry, a land certificate for one-third of a league of land, to be located and patented under the same rules and regulations that are provided by law in the case of first class certificates; and that this resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to incorporate the Texana College.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the persons hereinafter mentioned shall be commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners to receive subscriptions for shares in an Academy associa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, to be styled the Texana Academy, to be located at Texana in the county of Jackson, and State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the trustees to be elected as hereinafter provided, are hereby constituted a body politic and corporate with power of sueing and being sued, pleading and being impleaded, answering and being answered unto, in all courts hav<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing jurisdiction, in the name and style of the President and Trus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tees of the Texana Academy. They shall have power to open books, to receive subscription, and donations to the capitol stock of said Academy to acquire hold and convey property, real and personal to have and use a common seal, to alter the same at pleasure, to make and alter from time to time, such by-laws as they may deem necessary for the government and regulation of said institution, its officers and servants, and property, provided such by-laws be not inconsistent with the constitution and laws of the United States, and of this State or of this act.</p>
<pb n="691" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the Trustees of said in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution shall consist of six stockholders; at the first annual elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, two of whom, shall be elected by ballot for the term of three years, other two shall be elected for the term of two years, and other two shall be elected to serve for the term of one year, and who shall continue in office until their successors are duly elected; and every year thereafter there shall be an election of two Trustees, held at some convenient place, to be from time to time ascertained and fixed by the by-laws of said corporation, until the said academy is fitted for holding elections therein, after which all elections shall be held at said Academy; and that any person holding more than one right or share in said academy shall be entitled to one vote for each right or share he or she shall hold in the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the stockholders of said, institution shall have power to fill such vacancy or vacancies of said Trustees as may happen by death, resignation or otherwise, and the said Trustees shall hold the property of said institution safely for the purpose of education in said Academy, and not as stock for the individual benefit of themselves or any contribu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors to the endowments of the same, and no particular religious faith shall be required of those who become trustees, teachers, officers, scholars or servants, of said institution, nor shall any teacher, trustee, or any other person connected with said institu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion be allowed or permitted to use any means or influence in or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der to induce any of said students to subscribe to any particular creed or faith, or to attend on or at any particular creed or place of worship to the exclusion of any other; all persons however may be suspended or expelled from said institution by the trustees thereof, whose habits are evil or vicious, or whose moral character is bad.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That said institution, shall be located in, or within half a mile of the town of Texana, in the county of Jackson, in said State; and the said trustees shall be competent in law or equity to take to themselves and their suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessors in office, in their said corporate name, any estate, real per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonal or mixed, by the gift, grant, bargain and sale, conveyance, will, devise or bequest of any person or persons whomsoever, and the same estate, whether real, personal, or mixed, to grant, bargain, sell, demise or place out on interest or otherwise dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose of, for the use of said institution, in such manner as shall seem to them most beneficial to the institution; said trustees shall faithfully apply all funds collected, or the proceeds, accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing to their best judgment, in erecting and completing a suitable <pb n="692" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>building or buildings, supporting the necessary officers, instruct<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ors or instructresses and servants, and procuring books, maps, charts, globes, and apparatus necessary to the success of said Acad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />emy, provided nevertheless, That in case any donation, devise, or bequest shall be made for particular purposes, accordant with the design of this: institution, and the corporation shall accept the same; every donation, devise or bequest, shall be applied in con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formity to the express conditions of the donor or devisor.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the stockholders shall an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nually elect a Treasurer for said institution, who shall, before he enters upon the duties of his office, give a bond with approved security to the President and trustees of said academy, in such penal sum as they may require, for the sure and faithful perform<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance of his duty as Treasurer, and in case of his death, removal, refusal, or neglect to serve, it shall be lawful for the President and Trustees of the Academy at any of their meetings, to appoint an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />other Treasurer in his stead, to remain in office till the expiration of the time during which his predecessor was elected.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That all process against the said corporation shall be by summons, and the service of the same shall be by leaving an attested copy thereof with the Treasurer, or at his usual place of abode, at least twenty days before the return thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the President and Trustees shall have power to employ and appoint a principal for said insti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tution, and all such instructors and treachers, and servants as may be necessary, and to displace them, as the interest of the Academy may require the same; and to fill all vacancies which may happen by death or otherwise.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That the trustees shall meet an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nually, and oftener if they think necessary, in the town of Texana, and they shall, at their first meeting, elect one of their body Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent, who shall hold the office during the term for which he was elected Trustee, and at the same time, they shall in like manner elect a treasurer. They shall appoint one of their body clerk, who shall faithfully record all the proceedings of said Trustees; they shall elect all officers and servants by ballot, and a majority of said Trustees shall be sufficient in all cases to transact the busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness of said corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That not over forty acres of land in one or more lots shall be held in perpetuity by said Acad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />emy, for the sole use and occupancy of the buildings and append<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ages connected therewith; and such land so held, together with <pb n="693" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the buildings thereon, and all books, maps, and other property connected with and belonging to said institution, shall be held free from taxation.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That on the payments of ten dollars to the treasurer, every free white person shall be consid<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ered a stock-holder, and be entitled to one vote for each share of ten dollars held by him; and it shall be lawful for each and every stock holder for the time being of said Academy, his executors, administrators or assigns, to give, sell, devise, and dispose of their respective rights or shares in said Academy, and such donee or purchaser shall be entitled to all the rights of the original holder.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Be it further enacted, That E. M. Glenn, Thomas Haynes, A. T. Gayle, James Kerr, George Sutherland, J. S. Meni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fee, Samuel Wilder, G. A. McDonald, C. L. Owen, L. M. White, Thomas Simons and E. F. Wells, be and they are hereby appoint<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed Commissioners to solicit and receive subscriptions of stock to said institution, and give receipts for the same; and when the sum of five hundred dollars of stock is subscribed, said Commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers, or any three of them, shall be authorized to give public notice in some newspaper of the time and place of holding an election of trustees of said institution, which first election shall be held at some convenient place in Texana, between the hours of twelve M. and six P. M. on said day, and the trustees so elected shall hold their offices until the 1st Monday in January following, at which time a regular election shall be held, as hereinafter provided, and the Chief Justice of said county shall act as judge of said election, and give certificates to those elected.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. Be it further enacted. That the second election of trustees, and any subsequent one, shall be held on the first Monday in January annually, at the Academy, between the hours of 12 M. and 6 P. M. on said day.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. Be it further enacted, That each stock-holder, shall be required at or before the first election for trustees, to pay to said Commissioners, five dollars on each share by him or her sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed, and the residue in six months thereafter, or the amount paid shall be forfeited.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. Be it further enacted. That, all elections for trustees shall be by ballot, with the name of the stock-holder or voter writ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ten on the ballot, and the number of shares of stock, he or she holds in said institution, and which ballot after the first election shall be given to the treasurer or clerk of the board of trustees; a majority of whom shall act as a board of election.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. Be it further enacted, That the said Academy, when erected and in operation, shall at all times be open for the use and <pb n="694" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>privilege of every free white person who may wish to be instructed there, if such free white person will comply with the laws and by-laws, and pay the sum affixed by said trustees, for the instruc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of students attending there.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. Be it further enacted, That every free white person may at any time pay the sum of ten dollars, to the treasurer of the Academy; it shall be the duty of the treasurer to accept the same, and give him a receipt for the same, and, upon the presenta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of said receipt to the clerk, it shall be the duty of the clerk, to issue to the holder a certificate of stock, for the amount paid.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. Be it further enacted, That all conveyances of prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty belonging to said institution, shall be made by the President, under the seal of said corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. Be it further enacted, That if at any time the cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration shall violate the provisions of this charter, it shall be the duty of the Attorney General to file an information in the nature of a quo warranto, for the purpose of vacating this act; provided, in that ease, the trustees shall have the right of selling all the prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty, real and personal, belonging to said corporation, for the sole benefit of the stock-holders, who shall be entitled to the same, as soon as it is collected; and it shall then be considered as money paid to the use of the said stock-holders.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. Be it further enacted, That in case it should happen that an election should not be made on any day, when in pursu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance of this act it ought to have been made, the said corporation shall not for that reason be deemed to be dissolved, but that it shall be lawful on any other day, to hold and make an election of trustees in such manner as shall have been regulated by the by<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />laws and ordinances of said corporation.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to authorize the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue a head-right certificate, first-class, for one league and labor of land, to John Boyd, assignee of George W. Mead.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a certificate of <pb n="695" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>one league and labor of land, first class, to John Boyd, assignee of George W. Mead, and that the same shall be subject to the same liabilities as to government dues and office fees as are imposed on others of the same class.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 16, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Washington H. Secrest.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a certificate for one league and one labor of land, the same being his head right, to Washington H. Secrest.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the said certificate may be located upon any of the vacant and unappropriated lands of this State, and that the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby required, upon the return of the field notes, to is<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sue a patent to said Secrest, upon his paying the same fees and government dues required of colonists who emigrated previous to the second day of May, 1835, according to the requirements of law.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Jan. 16, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act making an appropriation for the pro rata pay of Thomas P. Anderson, deceased, Surgeon in the Navy of the late Repub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of eight hundred and forty-eight dollars and four cents be, and the same is hereby appropriated out of any money in the treasury not otherwise appropriated, to be paid to the widow and heirs at law of Thomas P. Anderson, deceased, being the amount to which he was entitled under the provisions of an act making an appropriation for the pro rata pay of the officers and seamen of the Navy of the Republic of Texas, <pb n="696" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>approved Feb&#8217;y 5, 1844; Provided, that the provisions of this act shall not have force and effect, if the claim herein referred to belongs to a third party, or any other than the widow and child of Dr. T. P. Anderson; and provided, further, that the Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller shall, before paying the amount, require the heirs and repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of said Anderson to surrender any certificate or other evidence of debt which may have been issued, relative to the debt herein referred to.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Jan. 16, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to incorporate the town of Castroville.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the citizens of the town of Castroville, in the county of Medina, are hereby declared a body politic and corporate, by the name and style of the Town of Castroville, and by that name may sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, and may hold and dispose of real and personal estate in said town.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the bounds and limits of said town and within which the said corporation shall exercise lawful jurisdiction, shall include and comprehend the whole of the league of land upon which said town is situated.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the town council of said town shall consist of a Mayor and five Aldermen, who shall be elected by the qualified electors residing within the corporate juris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diction on the first Monday in January in each year.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That there shall also be elected by the qualified electors at the same time of the election of the town council, a treasurer and collector, who shall be required to give good and sufficient security, to be approved by the council, for the faithful discharge of their dirties, the amount of their bonds, if forfeited, to be paid into the city treasury.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the members of the city council, and the treasurer and collector, shall hold their offices for one year, or until their successors are qualified.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the Mayor and Aldermen and other officers elected, shall enter upon the discharge of their duties on the second Monday in January of each and every year.</p>
<pb n="697" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That if, from any cause, an elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion shall fail to be held for the aforesaid corporate officers at the time herein prescribed, it shall be the duty of the Chief Justice of the county of Medina, upon the application of any five citizens, to order a special election, and the officers elected at such special elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion shall hold their offices until the second Monday in January thereafter, and no longer.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That no person shall be a mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber of said town council who is not either a householder or owner of real estate within the boundaries of said Corporation, and who has not resided therein at least six months previous to an election, nor shall any person vote for any of said corporate officers, unless such voter has had a like residence, and paid his city taxes.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That the Mayor shall be president of the council, and that the Mayor and three Aldermen shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute a quorum to do business. If the office of Mayor shall be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />come vacant, the council shall have power to appoint one of their own members to act as Mayor during such vacancy; and if a va<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cancy should occur in the office of Alderman, the council shall have the power to appoint another to fill the unexpired term of such Alderman.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted. That the council shall have power to enact and enforce such ordinances and regulations as they may deem necessary for the good government and general improvement of said town; Provided, the same shall not conflict, with the constitution or laws of this State. They shall also form by-laws to regulate their own proceedings, and shall have full power and authority to enforce proper police regulations. They shall also have power and authority to regulate the paving and cleaning the streets, regulating the markets, removing nuisances, establishing the squares, side walks and alleys of the town; and for these and similar purposes, may appoint such officers as they may deem necessary, and prescribe their compensation, and remove them from office at the pleasure of the council.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That said council shall have power to levy equitable and moderate taxes upon all fixed and moveable property within their jurisdiction, and recover the same upon process issued by the Mayor, after five days notice: the poorer class of citizens may be permitted to contribute their manual labor upon works of public utility, in lieu of taxes; the quantity of said labor to be regularly apportioned by the council. The council shall also have power to grant licenses to retailers of spirituous liquors, keepers of billiard tables, places of public <pb n="698" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>amusement, &#38;c.; Provided, that no gambling establishment, nor any other contrary to law shall be protected by such license, nor shall any license tax be imposed upon any mechanical or agricul<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tural employment.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Be it further enacted, That any suit instituted be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore the Mayor for the recovery of any taxes, dues, licenses, pen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />alties or forfeitures, where the amount in controversy exceeds ten dollars, the defendant shall have the right of trial by jury of six men.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. Be it further enacted. That the council shall have power to inflict moderate fines for the breach or non-observance of its ordinances, and collect the same as in other cases. Any person aggrieved by the decision or judgment of the Mayor, shall in all cases have the right of appeal to the District Court.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. Be it further enacted, That the Mayor shall have the same jurisdiction in criminal cases or breaches of the peace, as is by law vested in Justices of the Peace.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. Be it further enacted, That all elections for Mayor, members of the Council and other officers shall be held at the time prescribed, after ten days notice of said election has been given by the Mayor, and the Mayor and Aldermen shall conduct such election as President and managers thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. Be it further enacted, That the Mayor shall have power to call special meetings of the council whenever in his opinion the interest of the town requires, and it shall be his duty in all cases to take care that the ordinances of the council are duly executed.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 16, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Thos. William Ward.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of two hundred and sixty-eight dollars and thirty-eight cents be, and the same is hereby appropriated out of any money in the treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the reimbursement of Thomas William Ward, late Commissioner of the General Land Office, for advances made by him for <pb n="699" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="29" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the purchase and transportation of stationery, land patents, &#38;c., in the year 1847, and that the Comptroller of Public Accounts issue to him a draft on the Treasurer for said amount.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 19, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to incorporate the Texas Monumental Committee.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Albert L. Vail, George W. Sinks, John W. Dancy, William T. Russell, Isaac B. McFarland, Thomas W. Cox, John T. Cox, Hamilton Ledbetter, D. C. Gregory, A. P. Manley, Wil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liam G. Webb, William Menifee, William P. Smith, Charles S. Longcope, B. B. Jarmon and Joseph Shaw be, and they are hereby constituted a body politic and corporate, under the name and style of the Texas Monumental Committee, and by that name shall be able and capable in law to purchase, buy, have, receive and enjoy, to them and their successors, lands, tenements, and hereditaments of any kind in fee, or for life, or for years, and personal property of any kind whatsoever; and all sums of money which may be purchased by them, or given, granted or bequested to them, for the purpose of building a monument over the remains of the deci<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mated Mier prisoners, and the slain of Captain Dawson&#8217;s Company, and over the remains of all those who have fallen in the cause of Texas, which they may be able to procure.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That said Committee may have a common seal for the business of themselves and their succes<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sors; by their aforesaid names, they and their successors shall and may be able to sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />swer and be answered, defend and be defended in all the courts of law and equity in this State, and to grant, bargain and sell, or assign any lands, tenements, goods or chattels that may be ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired by the same, and to elect their own officers, employ agents or substitutes, and to do all things whatsoever for the purposes aforesaid, in as ample a manner as any person, or body politic or corporate can or may do by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That said Committee shall elect a President, Secretary, and Treasurer, and such other officers as they may deem proper.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the President and four <pb n="700" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="30" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>members of said Committee shall constitute a quorum to do busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness; and in the absence or disability of the President, five mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers shall constitute a quorum at any regular meeting.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That all monies loaned out at interest by said Committee for the purposes expressed in the first section of this act, all lands, tenements, goods and chattels ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired by said Committee, either by purchase or otherwise, shall be, and they are hereby declared to be free from any kind of pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic tax, until they may be disposed of by said Committee.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That whenever any vacancy shall occur in said Comittee, either by death or resignation, removal from this State or otherwise, such vacancy shall be filled by the Committee.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That said Committee shall have power to pass such by-laws as shall not conflict with the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion and laws of this State, and the constitution of the United States.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 19, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to change the name of William Lipe Walradt to William Waldradt Dunlap.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That from and after the passage of this act, the name of William Lipe Waldradt, of Cameron county, in this State be, and the same is changed to William Waldradt Dunlap.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 19, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Mary Henderson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required, upon the application of Mary Henderson or her legal representatives, to cancel patent No. six hundred and ninety-four, second class, for twelve hund<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="701" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="31" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>red and eighty acres of land, situated on Wolf Creek, in Tyler county; and the said Commissioner of the General Land Office is further authorized and required to deliver to the said Mary Henderson, or her legal representatives, her headright certificate upon which said patent, number six hundred and ninety-four, was predicated, which certificate shall be sufficient authority to any lawful surveyor to survey the same upon any vacant and un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />appropriated public domain of the State; upon which certificate and survey, or surveys, the Commissioner of the General Land Office is hereby required to issue a patent or patents, as on any other legal claim against the government for land.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Jan. 19, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act supplementary to an act to incorporate the Western Texas Orphan Asylum, approved March 16, 1848.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Directors of the Western Texas Orphan Asylum, shall be, and they are hereby authorized to establish, in addition to said Asylum, an Agricultural School and such other institutions of learning, in any branch of the arts and sciences, as they may deem proper; and they shall have power in their corporate ca<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pacity, to control and govern the same, in the same manner and to the same extent, as they are now permitted to control and govern said institution.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That said Directors shall have power upon the establishment of any such institution, to appoint a President and such other officers as may be necessary for conduct<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing such institution; to appoint such Professors as they may deem proper, and regulate and prescribe their duties; and in conjunction with the faculty, and professors of such institution, may grant and confer such degrees, in arts and sciences, as are usually granted by Colleges and Universities. The said Directors shall also be vested with all such necessary powers, to secure the prosperity and objects of such institution, as are usually granted to similar insti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tutions.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That no religious qualification, or test whatever, shall be necessary in order to become a Profes<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sor or student of any institution established by said Directors; <pb n="702" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="32" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>nor shall any student be excluded from the benefits of the same, in consequence of his religious faith.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Apyroved, <date>January 19, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XL.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to incorporate the Grand and Subordinate Divisions of the Sons of Temperance.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the officers of the Grand Division of the Sons of Temperance, and their successors in office, be, and they are here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by declared to be a community corporation and body politic, by the name, style, and title aforesaid, and by that name, they and their successors shall, and may be capable in law, to have, receive and retain to them, and to their successors, property real and per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonal; also, devises and bequests, of any person or persons, bodies corporate or politic, capable of making the same, and the same at their pleasure to transfer or dispose of in such manner as they may think proper.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the said corporation and their successors, by the name, style and title aforesaid, shall be forever hereafter capable in law, to sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, answer and be answered unto, defend and be defend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed, in all or any courts of Justice, and before all or any Judge, officers or persons whatsoever in all and singular actions, matters and demands whatsoever.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the officers and members of all Subordinate Divisions under the jurisdiction of said Grand Division shall be entitled to the benefits of the provisions of this act, and may erect buildings for their own convenience, and hold property by the name of the particular Division; and the record of this charter in the office of the clerk of the county court, where such Subordinate Division is formed, shall be evidence of their incorporation under this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 19, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="703" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="33" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of the Heirs or legal representatives of William H. Malone, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby authorized to issue to the heirs or legal representatives of William H. Malone, deceased, a land certificate for six hundred and forty acres of land, as his headright certificate, and that said land be located, surveyed and patented in accordance with the laws, now in force, regulating the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 19, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of the Heirs of Duncan McIntyre, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Duncan McIntyre, joined the Army of the late Repub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic of Texas, as a volunteer, previous to the first day of August, eighteen hundred and thirty-six, and served a tour of duty as such, and died without receiving his headright certificate, as guarantied to him by the Constitution and laws of said Repub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office of the State of Texas, be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to the heirs of said Duncan McIntyre, deceased, a land certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate for one third of a league of land, to be located and patented in the same manner, as provided in cases of first class certificates; and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 19, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend an act entitled an act to incorporate Baylor Uni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />versity, approved February 1, 1845.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the tenth section of an act entitled an act to incor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="704" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="34" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>porate Baylor University, approved February 1, 1845, and in the words following, to wit: that when any vacancy shall occur either by resignation or otherwise in the board of trustees, such vacancy shall be filled by the Executive Committee, of the Texas Baptist Education Society, be and the same is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That when any vacancy shall hereafter occur, by death, resignation or otherwise, in the said board of Trustees, such vacancy shall be filled by the Texas Bap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tist State Convention.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 19, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Samuel G. Norvell and John H. Carter.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby required to issue to Samuel G. Norvell and John H. Carter, certificates for six hundred and forty acres of land each, as their headlights; and that said certificates may be located, sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyed and patented, according to the laws now in force regulating the same; and that this act be in force, and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 19, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to incorporate the Mount Vernon Male and Female Academies.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the present Trustees of Mount Vernon male and fe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />male Academies, in the village of Mount Vernon and county of Titus, be, and they are hereby constituted a body corporate and politic, by the name and style of the Trustees of the Mount Ver<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />non Male and Female Academies, and as such shall be capable and liable in law to sue and be sued, to plead and be impleaded, and shall be authorized to make such laws and regulations as <pb n="705" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="35" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>shall be necessary for the government of said Academies; provided, such laws and regulations are not repugnant to the constitution and laws of this State; and for that purpose, may have and use a common seal, and appoint such officers as they may think proper out of their own body, and remove the same from office for im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proper conduct or neglect of duty.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That said trustees of said body corporate shall be privileged to accept of, and may be invested with, all manner of property, real or personal, or mixed; also, all donations, gifts, grants, and privileges which may be hereafter made or granted to said institution, or which may be hereafter conveyed or transferred to said trustees or their successors in office, to have and hold the same for the use, benefit and behalf of said Academies, provided said property shall not exceed in amount thirty thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That on the first Monday of Au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gust, in the year eighteen hundred and fifty, until which time the present trustees shall hold their office, and annually hereafter, the qualified electors for representative to the State Legislature, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />siding at the time within the precinct in which the Mount Vernon academies are situated, shall elect seven trustees for the succeeding year.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the election shall be held by three persons appointed by the acting Trustees, and a majority of said electors present and voting, shall be sufficient to constitute the persons so voted for duly elected Trustees, and in all cases the old Trustees shall hold their offices until their successors are elected.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That said Academies shall be forever free from the control of any particular denomination of Christians, but shall be ever open for the use and benefit of all.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and he in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Jan. 24, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Lemuel M. Rodearmel.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Adjutant-General of the State be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Lemuel M. Rodearmel or his assignees, a certificate for twelve hundred and eighty acres <pb n="706" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="36" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>of land, that being the amount to which he is entitled by law for services rendered in the army of the late Republic of Texas in the year 1837.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the certificate, when issued, may be located and the survey made on any vacant or unappropri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated land of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the Commissioner of the General Land Office, when the field-notes of said survey shall be returned to his office, to issue a patent thereon.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect, and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Jan. 24, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of James S. Patterson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to James S. Patter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son a certificate for one-third of a league of land, to be located on any of the vacant and unappropriated land of this State, and on the return of the field-notes and the payment of the govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment dues, to issue title as in other cases provided by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this joint resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>Jan. 24, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Samuel G. Newton &#38; Co., and Tilly and Hewitt.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, there was audited on the 27th day of January, 1849, in the Auditor&#8217;s office of the State of Texas, in favor of Sam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uel G. Newton &#38; Co., certain claims for services rendered the late Republic of Texas, in the army, in the year 1845, by Jackson Hewitt and James Cole, amounting to one hundred and seventy-eight dollars, the certificate to said Newton being num ber seventy-six, second class; also, on the 27th day of Janua<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="707" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="37" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ry, 1849, was audited in favor of Tilly &#38; Hewitt, for services rendered in the army of the late Republic of Texas, by F. Ballard, J. Thomas, J. N. Dalton, and P. Rice, in the year 1845, amount<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing to three hundred and nineteen dollars, the certificate being number seventy-five, second class; therefore.</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Auditor of the State of Texas be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Samuel G. Newton &#38; Co., and Tilly &#38; Hewitt, or their legal representatives, duplicate certificates for said claims when called for; provided, however, that the said Samuel G. Newton &#38; Co., and Tilly &#38; Hewitt, or their legal repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives, shall first give to said Auditor a bond in double the amount of their respective claims, with good and sufficient security, conditioned that the original certificates shall never hereafter be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />come a charge against the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Jan. 24, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act changing the name of George North to George Douglass Bigelow.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the name of George North be, and the same is here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by changed to George D. Bigelow.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That Israel Bigelow be, and he is hereby authorized and empowered to adopt the said George Doug<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lass Bigelow as his son, and that such adoption shall confer upon the said George all the rights and privileges of his own child, with full capacity of inheriting from the said Israel.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Jan. 24, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="708" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="38" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER L.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution authorizing the Comptroller of the State of Texas to exchange some of the public property in the City of Austin for a certain lot and buildings adjoining the General Land Office.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller of the State is hereby authorized and empowered to purchase with so much of the public property as may be necessary, a certain lot of ground and houses adjacent to the General Land Office, and dispose of said buildings so as to have them removed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this joint resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Jan. 24, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of the heirs of Wm. S. Tuten.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, William S. Tuten, a soldier in the late Republic of Texas, entered the army on the 7th day of May, in the year 1836, and died while in the service during the same year; and whereas, his heirs have never received the quantity of land to which he was entitled as his head-right; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized to issue to the heirs of William S. Tuten a head-right certificate for one-third of a league of land, which certificate may be located-upon any of the vacant and unappropri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated lands of this State, and on the return of the field-notes, and the payment of the government dues, shall be patented as in other cases provided for by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this joint resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Jan. 24, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to incorporate the City of Brownsville.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the citizens of Cameron county in the State of Texas, <pb n="709" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="39" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>residing within the limits of that section of territory situated and lying on the left margin of the Rio Grande in the county of Cam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eron aforesaid, formerly a part of the town tract of four leagues of land (ejidos) of the city of Matamoros, in the Republic of Mexico, be, and they are hereby declared a body politic and corpor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ate, by the name and title of the &#8220;City of Brownsville,&#8221; and by that name may sue and be sued, implead and be impleaded in all courts and in all actions and matters whatsoever, and by the same name may, by deed or gift, grant or purchase, hold and dispose of any estate, real or personal, within the limits of said city, for the use of the corporation, and may have a common seal, which they may alter and change at their pleasure, and all the right, title and interest of the State of Texas in and to all the land included within said tract, that was owned by the town of Matamoros, on the 19th day of December, 1836, shall be, and is hereby relinquished to the corporation of the city of Brownsville and their successors in office in trust for the use and benefit of said city; provided, this act shall not impair private rights.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That said corporation shall have power to sell and alienate any portion of the lands owned by the said corporation, and appropriate the proceeds thereof to the erection of a substantial jail and courthouse for the use of the county of Cameron, and the balance shall be appropriated for the purpose of education within said city, and for no other pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poses; provided, that no part of said land shall be sold or alien<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated until notice of such sale or alienation be given, by publish<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the same in some newspaper printed in said city of Browns<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ville, for at least sixty days previous to the day of sale, or alien<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of said land.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That there shall be the following officers for said city, to wit: One Mayor, nine Aldermen, forming the city council, one of whom shall be chosen to preside, one treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer, one city marshal, and as many subordinate officers not herein mentioned, for preserving the peace and well ordering the affairs of the city, as the city council shall direct and the mayor approve; the city council shall be the judges of the validity of the selection of all officers chosen under this act. The treasurer and city mar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />shal shall give good and sufficient security, in such form, man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner, and amount as the city council shall direct, subject to the approval of the mayor and aldermen. After the first election, [the mayor and aldermen] shall be elected for one year, and all other officers elected or appointed under this charter, shall hold their offices for one year, unless sooner removed, and shall, before <pb n="710" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="40" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>entering upon the discharge of the duties of their respective offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ces, respectively take the oath required by the constitution of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the city council shall have full power to make and pass such by-laws and ordinances as they shall deem necessary to maintain the cleanliness and salubrity of said city, to ensure the safety and convenience of passing in the streets, squares, ways, alleys; to fix the squaring and prevent any encroach<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment or other undertakings on the same; to determine the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pletions and dimensions in the said streets and ways, at the cost of the proprietors of houses, lands or neighboring lots; to regulate the wharves, levies or landing places along the bank of the river; to erect a hospital for the sick, and to appoint a physician for the same; to provide for the maintenance of indigent citizens unable to support themselves; to establish and regulate such common schools as they may direct; to borrow money for the use of the cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration; to organize and regulate a fire department for the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose of extinguishing and preventing conflagrations; to establish and determine fire limits in said city; to prevent the storage of gunpowder within the limits of said city in such quantities as to en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />danger the public safety; to establish an active system of inspection over the conduct of slaves; to provide for the lighting of streets; to permit or forbid theatres, shows or other public amusements; to close play-houses or places for shows or exhibitions whenever the preservation of order, public safety or tranquility shall require it; to establish one or more market places; to determine the mode of inspection of all eatables offered for sale in the market or other public places; to regulate everything relative to butchers, bakers, tavern-keepers, tippling houses, bowling saloons, billiards, dray<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men, horse-drivers, water-carriers, hucksters, hawkers and pedlers, and slaves employed as day laborers; to fix the salary of draymen, horse-drivers and water-carriers, and to make other regulations which may contribute to the better administration of the affairs of such corporation, as well as for the maintenance of the public tranquility and safety of the said city.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the mayor to convene the council whenever he shall deem it neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary, and to recommend such measures as he may deem proper for the public weal; to nominate for the council such subordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nate officers as may be authorized to be appointed by said council; to grant licenses to such persons as the council may direct; to approve or disapprove all ordinances, by laws and regulations which said council may pass; and for this the council shall cause <pb n="711" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="41" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>all acts, ordinances, by-laws and resolutions, as soon as they shall be passed, to be placed before said mayor, and the said mayor shall approve or disapprove the same within three days after the same shall be so placed before him: If the mayor approves, he shall return the same approved to the council; if he disapproves, he shall return the act, ordinance, by-law or resolution, with the rea<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son of his disapproval, to the council, and the said act shall not thereafter become a valid act, unless after its return [it] be read, together with the disapproval that accompanies the said act, ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nance, by-law or resolution, and then be passed by a vote of two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds of said council. If the mayor do not return any act, ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nance, by-law or resolution within three days as aforesaid, the same shall be deemed approved.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That a majority of the whole number of aldermen councils elected shall constitute a quorum for transacting business except in case a tax is to be levied, when a vote of two-thirds shall be required.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That the city council of the city of Brownsville shall have and exercise the power of laying and levy<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing taxes upon all subjects of taxation within their corporate lim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />its upon which a tax may be levied by the State, as may be deemed necessary; provided, said tax shall not exceed in any one year one half of the amount of the tax levied by the State upon such sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jects of taxation; and provided, also, that such tax shall be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />portioned in the same manner as the State tax, and the city treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer or collector of taxes shall have the same power to enforce the collection of such taxes as may be imposed in said city, as the as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sessor and collector of each county has for its collection of the State and county taxes.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That whenever it may be deemed necessary to open, alter, close or change any public road or street in said city, under the provisions of this act, it shall be the duty of the city council to give thirty days notice, by publi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cation in one or more newspapers in the city of Brownsville, in the English and Spanish languages, requiring all persons having objections to the opening, altering, closing or changing of such road or street, to make their objections in writing on or before the expiration of said thirty days notice; and if after such objec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions have been received and considered, it shall appear to the city council that such opening, altering, closing or changing of such street or road is necessary, they shall proceed to appoint viewers, whose numbers, qualifications and duties shall be the same as are now laid down by the law regulating roads; and upon receiving their report, the city council shall proceed to open, <pb n="712" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="42" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>alter, close or change said public road or street, according to the powers and restrictions conferred and imposed by this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That the first election of city officers under this charter, shall be held as soon as may be after the passage of this act, by the Chief Justice of the county of Cam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eron issuing his writs to two persons residing in the limits of this corporation, directing them to hold polls at two different places in said corporation, and to act as presiding officers; to appoint judges and clerks to assist in the election, who shall be sworn to faithfully conduct the election according to the provisions of this act. And said presiding officers shall post up notices [in] each [ward] in three public places within said city limits at least seven days before the election, of the time and place of holding the same; the polls for this purpose shall be opened at 9 o&#8217;clock, A. M., and closed at four o&#8217;clock, P. M., allowing an adjournment of one hour from noon. And after counting the votes in the presence of the judges, shall seal up true lists of the same, and deliver them to the Chief Justice aforesaid within three days after such election has been holden, and said Chief Justice shall thereupon give a cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate to the officers elected, who shall be empowered thereby to enter upon the duties of their respective offices, according to the provisions of this act; and that from and after the first election, all elections for charter officers&#8212;except to fill vacancies&#8212;shall be holden on the second Monday in December annually; and it shall devolve upon the city council to decide upon the time and places of keeping open the polls, always giving ten days notice of each election, by posting advertisements in each ward, and by publica<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion in English and Spanish languages, in at least one newspaper printed in the city of Brownsville. And in case of vacancy of any of the officers which are filled by election under this act, the city council shall order an election in the manner aforesaid to fill such vacancy; and the officers first elected under this act shall hold their offices until the first Monday in January, eighteen hundred and fifty-one, or until their successors are duly qualified; and the Aldermen or city council chosen at the first election, shall lay off the city into three wards, containing as nearly as may be an equal number of voters in each ward; and each ward shall at every annual election hereafter be entitled to elect three Aldermen, and the three persons in each ward receiving the highest number of votes for Aldermen shall be elected.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That the city council, subject to the approval of the Mayor, shall determine the compensation of the Mayor, Treasurer, City Marshal and all subordinate officers.</p>
<pb n="713" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="43" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 11. Be it further enacted. That no election shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tested by any person, unless within ten days after holding the same; and the person intending to contest shall cause the person haying a certificate of election to be notified thereof, at least three days before the time he intends to appear and contest the election, and shall cause a statement in writing to be delivered to him by the city Marshal or his deputy, stating the grounds upon which he re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lies to sustain the contest. And in case the candidate elect cannot be found, then the notice and statement to be left at his usual place of residence. No ex parte testimony shall be received as evidence in any contested election, without the consent of the opposite party; and in all cases of contested elections, the Mayor and city council shall have power to settle all questions relative to the legality and number of voters thereon, and decide upon the candidate entitled to a certificate of election.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Be it further enacted, That no person shall be eligible to any office in this corporation, or entitled to vote for city officers, unless he be a citizen of this State, and shall have resided in the corporate limits of the city for at least six months next preceding the election.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 24, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Richard B. Jarmon.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office of the State, be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Richard B. Jarmon, a patent for one-third of a league of land, on the head-right certificate of John D. Raines, the same having been located in Gonzales county, and surveyed by Arthur Swift, deputy surveyor of Gonzales county, as per field-notes returned to the General Land Office, and marked (file 360, Gonzales county, first class,) survey number 41, in class 7, of one third of a league.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 25, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="714" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="44" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of Elizabeth Hart.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the Commissioner of Power and Hewetson&#8217;s Colony, now Refugio county, did on the 28th day of December, in the year 1834, grant to the said Elizabeth Hart, one league of land, and issued a title therefor; and whereas, the said title is incomplete, and insufficient in law to ascertain by the field notes the identity of the land intended by the Commissioner to be granted to the said Elizabeth Hart; and whereas, the Constitution of the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public of Texas, plainly and expressly declared that every head of a family who emigrated to Texas as a colonist, previous to the revolution, shall be entitled to one league and labor of land; and the said Elizabeth Hart being within this proviso of the Constitution and laws; in order to secure to her and her heirs their constitutional rights; therefore,</p>
<p>Section. 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to cancel the title now of rec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ord in the said General Land Office of this State, issued to Elizabeth Hart on the 28th day of December, in the year 1834, by the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of Power and Hewetson&#8217;s Colony, and in place thereof issue to said Elizabeth Hart, a certificate for one league of land.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That the certificate so issued may be laid on any vacant and unappropriated land in this State, and that the Commissioner of the General Land Office is hereby directed to issue a patent for said land, when located, surveyed, and the field notes returned to his office, as in other cases of valid claims.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further resolved, That this joint resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 25, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of General Memucan Hunt.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Auditor and Comptroller of the State, are here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by authorized and required to issue to General Memucan Hunt, <pb n="715" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="45" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>a certificate, or certificates for sixteen thousand two hundred and fifty-seven dollars, and eighty-six cents; provided, that the said Hunt shall have the right to surrender this claim or any part there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />of, before the Auditor and Comptroller, and on presentation of their certificate of the fact to the Commissioner of the General Land Office, receive land certificates at the rate of fifty cents per acre therefor, in quantities not less than three hundred and twenty acres each.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the said certificate, or cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates shall entitle the said Hunt, to all the rights and privileges to which any other creditor of the Republic of Texas is entitled who has filed his claim, and received a certificate or certificates therefor under the act of the Legislature, approved March 20, 1848, entitled an act to provide for ascertaining the debt of the late Republic of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 25, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of Joseph Branham.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Sec. 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Joseph Branham, a cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate for one-third of a league of land, as his head-right.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That said land certificate when issued shall entitle the said Joseph Branham to have surveyed on any of the vacant and unappropriated lands of this [State,] one third of a league of land, upon the same conditions that certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cates issued by virtue of the twentieth section of the land law of Texas, in the year eighteen hundred and thirty-seven.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further resolved, That this joint resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 26, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="716" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="46" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Uzziel Baggett.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Uzziel Baggett, be, and he is hereby entitled to the following described parts of two sections of land, namely: the north half of section number twenty-five, and the south half of section number twenty-four, the same lying in township three south, range two west, in Peter&#8217;s colony; provided, however, that the said Uzziel Baggett, shall be required to take the oath, and make the same proof as other emigrants to said colony, are required to make, in re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lation to the emigration and settlement in said colony.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 26, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of Araminta D. Allen, heir at law of Preston P. Allen, lately a soldier in the army of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Araminta D. Allen, heir at law of Preston P. Allen, a certificate for one-third of a league of land.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That the said land certificate when so issued, shall entitle the said Araminta D. Allen, or her assignee to have surveyed on any of the vacant and unappropri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated land of this State, one-third of a league of land, upon the same conditions that certificates issued under the twentieth section of the land law of Texas, in the year eighteen hundred and thirty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />seven.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further resolved, That this joint resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 26, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="717" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="47" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to legalize the headright certificate of Simon P. Barnes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorised and required to issue a patent for three hundred and twenty acres of land, on the certificate issued to said Barnes, by the Board of Land Commissioners of Shelby county, dated fifth of April, 1843.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 26, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Mason W. Cope.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Mason W. Cope, a patent for nine hundred and sixty acres of land survey<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed by virtue of bounty certificate, number three thousand eight Hundred and fifteen, issued by George W. Hockley, Secretary of War, dated on the eleventh day of June, in the year eighteen hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and thirty-five, and granted to W. F. Gray as assignee of D. L. Kokernot, to the said Mason W. Cope as assignee of said W. F. Gray.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That, said patent shall issue when said Gray pays the land dues and fees required by law, and not before; and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 26, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to incorporate the Bexar Manufacturing Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Nathaniel Lewis, John D. Groesbeck, Bryan Cal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lahan, C. J. Cook, John Bowen, F. Gilbeau, Thomas J. Devine, F. L. Paschal, Richard Burdsall, J. H. Beck, Samuel A. Maverick and William Vance, or such of them, or such other person as may <pb n="718" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="48" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>hereafter be associated with them, are hereby created a body cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate, by the name of the &#8220;Bexar Manufacturing Company;&#8221; and by that name my sue and be sued; may plead and be im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleaded; may transfer their rights by succession or assignment; and also, by that name and style, they and their successors may purchase, hold and convey real and personal estate.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That said company shall have the right to erect and establish in the county of Bexar, machinery and establishments for the manufacture of cotton and wollen goods, or such other articles, as said company may at any time manufacture for sale.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the capital stock of said company, shall be fifty thousand dollars, to be divided into five hundred shares of one hundred dollars each; and said company shall have authority to increase said capital to one hundred and fifty thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the affairs of said company, shall be managed by a board of five Directors, each of whom shall own at least five shares of the capital stock of said company; a majority of said directors shall constitute a quorum to do business, and shall have power to appoint a President from their own num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber, and to fill all vacancies that may occur in the board of directors, from death, resignation or otherwise, after the first election of directors by virtue of this act; all subsequent elections shall be held at the city of San Antonio, on the first Monday in January of each year: in case of failure to elect said directors at the time and place specified in this act, the corporation shall not be dissolved for that cause, but the President and directors previously elected shall continue to perform their duties, until their successors are chosen.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the directors shall be chosen by the stock holders of said company, and that each stock-holder shall have one vote for each share that he may own, and may vote in person or by proxy.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the President and Directors of said company shall have full authority to adopt all such rules, regulations and by-laws as they may consider necessary to effect the objects of this act of incorporation, not inconsistent with this act or the laws of this State; and may appoint and remove at their pleasure, all agents or other employees necessary to transact the business of said corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That every person subscribing for any of the capital stock of said company, shall pay such pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />portion thereof at the time of subscribing, as may be directed by <pb n="719" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="49" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the terms of the original subscription list, and after the election of the first board of directors, the balance shall be paid at such times and upon such terms as said directors may designate; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that in all cases, when further payment may be required, notice thereof shall be given by advertisement in the nearest news<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />paper at least ninety days before the time of said payment.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That if any stock-holder, shall fail or refuse to pay the balance of his subscription at the time required by said directors, it shall be lawful at any time after due notice and advertisement has been made in accordance with the preceding section of this act, for said directors to sell the shares of said stock-holder at public auction, after ten days previous notice of said sale has been given by public advertisement; and the purchaser of said shares, shall be subject to all the liabilities and entitled to all the benefits of the defaulting stockholder.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That all suits instituted against said company, the service of process upon the President or upon either of the directors, shall be sufficient notice.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That this act shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 26, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of J. F. Brown and Lyman Tarbox.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, J. F. Brown and Lyman Tarbox, mail contractors on route No. from Houston to Austin, in this State, were bound by their contract to transport the mail but twice a week on said route; and whereas, the said Brown and Tarbox have, at their individual expense, transported the mail on said route each al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ternate day in four horse coaches, during the present sessoin of the Legislature, thereby greatly facilitating the transmission of intelligence to and from the capital of this State, during the ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion of the Legislature; therefore.</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That our Senators in the United States Congress, be, and they are hereby instructed, and our Representatives requested to use their exertions to procure an appropriation by the United States Congress, for the payment of Messrs. Brown and Tarbox fur such additional mail service, as the said parties may prove to have been performed.</p>
<pb n="720" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="50" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this joint resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 26, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of B. C. Johnson, assignee of John F. Stacy.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a patent for fifty-six and one-half acres of land, on field notes No. 776, from Bed River county, to B. C. Johnson, assignee of John F. Stacy, upon his filing in the General Land Office the proper field notes, with a regular transfer from said Stacy.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 26, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Amos Morrill.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Calaway Davis was a resident citizen of Texas at the date of the Declaration of Independence, entered the service of the same in May, 1836, and married in 1837, by which he became entitled to one league and one labor of land; and where<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />as, the said Davis conveyed by deed, duly authenticated on the 26th day of March, 1840, said land, by which deed Amos Morrill became entitled to the same, which he has never received; there&#38;&#38;&#38;fore.</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commisioner of the General Land Office of the State, be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Amos Morrill, as assignee of said Calaway Davis, a certificate for one league and labor of land, to be located and patented in the same manner as other first class certificates.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 26, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="721" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="51" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to establish and incorporate a Literary Institution, under the supervision and control of the Eastern Texas Annual Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ference, located at or near the town of Henderson, Rusk county, in this State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That an institution of learning, be, and the same is hereby established, at or near the town of Henderson, in the county of Busk, to be denominated &#8220;The Fowler Institute,&#8221; under the super<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vision and control of the Eastern Texas Annual Conference, of the Methodist Episcopal Church South.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the following persons have been duly chosen Trustees of said institute, by the said Confer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ence, and are recognized as such, to wit: William H. Estil, Samuel McClarty, Emory Lloyd, Winship S. Poe, Charles Lewis, William H. Johnson, James Smith, William Haweth and Martin H. Wads<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />worth.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the Trustees aforesaid, be, and they are hereby constituted a body politic and corporate in deed and in law, and by the name of the President and Trustees of the Fowler Institute, under the supervision and control of the Eastern Texas Annual Conference, of the Methodist Episcopal Church South; and by that name they and their successors in office, shall and may be able and capable in law, to have and receive, to hold and use all lands and tenements, moneys and hereditaments of any kind in fee or for life, or for years, for the use and benefit of the said Eastern Texas Annual Conference, of the Methodist Episcopal Church South; and also, personal property, of any kind whatsoever; and also, all sums of money which may be given, granted or bequeathed to them for the purpose of promoting the interest of said institution; provided the amount of property owned by said corporation, shall not at any time exceed one hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred thousand dollars&#8212;over and above the buildings, library and apparatus necessary for the institute.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the Trustees of said in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute, shall have a stated meeting of the board each year at the time of conferring degrees, and that the President of said board, shall have power to call an occasional meeting of the board, when<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever it shall to him appear necessary.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the Trustees of said in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute may and shall have a common seal for the business of themselves and their successors in office, with liberty to change and alter the same from time to time, as they shall think proper; <pb n="722" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="52" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and that they, by their aforesaid name, and their successors in office may, and shall be able to sue and be sued, plead and be im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleaded, answer and be answered, defend and be defended, in all courts of law or equity in this State; and (by and with the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sent of the said Eastern Texas Annual Conference, of the Meth<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />odist Episcopal Church South,) to grant, bargain, and sell, or as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sign any lands, tenements, goods or chattels, now belonging or that may hereafter belong to said institute, to construct all neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary buildings for the same, and to construct a preparatory depart<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, and such other dependent institutions, as they shall deem necessary; to have the management of the finances, the privilege of electing their own officers, of appointing all necessary com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mittees, and to act, and to do all things whatever, for the benefit of said institute; in as ample a manner as any person or body poli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tic or corporate, can or may do by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the said Trustees, shall have the power of framing and enacting all such ordinances and by-laws, as shall appear to them necessary, for the good govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the institute, and of their own proceedings; provided, the same be not repugnant to the constitution and laws of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That the head of this institute shall be styled the President; the instructors employed in it Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fessors, who shall be appointed by said Eastern Texas Annual Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ference; and the President and Professors or a majority of them, the faculty of said institute, which faculty shall have the power of enforcing the ordinances and by-laws adopted by the Trustees of said institute, for the government of the students, by reward<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing or censuring them, and finally by suspending such of them as, after repeated admonition, shall continue disobedient and refract<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ory, until a determination of the Trustees or a quorum of them, shall be had; but it shall be only in the power of the Trustees, or a quorum of them at their stated meetings, to expel any student or students of said institute.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the President and Professors, shall have full power by and with the consent of the Trustees of said institute, to grant or confer such degree or degrees in the arts and sciences to any of the students of said institute, or other persons by them thought worthy, as are usually granted or con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fered in other colleges or seminaries of learning, and to give di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plomas or certificates of the same signed by them, and sealed with the common seal of the Trustees of said institute; to authenticate and pereptuate the memory of such graduations.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That whenever any vacancy <pb n="723" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="53" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>occurs, either by death, resignation or otherwise, in the board of Trustees, such vacancy shall be filled by the appointment of said Conference.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That all necessary sub officers for said institute and board of Trustees, shall be elected by a ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jority of the members of the board of Trustees.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That whenever vacancies shall occur in the Presidency or any of the Professorships of the said institute, the same shall be filled by the said Conference.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Be it further enacted, That the Trustees or a majority of them, by and with the consent of said Conference, shall have the power of fixing the salaries of all the officers and instructors connected with the institute, and of removing any of them for ne<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />glect or misconduct in office; a majority of the board of Trustees concurring in said removal.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. Be it further enacted, That no misnomer of the said institute, shall annul or make void in law or equity, any gift, grant or bequest, made to the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. Be it further enacted, That the President or Profess<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ors of said institute, shall not be eligible to act as Trustee or Trus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tees for the same, and in case any of the Trustees shall hereafter be employed to discharge any of the duties of those functionaries, to wit: Professors in said institute, he or they shall resign their station of Trustee, before entering on the duties assigned them.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. Be it further enacted, That when any law, rule or resolution, may be passed by the board of Trustees at a regular or stated meeting of said board, it shall not be competent for a called meeting of said board to repeal or recind such law, rule or resolu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, unless there is a full board present.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 26, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the benefit of the heirs of James Ury, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, James Ury joined the army of Texas in the year 1842, under the command of General Somervelle, and was killed in the battle of Mier; and whereas, the said Ury was entitled to three hundred and twenty acres of land at the time of his <pb n="724" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="54" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>death, by authority of an act entitled an act to extend to late emigrants or those who may emigrate within a specified time a donation of land, approved January 4th, 1838; and whereas, the said Ury had not at the time of his death, received of the government of Texas the land to which he was entitled as a citizen, nor has any one ever received the same in his name; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commisioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a certificate for three hundred and twenty acres of land to the heirs or legal representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives of James Ury, which may be located upon any of the unap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated lands in Texas, subject to the same fees of office as other certificates; and that this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 28, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of the Heirs of William Arnold, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to the heirs at law of William Arnold, deceased, an unconditional certificate for six hundred and forty acres of land, and to issue a patent thereon, after the same shall have been legally surveyed and located on any of the vacant lands of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this joint resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 28, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act legalizing and confirming the marriage of William Pear<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son and Elizabeth Ogle.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the marriage of William Pearson and Elizabeth Ogle, now Elizabeth Ledbetter, be, and the same is hereby de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="725" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="55" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>dared legal and valid to all intents and purposes; and that the issue of the said William and Elizabeth Pearson, are hereby de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clared legitimate children, and capable of inheritance.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 28, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act authorizing the Comptroller to issue duplicates of certain certificates.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller, be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Charles Shearn, duplicates of certain cetrifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cates issued to him by the late Republic of Texas, for supplies fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nished the army; which certificates were lost in the wreck of the steamship New York.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 28, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of Berry W. Perkins.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Berry W. Perkins a certificate for six hundred and foty acres of land, to be located on any of the vacant and unappropriated lands of this State, and on the return of the field notes and the payment of the government dues, to issue a patent as in other cases, provided by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this joint resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 28, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="726" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="56" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of the legal representatives of Henry B. Wil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liams, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the G-enearl Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to the legal repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of Henry B. Williams, deceased, a certificate for one<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />third of a league of land, to be located upon any of the vacant and unappropriated lands within this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted. That after the location and the return of survey according to law, and the payment of all the gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment dues thereon, it shall be the duty of the Commissioner aforesaid to issue a patent upon said certificate, in the same man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner as provided by law in other cases.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 28, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of E. H. Grisham.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office of the State be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to E. H. Grisham a certificate for six hundred and forty acres of land, to be located upon any of the vacant and unappropriated public lands within this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted. That upon.the return of the survey and field-notes under the said certificate to the General Land Office, and the payment of all government dues, it shall he the duty of the Commissioner aforesaid to issue a patent thereon, in the same manner as provided by law in other cases.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 28, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of the heirs of Robert Earl, de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Robert Earl emigrated to the State of Coahuila and Texas in the year 1831; and whereas, the said Robert Earl <pb n="727" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="57" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>was entitled under the colonization law then in force, to one league and labor of land, or any part thereof; and whereas, neither the widow nor heirs of the said Robert Earl have since received the said land to which the said Robert Earl was enti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tled; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby required to issue to the heirs of Robert Earl, deceased, a certificate for one league and labor of land, to be located on any of the vacant and unappropriated lands of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted. That when said certificate is lo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cated and the land surveyed and the field-notes returned to the General Land Office, and payment of government dues in accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance with law, it is hereby made the duty of the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue a patent thereon.</p>
<p>See. 3. Be it further enacted, That this joint resolution take effect and he in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 28, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to declare John James Elliott the legitimate child of Wil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liam Elliott and Polly Elliott, of the county of Rusk.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That John James Elliott be, and he is hereby declared to be the legitimate son of William Elliott and Polly Elliott, of the county of Busk, with full rights and qualifications to take prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty by inheritance or otherwise, from, by or through his said parents, or any other person, in the same manner as other chil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dren of his said parents begotten in lawful wedlock.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 28, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend an act entitled &#8220;an act to incorporate the city of Nacogdoches,&#8221; approved March 16th, 1848.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the second section of the above recited act be, and the <pb n="728" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="58" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>same is hereby amended so as to read as follows, to wit: The limits of said corporation shall be one square mile, of which the court<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />house shall be the centre; the boundary lines of said corporation to be run and plainly marked by a competent surveyor, whom said corporation may employ for that purpose, and whose fees shall be the same as are provided for by law, to be paid out of any funds in the treasury of the corporation not otherwise appropriated.</p>
<p>See. 2. Be it further enacted. That the fourth section of said act shall he amended so as to read as follows: The election under this act shall he held on the first Mondays of April in each of every year; the first election after the passage of this act to he held under the direction of the Chief Justice of the county of Nacog<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />doches, or in case of his absence or inability to act, by any two County Commissioners, after giving ten days notice thereof; and thereafter said election shall be held under the direction of the Mayor, at least ten days prior to the expiration of his term of office, and that in case of death or resignation, the vacancy shall he filled by new elections.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That all after the word corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration,&#8221; in the fifth line of the sixth section of the above recited act be, and the same is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That all laws and parts of laws conflicting with the provisions of this act be, and the same are hereby repealed, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 28, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of A. Balleuill.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office of the State be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to A. Balleuill a certificate for six hundred and forty acres of land, to be located on any vacant and unappropriated lands within this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted. That upon the return of the survey and field-notes under said certificate to the General Land Office, and after the payment of all government dues, it shall be the duty of the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue <pb n="729" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="59" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>a patent thereon, in [the] same manner as provided [for] by law in other cases.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 28, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolntion for the relief of the heirs of R. W. Balentine.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, satisfactory evidence has been received that R. W. Balen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tine fell in the massacre of the Alamo, on the 6th day of March, 1836, and that he was entitled to 640 acres of land as a dona<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, 1920 acres as a bounty, and 1476 as his head-right, and that he has never received the above amount of land, or any part thereof; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby anthorized and required to issue certificates for the above amount of lands, to the heirs or legal representatives of R. W. Balentine, and on return of field-notes and payment of govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment dues, patents to issue as in other eases provided by law, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 28, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of George Washington Sheet.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to George Washing<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton Sheek a certificate for three hundred and twenty acres of land.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 28, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="730" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="60" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of John Hobson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to John Hobson a certificate for two-thirds of a league of land, to be located on any of the vacant and unappropriated lands of the State, and on the return of the field notes, and the payment of the government dues, to issue a patent as in other cases provided by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this joint resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 29, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to incorporate the town of Tyler, in Smith county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas. That the citizens of the town of Tyler, in Smith county, he, and they are heerby declared a body politic and corporate, under the name and style of the corporation of the town of Tyler, and by that name shall have power to sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, and to hold and dispose of real and personal property; provided such real property is situated within the limits of said cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration.</p>
<p>See. 2. Be it further enacted, That it shall he the duty of the citizens of said corporation to elect a Mayor, eight Aldermen, a Collector and a Constable; and a Treasurer and Secretary shall be selected by said Aldermen from their own body; the Treasurer and Collector being required to give bond with security, to be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved of by the presiding officer, for the faithful performance of their duties, and to make reports when required by the Mayor or board of Aldermen. And the Mayor shall have power when neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary to suppress riots and disturbances, and to call out the citizens of said corporation for the purpose of restoring order.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the first election shall he held under the direction of the Chief Justice of said county, af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter having given ten days notice thereof, and annually afterwards under the direction of the Mayor, at least ten days before the expiration of his term of office; and that in ease of death or resig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nation, the vacancy or vacancies shall be filled by new elections, to be ordered by the Mayor; and in case the office, of May<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="731" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="61" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>or shall be vacant, then the Aldermen shall elect one of their own body to act as Mayor until the next annual election.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That no person shall he eligible to any office under the provisions of this charter, who is not a citizen of this State, and a resident within the limits of the incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration, nor shall any person have a right to vote for officers who is not a citizen and resides within its limits.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the Major and Board of Aldermen of said corporation shall have power to pass such rules and ordinances as may he necessary for the regulation of the po<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lice and the preservation of order within the corporation limits; to levy taxes for the removal of nuisances and keeping the streets in good order; and to prescribe penalties for the violation of the ordinances and by-laws of the corporation; provided, that in no ease such penalty shall exceed one hundred dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the limits of said corporation shall extend over one hundred acres of land in a square, laid off so as to leave the public square of said town of Tyler in the center of said corporation limits.</p>
<p>See. 7. Be it further enacted, That the Mayor, with a majority of said Aldermen, shall constitute a quorum for the transaction, of business; and shall enact and enforce such rules and regula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions as they may deem necessary for the government of said corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration; provided the same do not conflict with the constitution and laws of this State.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 29, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of Zebulon M. Porter.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a certificate for three hundred and twenty acres of land to Zebulon M. Porter, and on the return of the field-notes and the payment of the government dues, to issue patent as in other cases provided by law.</p>
<p>See. 2. Be it further resolved, That this joint resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 29, 2850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="732" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="62" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolntion for the relief of Samuel C. Douglass.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Samuel C. Doug<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lass a certificate for one league of land, to be located upon any of the vacant and unappropriated lands of this State, and on the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turn of the field notes, and the payment of the government dues, to issue title as in other cases provided by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this joint resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 29, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act donating to John Neill and James O. Rice one league of land each, for being permanently disabled in the service of the Republic of Texas, and one league of land to the heirs of Hays Covington, who was killed in the service of the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to John Neill, James O. Rice, and the legal representatives of Hays Covington, deceased, a land certificate for one league of land each, which certificate may be located, surveyed and patented in accordance with the laws now in force regulating the same.</p>
<p>See. 2. That this act shall he in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Jan. 31, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of John W. Little.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized and required to issue a certificate to John W. Little for six hundred and forty acres of land, which certificate may be loca<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="733" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="63" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ted on any of the vacant and unappropriated lands of the State of Texas, and that this joint resolution take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Feb. 1, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Cain F. Brush, a soldier in the army of the Republic of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized to issue to Cain F. Brush a certificate for one-third of a league of land, as his head-right, to which said Brush was entitled by virtue of his emigration to the country previous to the first day of August, 1836.</p>
<p>See. 2. That the said certificate may he located, surveyed and patented in accordance with the laws regulating the same, on claims of a like character, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Feb. 1, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of the heirs of Patsey Lewis, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to the heirs of Patsey Lewis, deceased, upon their paying the usual fees and govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment dues, a patent for thirty-five hundred and sixty-two acres of land, that being the residue of a league to which said Patsey Lewis in her life time was entitled, and that this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Feb. 1, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to authorize and require the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue certificates to Wiley Marshall and Edward H. Pitts for three hundred and twenty acres of land.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Wiley Marshall and Edward H. Pitts emigrated to the Republic of Texas previous to the first day of January, <pb n="734" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="64" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>one thousand eight hundred and forty-two, were single men, and over the age of seventeen years, and have continued to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />side in Texas up to this time, and have never received certificates for the headlights, to which they were entitled under the laws of said Republic; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature oi the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office he, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to said Wiley Mar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />shall and Edward H Pitts a certificate for three hundred and twen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty acres of land each, which may be located upon any of the vacant and unappropriated land of this State, and this act shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Feb. 1, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act authorizing the Galveston City Company to change the plan of a certain block of lots in the City of Galveston.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Directors of the Galveston City Company be, and they are in their corporate capacity hereby authorized to change the plan of block number three hundred and nineteen, as marked on the map of said city of Galveston, so that the lots in said block may front eastwardly and westwardly, and that the alley through the centre of said block be run north and south, instead of east and west, as now marked out on said map.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Feb. 1, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of Charles Morgan and Robert Rose.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, in the year 1840, the Secretary of the Treasury of the Republic of Texas, in order to extend greater facility to the holders of the liabilities of Texas, for funding the same in the Public Debt of the Republic, did authorize Alden M. Jackson, Collector of customs at Galveston, to receive and cancel such promissory notes, as should be presented, to whom Charles <pb n="735" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="65" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Morgan and Robert Rose, surrendered their promissory notes which were canceled by the said Jackson; and, whereas, the stock to which they were entitled has never issued, tor the rea<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son that said notes were not received at the Treasury Department, until after the period allowed for funding the same had expired; and whereas, the Comptroller and Auditor, acting under the provisions of an act, approved March 20, 1848, issued cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates to the said Charles Morgan and Robert Rose, with the following indorsement on the same: &#8220;the liabilities for which this certificate is given were cut in two, and the word &#8216;canceled&#39; written obliquely across the face; consequently, it will require a special action of the Legislature to place it on the same footing with other certificates issued for a similar character of liabili<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties;&#8221; which said certificate renders the acknowledgement of this indebtedness, of no value to the said Charles Morgan and Robert Rose; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Auditor and Comptroller of Public Accounts, be, and they are hereby authorized and required, on the presentation of certificates number seven hundred and fifty-six, and seven hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and fifty-seven, issued to Charles Morgan, and dated, October 3, 1849; and certificate, number seven hundred and fifty-eight, issued to Robert Rose, and dated, October 3, 1849, to cancel the same, and issue in lieu thereof, certificates as in other cases of lia<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bilities of a similar class.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this joint resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 1, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XC.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of William C. Sparks, assignee of Samuel W. Willis.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to issue a patent to William C. Sparks, assignee of Samuel W. Willis, upon certificate number one hundred and eight-four, for six hundred and forty acres of land, issued by the board of Land Commissioners of Nacogdoches county.</p>
<pb n="736" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="66" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 1, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Francis L. Merriweather and Peter P. Harding.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to issue to Francis L. Merri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />weather and P. P. Harding, each, an unconditional certificate for three hundred and twenty acres of land, which certificates may be located on any of the vacant and unappropriated lands in this State.</p>
<p>See. 2. Be it further enacted, That after the survey shall have been made by virtue of said certificates, and the field notes returned in accordance with law; the said Commissioner of the General Land Office, is hereby authorized and required to issue patents thereon.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 1, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Thomas Garner, assignee of Hiram H. Mil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />leions.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to issue a land certificate for one league and labor of land, first class, to Thomas Gamer, assignee of Hiram H. Milleions, which may be located on any of the vacant and unappropriated lands in this State; and on return of the field notes of the survey, and payment of the government dues, to issue patent as in other eases provided by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 1, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="737" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="67" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution authorizing the Comptroller to make a final set<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tlement with the late Public Printer, for printing the Laws and Journals of the second Legislature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller, be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to settle and close the accounts of the Public Printer of the second Legislature, for the printing of the General Laws and Journals, allowing one-third of a cent per page for an edition of live hundred copies, of seventeen hundred and ninety-one pages of the Journals of the Senate and House; and for an edition of twenty-five hundred copies, of live hundred and seven pages of the General Laws; deducting therefrom the amount heretofore paid for the same, and if any balance shall be found due said publishers, the Comptroller is hereby authorized to draw on the Treasurer for the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That this joint resolution take, effect and be in force from from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution authorizing and requiring the Commissioner of the General Land Office, to issue a certificate to J. H. Singleton, for one-third of a league of land.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to issue a certificate for one<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />third of a league of land, first class, to J. H. Singleton, subject to the same liabilities as to government dues, as other certificates of the same class; and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of the Estate of Lieutenant Lan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sing, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, an accusation has been preferred against J. Platt Lan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sing, deceased, a Lieutenant in the Navy of the late Republic <pb n="738" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="68" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>of Texas, of having been a defaulter in the small arms of the schooner Bernard; and in consequence thereof, the sum of eleven hundred and twenty-five dollars, was charged to his account; and whereas, it appears that such accusation or charge was un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />justly made and is without foundation, and by the evidence of Commodore E. W. Moore, late commander of said Navy, the de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />falcation aforesaid, was duly reported to him by said Lansing; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That said accusation be withdrawn, and that the Adjutant General of the State, be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to make an entry of the same on the account of said Lansing, in the books of the late Auditor of the Republic of Texas, and to credit said account [with] the amount of eleven hundred and twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />five dollars, improperly charged therein, to cover said defalcation; and that the Auditor and Comptroller, be required to audit the account due said Lansing at the time of his decease, to be placed upon the same footing of other claims against the late Republic of Texas.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Daniel Fuller.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby authorized, to issue a certificate to Daniel Puller, for one league and one labor of land, as his headright, to which said Puller is entitled by virtue of his emigration to Texas, previous to the Declaration of Independence with his family.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said certificate may be located, surveyed and pat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ented, in obedience to the laws regulating the same, on first class claims; and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of John Jackson, of Dallas county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That John Jackson of Dallas county, be, and he is here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="739" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="69" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>by entitled to the same quantity of land, that other colonists are, and upon the same terms and conditions, except as to the time of his emigration; and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of the Heirs at law of Joseph Thompson, de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas. That the Commissioner of the General Land Office of the State, be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to issue to the heirs at law, of Joseph Thompson, deceased, a certificate for one league and labor of land, to be located on any of the vacant and unappropriated public lands within this State.</p>
<p>See, 2. Be it further enacted, That upon the return of the field notes and survey under said certificate, to the General Land Office, and the payment of all government dues thereon, it shall be the duty of said Commissioner to issue a patent in the same manner, as provided for by law, in other cases.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted. That this act take effect and he in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to incorporate the Town of Rusk.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the citizens of the town of Rusk, be, and they are hereby declared a body corporate and politic, under the name and style of the corporation of the town of Rusk; and by that name may sue and be sued; implead and be impleaded; and may hold and dispose of real and personal property, within the limits of said corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That it shall he the duty of said citizens, to elect a Mayor, five Aldermen, a Treasurer, a Sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />retary, a Collector and a Constable; the Treasurer and Collector shall make reports, when required by the Mayor&#8217;s warrant, and shall give bond in such a sum as the said Mayor and Aldermen <pb n="740" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="70" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>may think proper, payable to the Mayor and Aldermen of the corporation of the town of Husk, and their successors in office; and the Constable shall perform all the duties required of him by the by-laws of said corporation, and shall give bond as required of said Treasurer and Collector.</p>
<p>See. 3. Be it farther enacted, That the said Mayor, when he shall deem it necessary to suppress riots and disturbances, may call out the posse comitatus of the said town, for the purpose of restoring order.</p>
<p>See. 4. Be it further enacted, That no person shall be eligible to hold any office in said corporation, or to vote for the officers thereof, unless he be a qualified elector as required by the law regulating elections, or shall he a free or householder in said town, and shall actually reside within the limits of said corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted. That the first election shall he held for said officers by the Chief Justice of the county of Chero<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />kee, after having given ten days notice thereof, at the court-house door, and at four of the corner houses in said town, and shall be held annually thereafter by the Mayor, giving at least ten days notice as aforesaid.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That in case of the death or resignation of either the Mayor or any of the Aldermen, the va<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cancy shall be filled by election as aforesaid, to be ordered by the Aldermen or a majority of them; all of whom shall hold their of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fices until their successors are duly qualified.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That it shall he the duty of the Aldermen to pass such rules and ordinances from time to time, for the regulation of the police and preservation of good order within the corporation limits; as they may think necessary; to levy taxes for the removal of nuisances, and for keeping the streets of said town in good repair; and to prescribe the penalties for all of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fences, against the by-laws of said corporation; provided however, that no tax shall be laid, unless by the consent of two thirds of the Aldermen present, and be assessed according to the valuation of property.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That when a meeting is called for the purpose of assessing taxes, the object must he stated in the notice therefor; and said taxes shall not exceed one-half of one per cent in any one year.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That the said corporation of the town of Busk, shall extend half a mile from each boundary line of the public square in said town.</p>
<pb n="741" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="71" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That said corporation shall cause a copy of all their by-laws to be kept in a book for that pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose, which by-laws shall be written in a plain and legible style; and shall be subject to the inspection of the citizens of said town whenever required.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That the said Chief Justice of Cherokee county, shall order the election as required in the fifth section of this act, as soon as he shall be furnished with an ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved copy of the same.</p>
<p>See. 12. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER C.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of James R. Pace.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Treasurer of the State of Texas, be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to pay James R. Pace, the sum of one hundred and twenty dollars, out of any money not other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise appropriated; and that this act take effect and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 2, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to authorize Mrs. Julia Stanton to take the guardianship of her son William Ewing Stanton.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Mrs, Julia Stanton, be, and she is hereby authorized to take the guardianship of her minor son, William Ewing Stanton, on filing in the office of the clerk of the county court of the county in which she resides, a bond with two good and sufficient securities, in such sum as such county court shall direct; conditioned, for the faithful performance of her duties as guardian; and that this act take effect immediately.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="742" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="72" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to authorize the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue a headright certificate to Guy M. Bryan.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Guy M. Bryan emigrated to Texas, some time in the year 1831, and arrived at the age of seventeen years, previous to the first of January one thousand eight hundred and forty, whereby he was entitled to a headright of three hundred and twenty acres of land, under the laws of the Republic of Texas, for which he has never received any certificate: therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby required to issue to said Guy M. Bryan, a certificate for three hundred and twenty acres of land; which may be located on any vacant or unappropriated land in this State; and this act shall take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of Jacob Allbright.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Jacob Allbright, Assessor and Collector of Taxes of Houston county, was robbed on the night of the 4th of Janu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary last, 1849, of one thousand dollars or upwards, of the public moneys belonging to the State of Texas, and of the county taxes, collected for the county of Houston; therefore,</p>
<p>Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the State relinquishes to Jacob Allbright, Assessor and Collector of Taxes of the county of Houston, for the year 1849, the sum of six hundred and sixty-six dollars and sixty-six cents, it being the amount of taxes collected by him for the State, and of which he was robbed on the night of the fourth of January, 1849; and the said Allbright, and his securities are hereby exonerated from the pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the said sum, of six hundred and sixty-six dollars and sixty-six cents, and the Comptroller of public accounts is hereby authorized, to enter a credit in favor of the said Jacob Allbright, for the aforesaid sum of money, by virtue of this Joint Resolution; provided, that the ten per cent reserved by the constitution for educational purposes, be, and the same is hereby required, to be paid into the treasury; and that this joint resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="743" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="73" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Frederick Scranton.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to issue to Frederick Scran<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton, a certificate for seventeen and two thirds labors of land, as an augmentation to which he was entitled by virtue of his marriage, in the year 1839, under the laws then in force regulating the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said certificate may be located, surveyed and pat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ented in obedience to the laws regulating first class claims to land; and that this act be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of Christopher Troute and R. M. Davis.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Christopher Troute and R. M. Davis, have been wounded in fighting the battles of Texas, and thereby permanently dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />abled: therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to issue to Christopher Troute and E. M. Davis, a certificate for one league of land, each; to be located on any of the vacant and unappropriated lands in this State, and upon the return of the field-notes, to issue patents for the same, as in other cases provided by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved. That this joint resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Jonathan Burleson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Jonathan Burleson settled with his family in Texas previous to the revolution thereof, and was thereby entitled to one league and labor of land, of which three fourths of a <pb n="744" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="74" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>league were granted to him under Austin and Williams, through their Commissioner, Robert Peebles, on the sixteenth day of February, 1836; and whereas, said title is considered, void by law, and therefore conveying no right to said Burleson, who has paid all dues and taxes on said lands granted to him as aforesaid; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to issue to Jonathan Burle<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, a patent for three fourths of one league of land; the same known on the map of the land district of Bastrop, as survey num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber twelve, and granted to the said Jonathan Burleson by Robert Peebles, Commissioner of Austin and Williams, on the sixteenth day of February, in the year eighteen hundred and thirty-six.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and he in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of William R. Baker.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to issue a certificate for one third of a league of land, to William E. Baker, assignee of Charles Irwin, and on the return of the field-notes and the payment of all government dues, to issue patent for the same, as in other cases pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided for by law.</p>
<p>See. 2. Be it further resolved, That this joint resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 5th, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint resolution granting the Hon. Fielding Jones. Judge of the Tenth Judicial District, leave of absence from this State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Fielding Jones, Judge of the Tenth Judicial Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="745" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="75" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>trict, shall have leave of absence from this State, from the fifteenth day of May, until the first day of September, in the year eighteen hundred and fifty.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to incorporate Chappell Hill College.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That an institution of learning is established at Danger<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />field, in the county of Titus; it shall be called Chappel Hill Col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lege, and shall be under the control of the Marshall Presbytery of the Cumberland Presbyterian Church.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. There shall he thirteen Trustees, whose duty it shall he to take charge of the interests of the institution, any five of whom, shall constitute a quorum to do business.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. James McReynolds, Mathias Ward, A. H. Lattimer, Al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />len Urguehart, Gen. Record, Thomas Rogers, Pinckney Hill, John Ware, Charles Lewis, William C. Lee, M. Wood, D. L. Rowe and William C. Batt, shall be the first board of Trustees.</p>
<p>See. 4. The Trustees aforesaid, and their successors in office, shall he a body politic and corporate in deed and in law, by the name of the Trustees of Chappel Hill College; and by that name, they and their successors, may and shall have perpetual succession, and be able and capable in law, to have, receive and enjoy to them and their successors, lands, tenements and hereditaments, of any kind, in fee or for life, or for years, and personal property of any kind whatsoever; and also, all sums of money, which may be given, granted or bequeathed to them, for the purpose of promoting the interest of the said College; provided, the amount of property owned by said corporation, shall not at any time exceed two hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. There shall he a stated meeting of the board of Trus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tees, in each year at the time of confering degrees, and that the President of said College, shall have full power to call an occa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sional meeting of the board of Trustees, or a quorum of the same, whenever it shall appear to him necessary.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The Trustees of said College, shall and may have a common seal for the business of themselves, and their successors, with liberty to change and alter the same as they shall think proper; and that by their aforesaid name, they and their successors. <pb n="746" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="76" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>shall and may be able to sue and be sued; plead and be impleaded; answer and be answered; defend and be defended; in all courts of law and equity, in this State; and to grant, bargain and sell, or assign any lands, tenements, goods or chattles, now belonging to said College, or that may hereafter belong to the same; to con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struct all the necessary buildings for said institution, to establish a preparatory department and College proper, as well as such other dependent structures as they shall deem necessary; to have the management of the finances; the privilege of electing their own officers, of appointing all necessary committees, and to act and do all things whatsoever, for the benefit of said institution, in as am<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ple a manner as any person or body politic or corporate, can or may do by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The said Trustees shall have the power of framing and enacting all such ordinances and by-laws, as shall appear to them necessary for the good government of the said College, and of their own proceedings; provided, the same shall not be repugnant to the constitution and laws of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. The head oi such College shall be styled the President, and the instructors thereof, the Professors; and the President and Professors, or a majority of them, the Faculty of Chappel Hill Col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lege; which Faculty shall have the power of prescribing the course of studies to be pursued by the students; of enforcing the ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nances and by-laws adopted by the Trustees for the government of the students, by rewarding and censuring them, and finally by sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pending such of them as after repeated admonitions, shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue disobedient or refractory, until a determination of a quorum of Trustees can be had; but it shall be only in the power of a quo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rum of Trustees to expel any student or students, of the said Col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lege.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. The Trustees shall have full power by the President and Professors of the said College, to grant or confer such degree or de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />grees, in the arts and sciences, to any of the students of the said College, or persons by them thought worthy, as are usually granted or confered in other Colleges; and to give diplomas or certificates thereof, signed by them and sealed with the common seal of the Trustees of the College, to authenticate and perpetuate the memory of such graduations.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. When any vacancy shall occur in the board of Trustees, either by death, resignation or otherwise, such vacancy shall be filled by the Marshall Presbytery of the Cumberland Presbyterian Church.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. The President, Professors and other officers, shall be <pb n="747" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="77" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>chosen by the board of Trustees, subject to the approval of the Marshall Presbytery of the Cumberland Presbyterian Church.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Whenever a vacancy shall occur in the Presidency or any of the Professorships of the College, the said Presbytery shall have the power to fill such vacancy.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. The Presbytery shall have the power, of fixing the salaries of all the officers connected with the College, and of re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />moving any of them for neglect or misconduct in office.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That in the institution hereby incorporated, the stu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dents of all religious denominations shall enjoy equal advantages.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. The said board of Trustees shall at the close of each Collegiate year, make a full report of their proceedings and the condition of said College and the preparatory departments thereof, to the said Presbytery; and that the said Presbytery shall have and exercise general supervision and control over the said board of Trustees; and that the said Presbytery, shall have and exercise full power to remove any member of said board of Trustees; and that any and all vacancies in said board of Trustees, caused by such removal, shall be filled as herein provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. In pleading this act or a right derived therefrom, it shall be sufficient to refer to the same by its title, and the day of its passage; and the court shall thereupon take judicial notice thereof.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Februar 7, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of David Lane, the heirs of Henry L. Lane, deceased, and Wesley Byers.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a patent to David Lane for one league and labor of land, first class certificate, issued by the board of land commissioners of Red River county, on the 13th February, 1838; also a patent to the heirs of Henry L. Lane, deceased, for one-third of a league of land, first class certificate, is<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sued to said heirs by the board of land commissioners of Red River county, on the 14th day of February, 1838; also a patent to Wesley Byers for one league and labor of land, on first class certificate, No. 279, issued to said Byers by the board of land commissioners.</p>
<pb n="748" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="78" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. That the said David Lane, the heirs of the said Henry L. Lane, and Wesley Byers shall be required to pay the customary dues and fees of office, as charged on first class certificates, and that this act be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to incorporate the Galveston. Lodge, Number Three, of the Independent Order of Odd Fellows.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the officers and members of the Galveston Lodge, Number Three, of the Independent order of Odd Fellows, and their successors shall be, and they are hereby declared to be a commu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nity corporation and body politic by the name and style of the Gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veston Lodge Number Three, of the Independent Order of Odd Fellows, and by that name they and their successors shall and may at all. times hereafter, be capable in law to have, receive and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain any estate, real or personal, by gift, purchase, devise, or be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quest, and such estate at their pleasure to transfer and dispose of in such manner as they may think proper; provided, that said cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration shall not at any time hold or possess estate exceeding in value the sum of twenty thousand dollars, nor more than five acres of land; Provided, however, that if any real estate exceeding five acres shall at any time accrue to said corporation, they shall be al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowed the time of one year to sell and dispose of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The corporation, by the name and style aforesaid, shall he capable in law to sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, answer and be answered unto, defend and be defended, in all or any courts of this State, and lief ore all or any judge, officers and persons whatsoever, in all and singular actions, matters and things whatsoever.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The said corporation may have a common seal for their use, and the same at their will and pleasure to change, alter and make anew from time to time as they may think best, and shall in general have and exercise all such rights, privileges and immuni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties as by law are incident to, and necessary to corporations of a similar character, and that this act shall take effect from its pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="749" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="79" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Leoin S. Sargeant.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby authorized to issue a head-right certificate for six hundred and forty acres of land to Leoin S. Sergeant, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of the heirs and legal representatives of John C. Ogden.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby required to issue a head-right certificate to the heirs or legal representatives of John C. Ogden, deceased, a private in the army of Texas, for one-third of a league of land, which may be located upon any vacant and unappropriated lands of this State; and that the Commissioner of the General Land Office be required to issue a patent for the same according to the requirements of law; and that this act be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act requiring the Commissioners appointed by an act entitled an act creating the county of Cherokee, approved April 11, 1846, to deliver up certain documents and moneys therein mentioned.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioners appointed to locate the county seat of Cherokee county by the above recited act, approved April 11, 1846, be, and they are hereby required to deliver up to the Chief Justice and county commissioners, of said county, at the February term of the county court in the year 1850, or as soon thereafter as practicable, all the records, papers, documents and <pb n="750" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="80" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>moneys in their hands, relative to lots in the town of Rusk, in Cherokee county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That said Chief Justice, coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty commissioners, and county clerk of said county of Cherokee, or their successors in office, shall proceed to sell the remaining lots in said town of Busk, and to do and perform whatever may be necessary in finally settling the outstanding business of said town of Busk, for which services the said Chief Justice, county commissioners and county clerk shall be entitled to the same fees as in other similar cases are established by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the Chief Justice shall have power to institute suit on all notes heretofore drawn, and payable to said commissioners for lots in said town of Busk, as fully as though such notes had been executed to him, and that this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 8, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Charles F. Stanly.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby authorized to issue a certificate to Charles F. Stanly for one league and one labor of land, as a head-right to which said Stanly is entitled by virtue of his emigration to the Republic of Texas, with his family, previous to the first day of August, A. D. 1836.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said certificate may be located, surveyed and pat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ented according to the laws regulating first class claims for head<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rights to lands; and that this act take effect and he in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 8, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Greenberry Logan and Joseph Taylor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Greenberry Logan, as an augmentation under the land law of 1837, a certi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="751" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="81" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ficate for three-fourths of one league and one labor of land, and to Joseph Taylor, who was permanently disabled in the service of Texas, a certificate for one league of land.</p>
<p>See. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 8, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of John P. Rosier.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, John P. Rosier joined the army and performed military service in the Republic of Texas prior to the first day of August, 1836, and has received an honorable discharge from the same; and whereas, he has not received the quantity of land to which he is by law entitled; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to John P. Rosier a certificate for eight hundred and thirty-six acres of land, to be located on any of the vacant and unappropriated lands of this State; and on the return of the field, nots, to issue patent for the same, as in other cases provided by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted. That this joint resolution take ef<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fect and he in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 8, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Martha McBride and Margaret Garnett.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Martha Collum, now Martha McBride, and Margaret Jones, now Margaret Garnett, were resident citizens of Texas at the date of the declaration of Independence, and the heads of families of children; and whereas, they have never received the quantity of land to which they are entitled; therefore.</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office of the State be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to for one league and labor of land each, to be located on any of the <pb n="752" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="82" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the said Martha McBride and Margaret Garnett, a land certificate unappropriated public domain, and patented in the same manner as other first class certificates.</p>
<p>See. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 8, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Melville Langham.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Melville Langham a certificate for two-thirds of a league and labor of land, which may be located as now provided by law.</p>
<p>See. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 8, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of William McMasters, late Sheriff of Bra<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zoria county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That William McMasters, late Sheriff of Brazoria county, be allowed the term of one, two, three and four years for the pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the amount due by him to the late Republic of Texas, on his giving satisfactory security to the Comptroller of the State for the payment thereof, in equal annual instalments, together with interest thereon till paid; Provided, that said McMasters shall ren<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der to the Comptroller a true statement under oath, of the amount of his indebtedness to said Republic of Texas, and make a settle<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of his said indebtedness with the Comptroller on or before the first day of August, one thousand eight hundred and fifty; and shall pay all the costs of the suit that has been commenced against him.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 5, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="753" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="83" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to incorporate the Lafayette Academy, in the City and County of Matagorda.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Albert C. Horton, John D. Newell, Felix M. Gib<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, John W. McCalmey, and their associates, never to exceed the number of twelve in all, and their successors in office be, and they are hereby constituted a body politic and corporate, by the name and style of the President and Trustees of the Lafayette Academy, in which name they may sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, answer and be answered, in any court of justice, and to hold, control and dispose of property, real and personal, to any amount not exceeding fifty thousand dollars, for the use and bene<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fit of said Academy.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the members of said corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion may enact such by-laws and elect such officers as to them may seem fit, and as may be necessary to carry on the business, of said corporation, and they shall have full power and authority to establish rules for the said Academy, to appoint and remove or suspend professors and teachers, and that all by-laws enacted by said corporation shall be, to all intents and purposes, binding on the corporation and its members, and of full force and validity for the government of the institution, and shall be altered and amended only by the vote of a majority of the whole Board of Trustees.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 8, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of the heirs and legal representatives of William Wallace, who fell at Goliad, and Nathaniel Dennis, who fell in the service of Texas in 1836.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to the heirs and legal representaives of William Wallace, who fell at Goliad, a cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate for one-third of a league of land; also, a certificate for one-third of a league of land to the heirs and legal representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="754" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="84" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>tives of Nathaniel Dennis, who fell in the service of Texas in 1836, which may be located on any of the public domain of the State of Texas not otherwise appropriated, and a patent shall issue on the same as in other cases.</p>
<p>See. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 8, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of Samuel G. Norvell and William A. A. Wallace.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Samuel G. Norvell and William A. A. Wallace were mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers of Captain John C. Hays&#8217; company for the protection of the frontier, and while serving in said company were taken prisoners and carried to Mexico, and their claims for services have never been audited or paid; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Auditor and Comptroller be, and they are here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by required to audit the claims of Samuel G. Norvell and of Wil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liam A. A. Wallace, for services and losses while they were mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers of said company and prisoners in Mexico, amounting to the sum of six hundred and fifty dollars for Samuel G. Norvell, and Lour hundred and eighty-seven dollars to William A. A. Wallace, and issue to them certificates therefor, in accordance with the provisions of an act to provide for ascertaining the debt of the late Republic of Texas, approved March 20th, 1848, and that this joint resolution shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 8, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of A. H. Cooke and James Smith.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas That the Treasurer be, and he is hereby authorized and required to pay A. H. Cooke the sum of twenty dollars, and James Smith the sum of one hundred and forty two dollars and thirty cents out of any money in the treasury on special deposit, <pb n="755" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="85" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>belonging to the estate of Richard Vaughan, dec&#8217;d, for the pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of his funeral expenses.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Resolved, That this joint resolution take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 8, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to authorize Bartlett Simms to raise a location therein named, and to locate the same on any vacant land.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted By the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Bartlett Simms be, and he is hereby authorized to raise so much of a survey made for said Simms, lying in Bastrop county, as conflicts with a survey made for Jose Antonio Navarro.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Commissioner of the General Land Office is hereby authorized to issue a certificate for the number of acres covered by said conflict, and that it may be located, surveyed and patented on any of the vacant and unappropriated lands of this State; provided, that this act shall not be construed as a legislative expression of opinion in regard to the claim of the said Jose An<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tonio Navarro.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Feb. 8, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of William W. Wallace.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to William W. Wal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lace a certificate for one league and one labor of land, and that said certificate may be located, surveyed and patented according to the laws regulating the same on first class claims, as issued by the Republic of Texas; and that this act be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 8, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="756" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="86" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of the heirs of Tilford Baker.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby required to issue a head right certificate for three hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and twenty acres of land to the heirs of Tilford Baker, de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceased&#8212;that Johnson Wrenbe authorized to receive and locate said certificate for the benefit of said heirs, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 8, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of the heirs at law of Jesse Bledsoe.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a certificate for one third of a league of land to the heirs at law of Jesse Bledsoe, deceased, the same to be located on any of the vacant and unappro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated public domain of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That upon the location, survey and return of said certificate, it shall be the duty of the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner aforesaid to issue a patent thereon, upon the same terms and conditions as required by law in other cases.</p>
<p>See. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 9, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of the heirs and legal representatives of Charles Martin, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Charles Martin, at the time of his death in the year 1835, was a citizen of the municipality of Washington, now comprised in part of the county of Montgomery, in the State of Texas; and whereas, the heirs or legal representatives of said Martin have never received title to the lands to which he was entitled as a citizen of Texas prior to the declaration of independence; there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office he, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to the heirs or <pb n="757" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="87" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>legal representatives of said Charles Martin, deceased, a certificate for one-third of a league of land, upon such heir or legal repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentative producing sufficient proof of his representative capacity; which certificate may he located on any of the vacant and unappro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated domain of the State, and a patent shall issue thereon in obedience to the laws regulating the same on first class claims.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and he in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 9, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to incorporate the Town of Livingston.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the citizens of the town of Livingston, be, and they are hereby declared a body corporate, by the name and style of the corporation of the town of Livingston: and by that name, may sue and be sued; plead and be impleaded; and may hold, and dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose of real and personal estate.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the limits of said corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, shall be one mile square, of which the courthouse of the county of Polk, in the said town of Livingston, shall he the centre.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That an election for Mayor, five Aldermen, a Treasurer, a Recorder and a Constable, shall be held as soon as practicable, after the passage of this act, by the Chief Justice, or one of the Commissioners of Polk county, according to the laws governing elections generally: and annually there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after, for a similar purpose, an election shall be conducted by the Mayor, or a majority of the Aldermen, acting at the time of such election; and the persons elected shall continue in office one year, or until their successors are duly qualified: and the annual election for Mayor and Aldermen shall be held at such place in the town of Livingston, as may be designated by the Board for the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />venience of the people.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That whenever a vacancy shall occur in the office of Mayor, a majority of the Aldermen acting, shall order and conduct an election, to fill such vacancy; and the persons so elected shall hold his office until the next reg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ular election, or until his successor be duly qualified, and in case of the death, resignation or removal of any Alderman, Treasurer <pb n="758" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="88" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>or Constable, the Mayor shall order an election, under such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the board, to fill such vacancy.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That no person shall be eligible to the office of Mayor, Aldermen, Treasurer or Constable, unless such person be a citizen of said town.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted. That the Mayor shall he Pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ident of the hoard of Aldermen, that three of the members of said hoard shall constitute a quorum, to transact business; and that said board shall enact such by-laws for the government of said town, not inconsistent with the constitution and laws of the State, as may be deemed proper; and may impose fines for the infraction or disobedience of the same, not exceeding twenty dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars for such offence.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That the hoard of Aldermen shall have, and exercise control over the public square, and streets of said town, and may compel all free male citizens, ministers of the gospel excepted, over the age of seventeen years and under that of forty-five, to work on the same; provided, that such per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son shall not be required to work more than six days in any one year, and shall be exempt from other road duty, in said county; and the board may impose such fines on defaulters as they may deem necessary, in which they shall be governed by the laws of this State, regulating roads.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the hoard of Aldermen, shall hare power to levy a tax on all persons and property, both real and personal, in said town, subject to taxation by the laws of the State: provided, that the tax on property, shall not in any one year, exceed one-half of one per cent ad valorem, on such property; and no tax shall be levied unless by a vote of two-thirds of the members present; which shall be assessed and collected by the Constable, in the same manner as the State tax is collected.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted. That the hoard of Aldermen, shall have power to appoint such additional officers, with the regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lations of their duties and compensation as may be necessary, and may require of them bond and security, to the mayor in such sum as may be deemed necessary, to compel the efficient discharge of such duties as may be assigned them.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That all offences against the by-laws, be presented before the Mayor, and governed by the laws organizing Justice Courts, and the Constable shall execute, and return all writs, issued by the Mayor, in the same manner as is provided by the law defining the duties of Constables.</p>
<pb n="759" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="89" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That the Constable shall give bond and security as required of other Constables, and shall have the same power, and be entitled to the same fees for similar ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vices.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Be it further enacted, That the Mayor of said town shall be entitled to such fees as may be allowed Justices of the Peace, for similar services, together with such other compensation as may be allowed him by a majority of the Aldermen present, at the time of such allowance.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. Be it further enacted, That the Aldermen shall be entitled to such compensation as may be allowed by a majority of the board; provided, that in no case the sum shall exceed two dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars per day, for each day they may be required to sit as such Aider<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. Be it further enacted, That the Treasurer shall safely keep all the money of said corporation, shall pay out the same upon the order of the board, and shall do such other duty as may be assigned him, by the by-laws; and shall give bond and security payable to the Mayor, in such sum as may be deemed proper, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ditioned for the faithful performance of his duties, to be approved by the board; and shall be allowed such compensation as may be specified by the board of Aldermen.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. Be it further enacted, That the hooks and records of the corporation shall at all times he open for the examination of any citizen of said town.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 9, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to authorize and require the Auditor and Comptroller to audit and allow as a valid claim against the Republic of Texas, a debt contracted to pay the expenses of the Escort for General Santa Anna from Texas to Washington City.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, in the winter of the year, one thousand eight hundred and thirty-six, a note was drawn by Bernard E. Bee and George, W. Hockley, and endorsed by W. H. Patten, W. H. Wharton, Waddy Thompson, F. H. Elmore and William B. Lewis for the sum of fifteen hundred dollars, due the thirtieth day of March, eighteen hundred and thirty-seven; which note was drawn un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="760" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="90" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>der the direction, and by the authority of the government of the Republic of Texas, for the purpose of raising money, to pay the expenses of the Escort of General Santa Anna, from Texas to Washington City, and was subsequently paid by some of the endorsers thereof; and whereas, said endorsers were in no man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner interested in the consideration for which said note was given, and endorsed the same for the purpose of enabling the officers of the Republic of Texas, to raise means through their credit; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Auditor and Comptroller, be, and they are here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by directed, to audit and allow as a valid claim against the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public of Texas the aforesaid note, drawn by Bernard E. Bee and George W. Hockley, and endorsed by W. H. Patten, W. H. Whar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton, W. Thompson, F. H. Elmore and William B. Lewis, for the sum of fifteen hundred dollars, due the thirtieth day of March, one thousand eight hundred and thirty-seven; and that said Au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ditor and Comptroller, be, and they are hereby required to issue a certificate for the amount of said note, with interest thereon, at the rate of eight per cent per annum, from the maturity thereof, in favor of the present holder of said note; which certificate shall be isssued in conformity with the provisions of an act to provide for ascertaining the debts of the late Republic of Texas, approved March 20th, 1848; and shall have the same force and effect as other certificates issued under said act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 9, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend an act entitled an act for the incorporation of the City of Laredo.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the second section of the above recited act, be amended so as to read as follows: that the bounds and limits of said city, and within which the said corporation shall exercise lawful juris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diction, shall include and comprehend all that tract of land origi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nally granted to, and composing said city.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted. That the eighteenth section of the above recited act, be amended so as to read as follows: that no person shall be eligible to any office, nor be entitled to vote for any officer of said corporation, who is not either a householder <pb n="761" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="91" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>or freeholder, within the boundaries of said corporation, and who has not resided therein at least six months previous to such elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion. and paid up his city taxes.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 9, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act authorizing the Commissioner of the General Land Office, to issue headright certificates, fourth class, for three hundred and twenty acres each, to Juan Contreras and Juan Abilo.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to issue head right cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates, fourth class, for three hundred and twenty acres each, to Juan Contreras and Juan Abilo; and that this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 9, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Edward Miles.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a certificate for one third of a league of land to Edward Miles.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That said certificate may be lo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cated on any vacant or unappropriated lands in this State, ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cording to existing laws.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Feb. 9, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of John R. Baker.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Auditor and Comptroller of the State, be, and <pb n="762" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="92" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>they are hereby authorized and required, to audit the account of John R. Baker, for the sum of eight hundred and eighty-nine dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars and fifty cents; the same to be held as a claim against the late Republic of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 9, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of the Heirs of Thomas Weston, deceased, and their assigns.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the State of Texas, did on the first day of June, in the year 1846, by patent, grant to the heirs of Thomas Weston, de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceased, six hundred and forty acres of land, being the donation claim which the said Thomas Weston received from the late Republic of Texas; and whereas, the said land lies upon or near the county line of Bexar county; and wheras, doubts have arisen whether said land is included in the Bexar land district, in which the same was surveyed, or the adjoining district; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the State does hereby relinquish all her right, title and interest, in and to the land described in said patent, to the heirs of the said Thomas Weston, and their assigns, and declare legal and valid said survey; provide this act shall not be construed to the prejudice of any right heretofore acquired in and to the said land.</p>
<p>See. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of Green Iv. Cessna and Nancy K. Cessna.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to issue to Green K. <pb n="763" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="93" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Cessna, and Nancy K. Cessna, each a certificate for six hundred and forty acres of land; which certificate may be located on any vacant and unappropriated lands of this State, and upon the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turn of the field-notes and the payment of all government dues, to issue patent as in other cases provided for by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further resolved, That this joint resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act making an appropriation of land for the payment of Henry P. Brewster and James Webb, for professional services rendered by them in behalf of the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to issue [to] Henry P. Brewster and James Webb, each a certificate for one league and labor of land, for professional services rendered by them on be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />half of the State as follows: Henry P. Brewster in the. cases of Austin and Perry vs. the President, Geo. W. Glasscock vs. Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land Office; James Webb in the cases of James P. Perry, Executor of S. F. Austin vs. The Republic of Texas, James F. Perry, Executor and Samuel M. Williams vs. The Republic of Texas; said certificates to be located on any public domain of the State, free of all expenses except the fees for sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veying.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Robert E. Neill.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be and he is hereby authorized and required, to issue to Robert E. Neill, a certificate for one league of land, which may be located on any of the vacant and unappropriated domain of the State, and when so located and the field notes thereof returned to the General Land Office, the Commissioner thereof, shall issue a pa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="764" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="94" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>tent thereon to the said Neill, or his assignee, upon payment of patent fees and government dues, as in other eases.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXL.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution authorizing the Supreme Court to hold their sessions in the Capital of the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Supreme Court be authorized to occupy either chamber of the Capitol for the purpose of holding their sessions, after the adjournment of the Legislature; and that the Judges be requested to take such measures as may be necessary to prevent the removal from the Capitol, or the destruction of furniture, and for the safe delivery of the same to the superintendent of the Capitol, after the adjournment of the Court.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXLI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution making an appropriation for the purchase of certain books for the use of the Supreme Court.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of one hundred dollars, be, and the same is hereby appropri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated, for the purchase of thirteen volumes of a collection of the laws, decrees, edicts, regulations, etc., of the Supreme and other authorities of the Republic of Mexico, by Basilio Jose Arrillaga, for the use of the Supreme Court of this State; and that the Comptroller, be, and he is authorized to draw his warrant for the said amount, on the certificate of the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court, that he has received said books for the use of said court; and this resolution shall take effect, from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="765" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="95" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to change the name of Jesse Gilliam, to that of Jesse Tar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rant Gilliam.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the name of Jesse Gilliam, an adopted child of Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral Edward Tarrant, be, and the same is hereby changed to that of Jesse Tarrant Gilliam; and by that name the said child, shall be recognized and known in all cases, in which he shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cerned or in any way interested.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Feb. 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of George T. Howard and Duncan. G. Ogden.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of seven thousand three hundred and thirty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />three dollars, with eight years and six months interest thereon, at the rate of eight per cent per annum, being four thousand nine hundred and eighty-six dollars and forty-four cents, the principal and interest amounting together to twelve thousand three hundred and nineteen dollars and forty-four cents, be, and the same is here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by acknowledged to be due from the Republic of Texas to George T. Howard and Duncan C. Ogden, for sundry merchandise fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nished the Santa Fe expedition in the year 1841.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the Auditor and Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller, be, and they are hereby authorized and required, to issue to the said Howard and Ogden, certificates of debt, of the second class, against the said Republic of Texas, for the amount expressed in the first section of this act, in sums of not less than one thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars each.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That George T. Howard and Duncan C. Ogden, be authorized to surrender any portion of such certificates as may be issued under the provisions of ths act, and have the same cancelled by the Comptroller and Treasurer, who shall certify the same under their seals of office to the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner of the General Land Office; whereupon the said Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner of the General Land Office, shall issue to the said Howard and Ogden, land scrip for the same, at fifty cents per acre; to be <pb n="766" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="96" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>located in tracts not less than three hundred and twenty acres each, to be located on any public vacant domain of the State,</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to validate certain patents therein designated.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the State does hereby ratify and confirm, patent num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber one hundred and fifteen, -of the first class, dated August 24th, 1846, for one half of a league of land; patent number three hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and forty-eight dated December 20th, 1847, of the first class, for one league and one labor of land; and a patent for one half of a league of land, dated August 24th, 1848, granted to Francisco Gomez; all of which are surveyed in the district of San Patricio, and west of the Nueces river.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted. That the State of Texas does hereby relinquish all her right to the lands described in said patents, to the grantees, their heirs or assigns; and this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of the Heirs and legal representatives of Willis A. Forris, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby required, to issue a certificate for one league and labor of land, to the heirs or legal representatives of Willis A. Lorris, deceased; and that the same may be located, surveyed and patented, on and to any of the vacant and unappropriated lands of this State; provided however, this act shall only be of force and effect, if the party has not heretofore received his headlight.</p>
<p>Sec 2. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect and he in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approverd, <date>February 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="767" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="97" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXLVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to incorporate the Jasper Cotton Manufacturing Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Abel Adams, John B. Hewett, R. C. Doom, Z. Wil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liams Eddy, Thomas E. Herrington, Barney Lowe, Wm. S. Ney<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />land, Joshua Grant, L. M. Robertson, Thomas Beatty, Wm. S. Reaghis, A. F. Smyth, Wm. Allen and Seymour White, together with their successors and assigns be, and are hereby constituted a body politic and corporate, under the name and style of the Jas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />per Cotton Manufacturing association, with a common seal; and by that name may sue and be sued; plead and be impleaded;an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />swer and be answered unto; to appear, prosecute or defend; to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cover judgment in any court of competent jurisdiction; to elect annually, one Secretary and Treasurer, and nine Directors, each of whom shall own at least one thousand dollars worth of stock in the company, and fix their compensation for conducting the af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fairs of the corporation, and to do and perform all other acts and business that may come within the purview of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted. That the object and business of the corporation shall be the spinning and weaving of cotton and wool, and that it shall have a capital of twenty-five thousand dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars, in shares of one hundred dollars each, with the privilege of in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />creasing said capital to one hundred thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the company in and by their corporate name shall have power to purchase hold and en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />joy, to them and their successors and assigns, all such lands, tene<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments, hereditaments, goods, chattels, and slaves of every kind and description, as shall or may come within the scope and business of the corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the stock property and business of the company shall be under the care and control, management and direction of the said nine Directors, who shall elect from their number a President, to preside over them, and such other officers, agents, and associates, as the by-laws may direct, or the business require; said Directors shall open a book for subscription, and have power to call in, collect and appropri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ate the capital stock of said company, in such installments and at such times and places as they may order, giving such notice as the by-laws may direct, and upon a call for instalment, if a stock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holder neglects or refuses to pay such instalment, within sixty days, from such call and notice thereof, by publication or other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise, the stock of such stockholder shall be sold at public auc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="768" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="98" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>tion, after sixty days notice of the time and place of such sale, has been given by at least three publications in a newspaer, when deducting the amount of such instalment and all expenses of notice and sale, and all that may be due the company from such stock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holder, the remainder if any, shall be paid over to such stock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holder.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That five shall constitute a quorum of the directors when assembled for the transaction of business, and a majority of the stockholders shall be necessary to constitute a meeting of the stockholders for the purpose, and each share shall be entitled to one vote; said Directors shall cause to be made and published certain by-laws; may direct an annual statement of the accounts and business of the corporation; keep and cause to be kept fair books of the whole transaction of the company, and have the same open at all reasonable times, and ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessible for the inspection of the stock-holders, and a neglect or refusal to permit an inspection of the books thereof, by a stock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holder in person or by his attorney in fact, after three days notice in writing, served upon the Secretary, or posted on the door of his company office, shall be a misdemeanor on the part of the said Secretary and all the Directors, for which they shall be liable to fine and imprisonment, by proceeding in the District Court; and on an application of the funds or effects of the corporation by any of the officers or agents thereof, to his, or their own private use, or a wilful misapplication or mismanagement of the business or funds thereof by the Directors shall be a penal offence, and pun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ished as embezzlements are punished by the law of the land.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the stock of said company shall be considered personal property and transferable only on the books thereof, and the company shall have a lien upon all stock and property of a stock-holder, for all debts due to the company by a stockholder.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXLVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of J. B. Hoxie, William C. Harrison and William E. Parker.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to J. B. Hoxie, <pb n="769" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="99" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>a land certificate for one-third of a league of land as a head-right; to William C. Harrison a certificate, for twelve hundred and eighty acres of land, and to William E. Parker a certificate for three hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and twenty acres of land, to he located and patented under the same rules and regulations that govern the locating and patenting of similar claims.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXLVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to change the names of Magdaline Margaret and Robertor W. Simpson, minor daughters of the Rev. James Simpson, to Magdaline Eliza Walker and Robertor W. Walker.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the names of Magdaline Margaret Simpson and Rob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ertor W. Simpson, minor daughters of the Rev. James Simpson, be, and they are hereby changed permanently to Magdaline Eliza Walker and Robertor W. Walker.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXLIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to grant twelve thousand acres of land scrip to Mrs. Sophia J. St. Johns, wife of Samuel J. St. Johns, Jr.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, when the Republic of Texas required funds to assist her in the struggle for independence, Samuel J. St. Johns, Jr., with that zeal for the advancement of liberty, stepped forward to our assistance, and donated to the government at one time five thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars, and another time one thousand dollars, thus ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terially assisting us: therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That as a token of gratitude for services rendered, a cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate for twelve thousand acres of land scrip he issued to Mrs. Sophia J. St. Johns, wife of the said Samuel J. St. Johns, for her <pb n="770" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="100" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>sole use and benefit, and that the Commissioner of the General Land Office be required to issue scrip therefor, to be located on any vacant public land in this State; provided, the same shall be surveyed in tracts of not less than three hundred and twenty acres, and provided, further, said certificates shall not be located upon any previously titled land.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CL.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to incorporate the town of Marshall.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the citizens of the town of Marshall be, and they are hereby declared a body corporate by the name and style of the corporation of the Town of Marshall, and by that name may sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, and may hold and dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose of real and personal estate.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the limits of said corporation shall be one mile square, of which the Courthouse of the county of Harrison, in the town of Marshall, shall be the centre.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That an election for a Mayor, five Aldermen, a Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer, Recorder, and a Constable, shall be held as soon as prac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticable after the passage of this act, by the Chief Justice, or one of the Commissioners of Harrison county, according to the laws governing elections generally, and annually thereafter for a sim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ilar purpose, an election shall be conducted by the Mayor, or a majority of the Aldermen acting at the time of such election; and the persons elected shall continue in office one year, or un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />til their successors are duly qualified. And the annual election for Mayor and Aldermen shall be held at such place in the town of Marshall as may be designated by the board, for the convenience of the people.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That whenever a vacancy shall occnr in the office of Mayor, a majority of the Aldermen acting shall order and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />duct an election to fill such vacancy, and the person so elected shall hold his office until the next regular election, or until his successor be duly qualified; and in case of the death, resignation or removal of any Alderman, Treasurer or Constable, the Mayor <pb n="771" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="101" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>shall order an election, under such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the board, to fill such vacancy.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That no person shall he eligible to the office of Mayor, Aldermen, Treasurer, or Constable, unless such person be a citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zen of said town.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the Mayor shall be President of the Board of Aider<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men; that three of the members of said board shall constitute a quorum to transact business, and that said board shall enact such by-laws for the government of said town, not inconsistent with the constitution and laws of the State, as may be deemed proper, and may impose fines for the disobedience of the same, not exceeding twenty dollars for each offence.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the board of Aldermen shall have and exercise control over the public square and streets of said town, and may compel all free male citizens, ministers of the Gospel excepted, over the age of seventeen years and under that of forty-five, to work on the same; provided, that such person shall not be required to work more than six days in any one year, and shall be exempt from other road duty in said county; and the board may impose such fines on defaulters as they may deem necessary, in which they shall be governed by the laws of this State regulating roads.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That the board of Aldermen shall have power to levy a tax on all persons and property, both real and personal, in said town, subject to taxation by the laws of the State; provided, that the tax on property shall not in any one year exceed one-half of one per cent. ad valorem on such property; and no tax shall be levied unless by a vote of two-thirds of the members present, which shall be assessed and collected by the Constable, in the same manner as the State tax is collected.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That the board of Aldermen shall have power to appoint such additional officers, with the regulation of their duties and compensation as may be necessary, and may require of them bond with security to the Mayor in such sum as may be deemed requisite to compel the efficient discharge of such duties as may be assigned to them.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That all offences against the by-laws be presented be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore the Mayor, and goverened by the law organizing Justices&#8217; Courts; and the Constable shall execute and return all writs issued by the Mayor, in the same manner as is provided by the law de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fining the duties of Constables.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That the Constable shall give bond and security as required of other Constables, and shall have the same powers, and be entitled to the same fees for similar services.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That the Mayor of said town shall be entitled to <pb n="772" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="102" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>such, fees as may he allowed Justices of the Peace for similar ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vices, together with such other compensation as may he allowed him by a majority of the Aldermen present at the time of such allowance.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That the Aldermen shall be entitled to such com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pensation as may be allowed them by a majority of the board; provided, that in no case the same shall exceed two dollars per day for each day they may be required to sit as such Aldermen.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That the Treasurer shall keep safely all the money of said corporation; shall pay out the same upon the order of the board, and shall do such other duty as may be assigned him by the by-laws; and he shall give bond with security payable to the Mayor, in such sum as may be deemed proper, conditioned for the faithful performance of his duties, to be approved by the board, and shall be allowed such compensation as may be specified by the board of Aldermen.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. That the Mayor be, and he is hereby vested with all the power and jurisdiction of a Justice of the Peace within the limits of said corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. That the books and records of the corporation shall at all times be open for the examination of any citizen of said town.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. That all laws and parts of laws contravening the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act be repealed, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Feb. 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to change the name of George Harrell to GeorGe W. Gibbs.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the name of George Harrell be, and the same is here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by changed to that of George W. Gibbs, and that he is hereby de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clared the heir at law of Elhanan W. Gibbs, of the county of Pa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nola, and capable of inheriting his property in the same manner as if he was an heir by descent.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Feb. 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="773" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="103" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution authorizing R. J. Neighbors, the commissioner appointed to organize the Counties of Presidio, El Paso, Worth and Santa Fe, to draw his salary in advance.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Treasurer is authorized and required to pay to R. Neighbors the sum of five hundred and fifty dollars, the amount of his salary as commissioner to organize the new counties on the Rio Grande and Santa Fe, in advance; and that this joint resolu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of Brown and Tarbox.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Lyman Tarbox and J. F. Brown, mail contractors on route No.; and whereas, the said Brown and Tarbox con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyed said mail each alternate day during the last session of the legislature, when they were only bound to carry the same semi-weekly, thereby greatly facilitating the transmission of in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />telligence to and from the capitol of said State of Texas; there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore,</p>
<p>1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That our Senators and Representatives in the United States Congress are instructed to urge the passage of a law for the relief of said Brown and Tarbox, by compensating them for said extra services.</p>
<p>Resolved, That the Governor of the State is requested to trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mit to our said Senators and Representatives a copy of this joint resolution.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of the minor heirs of Louis P. Cooke.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller of Public Accounts be, and he is <pb n="774" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="104" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>hereby required to carry out the provisions of an act for the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lief of Louis P. Cooke, approved 4th February, 1842, and upon the payment of the balance due, it shall be the duty of the said Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller to execute a title in the usual form to the minor heirs of Louis P. Cooke.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of George C. Arnest.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a patent for one<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />third of a league of land to George. C. Arnest, for the land de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed in the field-notes of a survey made in his name in Bexar land district, upon his paying the government dues and the other fees required by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 11, 1850</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="775" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="105" />
<pb n="776" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="106" /><fw type="header" place="top">Certificate.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">STATE OF TEXAS.</head>
<p>I, JAMES WEBB, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, certify that the Third Legislature of said State, commenced its session at the City of Austin, on Monday the 5th day of November, in the year one thousand eight hundred and forty-nine, and adjourned on Monday the 11th day of February, in the year one thousand eight hundred and fifty.</p>
<p>And I further certify, that the Acts and Joint Resolutions con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained in this volume are true copies, with the exception of the words embraced in brackets, taken from the original rolls deposited in the Department of State, with which they have been carefully compared.</p>
<p>[L. S.]</p>
<p>Given under my hand and official seal, at the City of</p>
<p>Austin, the twenty-fifth day of March, in the year one thousand eight hundred and fifty.</p>
<closer>
<signed>JAMES WEBB.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Note.&#8212;The words embraced in brackets were inserted by the Secretary of State in comparing the laws, supposing them to be omissions in enrolling the bills.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="777" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="i" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX TO SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">A</head>
<p>Austin College, incorporated, <ref>4</ref>.</p>
<p>&#8221; &#8220; supplementary act, <ref>14</ref>.</p>
<p>Alexander, Melissa J., name of, changed, <ref>10</ref>.</p>
<p>Anderson, Thomas P., for the relief of the heirs of, <ref>25</ref>.</p>
<p>Austin, city of, certain property in, to be exchanged, <ref>39</ref>.</p>
<p>Allen, Araminta D., for the relief of, <ref>46</ref>.</p>
<p>Arnold, William, for the relief of the heirs of, <ref>54</ref>.</p>
<p>Albright, Jacob, for the relief of, <ref>72</ref>.</p>
<p>Abilo, Juan, for the relief of, <ref>91</ref>.</p>
<p>Arnest, George C., for the relief of, <ref>104</ref>.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">B</head>
<p>Brownsville Lyceum, incorporated, <ref>9</ref>.</p>
<p>&#8221; city of, incorporated, <ref>38</ref>.</p>
<p>Barton, John, for the relief of, <ref>10</ref>.</p>
<p>Barnes, Simon P., for the relief of, <ref>18</ref>.</p>
<p>Balch, John, for the relief of, <ref>19</ref>.</p>
<p>Boyd, John, for the relief of, <ref>24</ref>.</p>
<p>Baylor University, act incorporating, amended, <ref>33</ref>.</p>
<p>Branham, Joseph, for the relief of, <ref>45</ref>.</p>
<p>Baggett, Uzziel, for the relief of, <ref>46</ref>.</p>
<p>Barnes, Simon P., for the relief of, <ref>47</ref>.</p>
<p>Bexar manufacturing company, incorporated, <ref>47</ref>.</p>
<p>Brown and Tarbox, for the relief of, <ref>49</ref>.</p>
<p>Balleuill, A., for the relief of, <ref>58</ref>.</p>
<p>Brush, Captain J., for the relief of, <ref>63</ref>.</p>
<p>Bryan, Guy M., for the relief of, <ref>72</ref>.</p>
<p>Burleson, Jonathan, for the relief of, <ref>73</ref>.</p>
<p>Baker, William R., for the relief of, <ref>74</ref>.</p>
<p>Byers, Wesley, for the relief of, <ref>77</ref>.</p>
<p>Baker, Telford, for the relief of, <ref>86</ref>.</p>
<p>Bledsoe, Jesse, for the relief of the heirs of, <ref>86</ref>.</p>
<p>Baker, John R., for the relief of, <ref>91</ref>.</p>
<p>Brewster, Henry P., appropriation of land for the services of, <ref>93</ref>.</p>
<p>Brown and Tarbox, for the relief of, <ref>103</ref>.</p>
<pb n="778" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="ii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">C</head>
<p>Cunningham, A. S., for the relief of, <ref>10</ref>.</p>
<p>Gradden, Peter, for the relief of the heirs of, <ref>11</ref>.</p>
<p>Castroville, Town of, incorporated, <ref>20</ref>.</p>
<p>Carter, John H., for the relief of, <ref>34</ref>.</p>
<p>Cope, Mason W., for the relief of, <ref>47</ref>.</p>
<p>Chappel Hill College, incorporated, <ref>75</ref>.</p>
<p>Cherokee county, commissioners of, to deliver up documents, <ref>79</ref>.</p>
<p>Cooke, A. H., for the relief of, <ref>84</ref>.</p>
<p>Contreras, Juan, for the relief of, <ref>91</ref>.</p>
<p>Cessna, Green K., for the relief of, <ref>92</ref>.</p>
<p>Cessna, Nancy K., for the relief of, <ref>92</ref>.</p>
<p>Cooke, Louis P., for the relief of the heirs of, <ref>103</ref>.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">D</head>
<p>DeKalb College, supplementary act, incorporating, <ref>18</ref>.</p>
<p>Douglass, Samuel C., for the relief of, <ref>48</ref>.</p>
<p>Davis, R. M., for the relief of, <ref>73</ref>.</p>
<p>Dennis, Nathaniel, for the relief of the heirs of, <ref>83</ref>.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">E</head>
<p>Earl, Robert, for the relief of the heirs of, <ref>56</ref>.</p>
<p>Elliott, John James, declared legitimate, <ref>57</ref>.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">F</head>
<p>Fry, Benjamin F., for the relief of, <ref>20</ref>.</p>
<p>Fuller, Daniel, for the relief of, <ref>68</ref>.</p>
<p>Forris, Willis A., for the relief of the heirs of, <ref>96</ref>.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">G</head>
<p>Gillespie, Mary, to adopt Susan Lavinia McGuffin, <ref>7</ref>.</p>
<p>Guadalupe High School Association, incorporated, <ref>12</ref>.</p>
<p>Grisham, E. H., for the relief of, <ref>56</ref>.</p>
<p>Galveston City Company, to change the plan of a block of lots, <ref>64</ref>.</p>
<p>Garner, Thomas, for the relief of, <ref>66</ref>.</p>
<p>Garnett, Margaret, for the relief of, <ref>81</ref>.</p>
<p>Gilliam, Jesse, name of, changed, <ref>95</ref>.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H</head>
<p>Henderson, Mary, for the relief of, <ref>30</ref>.</p>
<p>Hart, Elizabeth, for the relief of, <ref>44</ref>.</p>
<p>Hunt, Gen. Memucan, for the relief of, <ref>44</ref>.</p>
<p>Harding, Peter P., for the relief of, <ref>66</ref>.</p>
<p>Howard, George T., for the relief of, <ref>95</ref>.</p>
<p>Hoxie, J. B., for the relief of, <ref>98</ref>.</p>
<p>Harrison William C., for the relief of, <ref>98</ref>.</p>
<p>Harrell, George, name of, changed, <ref>102</ref>.</p>
<p>Henderson, literary institute incorporated, <ref>51</ref>.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">J</head>
<p>Jarmon, Richard B., for the relief of, <ref>43</ref>.</p>
<pb n="779" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Johnson, B. C., for the relief of, <ref>50</ref>.</p>
<p>Jackson, John, for the relief of, <ref>68</ref>.</p>
<p>Jones, Hon, Fielding, leave of absence granted to, <ref>74</ref>.</p>
<p>Jasper cotton manufacturing company, incorporated, <ref>97</ref>.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">K</head>
<p>Kaufman, Daniel Richardson, name of, changed, <ref>3</ref>.</p>
<p>Knight, James, authorized to adopt Lucinda E. Nibbs, <ref>14</ref>.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">L</head>
<p>Latimer, Robert W., for the relief of, <ref>12</ref>.</p>
<p>Lewis, William Irvine, for the relief of the heirs of, <ref>15</ref>.</p>
<p>Literary institution at Henderson, Rusk county, incoroorated, <ref>51</ref>.</p>
<p>Little, John W., for the relief of, <ref>62</ref>.</p>
<p>Lewis, Patsey, for the relief of the heirs of, <ref>63</ref>.</p>
<p>Lansing, Lieutenant J. Platt, for the relief of the estate of, <ref>67</ref>.</p>
<p>Lane, David, for the relief of, <ref>77</ref>.</p>
<p>Logan, Greenberry, for the relief of, <ref>80</ref>.</p>
<p>Langham, Melville, for the relief of, <ref>82</ref>.</p>
<p>Lafayette Academy, incorporated, <ref>83</ref>.</p>
<p>Livigston, Town of, incorporated, <ref>87</ref>.</p>
<p>Laredo, act incorporating Town of, amended, <ref>90</ref>.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">M</head>
<p>Marshall cemetery company incorporated, <ref>7</ref>.</p>
<p>McClure, Hugh, for the relief of, <ref>8</ref>.</p>
<p>Manning, James M., for the relief of, <ref>13</ref>.</p>
<p>Maine, George W., for the relief of the heirs of, <ref>17</ref>.</p>
<p>Mockford, William, for the relief of the heirs of, <ref>19</ref>.</p>
<p>Monumental Committee, Texas, incorporated, <ref>29</ref>.</p>
<p>Malone, William H., for the relief of the heirs of, <ref>33</ref>.</p>
<p>McIntyre, Duncan, for the relief of the heirs of, <ref>33</ref>.</p>
<p>Mount Vernon Male and Female Academies incorporated, <ref>34</ref>.</p>
<p>Morrill, Amos, for the relief of, <ref>50</ref>.</p>
<p>Marshall, Wiley, for the relief of, <ref>63</ref>.</p>
<p>Morgan, Charles, for the relief of, <ref>64</ref>.</p>
<p>Merriweather, Francis, for the relief of, <ref>66</ref>.</p>
<p>McBride, Martha, for the relief of, <ref>81</ref>.</p>
<p>McMasters, William, for the relief of, <ref>82</ref>.</p>
<p>Martin, Charles, for the relief of the heirs of, <ref>86</ref>.</p>
<p>Miles, Edward, for the relief of, <ref>91</ref>.</p>
<p>Marshall, town of, incorporated, <ref>100</ref>.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">N</head>
<p>Nobles, Benjamin D., heirs of, for the relief of, <ref>11</ref>.</p>
<p>Nibbs, Lucinda E., may be adopted by James Knight, <ref>14</ref>.</p>
<p>Norvell, Samuel G, for the relief of, <ref>84</ref>.</p>
<p>Newton, Samuel G. &#38; Co., for the relief of, <ref>36</ref>.</p>
<p>North, George, name of, changed, <ref>37</ref>.</p>
<p>Nacogdoches, city of, incorporated, <ref>57</ref>.</p>
<p>Neill, John, for the relief of, <ref>62</ref>.</p>
<p>Norvell, Samuel G., for the relief of, <ref>84</ref>.</p>
<p>Neill, Robert E., for the relief of, <ref>83</ref>.</p>
<p>Neighbors, R. J., for the relief of, <ref>103</ref>.</p>
<pb n="780" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iv" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">O</head>
<p>Orphan Asylum, Western Texas, supplementary act incorporating, <ref>31</ref>.</p>
<p>Odd Fellows, Galveston Lodge of, incorporated, <ref>78</ref>.</p>
<p>Ogden, John C., for the relief of the heirs of, <ref>79</ref>.</p>
<p>Ogden, Duncan C., for the relief of, <ref>95</ref>.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">P</head>
<p>Patterson, James S., for the relief of, <ref>36</ref>.</p>
<p>Pearson, William, and Elizabeth Ogle, marriage of, legalized, <ref>54</ref>.</p>
<p>Perkins, Berry W., for the relief of, <ref>55</ref>.</p>
<p>Porter, Zebulon M., for the relief of, <ref>61</ref>.</p>
<p>Pitts, Edward H., for the relief of, <ref>63</ref>.</p>
<p>Printer, Public, Comptroller to settle with, <ref>67</ref>.</p>
<p>Pace, James R., for the relief of, <ref>71</ref>.</p>
<p>Patents, certain, made valid, <ref>96</ref>.</p>
<p>Parker, William E., for the relief of, <ref>98</ref>.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">R</head>
<p>Rutersville College, act incorporating amended, <ref>6</ref>.</p>
<p>Rio Grande City, incorporated, <ref>15</ref>.</p>
<p>Rodearmel, Lemuel M., for the relief of, <ref>35</ref>.</p>
<p>Rice, James O., for the relief of, <ref>62</ref>.</p>
<p>Rose, Robert, for the relief of, <ref>64</ref>.</p>
<p>Rusk, Town of, incorporated, <ref>69</ref>.</p>
<p>Rosier, John P., for the relief of, <ref>81</ref>.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S</head>
<p>San Augustine, town of, incorporated, <ref>3</ref>.</p>
<p>Simonds, Melissa J., name of, changed, <ref>10</ref>.</p>
<p>Simonds, James Alexander, name of, changed, <ref>10</ref>.</p>
<p>Simonds, Parola, name of, changed, <ref>10</ref>.</p>
<p>Secrest, Washington H., for the relief of, 25,</p>
<p>Sons of Temperance, Grand and Subordinate Divisions of, incorporated, <ref>32</ref>.</p>
<p>Shearn, Charles, for the relief of, <ref>55</ref>.</p>
<p>Sheek, George Washington, for the relief of, <ref>59</ref>.</p>
<p>Sparks, William C., for the relief of, <ref>65</ref>.</p>
<p>Singleton, J. H., for the relief of, <ref>67</ref>.</p>
<p>Stanton, Mrs. Julia, to take the guardianship of her son, <ref>71</ref>.</p>
<p>Scranton, Frederick, for the relief of, <ref>73</ref>.</p>
<p>Sargeant, Leoin S., for the relief of, <ref>79</ref>.</p>
<p>Stanly, Charles F., for the relief of, <ref>80</ref>.</p>
<p>Smith, James, for the relief of, <ref>84</ref>.</p>
<p>Simms, Bartlett, for the relief of, <ref>85</ref>.</p>
<p>Santa Anna, debt contracted by escort of, to be audited, <ref>89</ref>.</p>
<p>Supreme Court, sessions of, to be held in the Capitol, <ref>94</ref>.</p>
<p>Simpson, Magdaline Margaret, name of, changed, <ref>99</ref>.</p>
<p>Supreme Court, appropriation to purchase books for, <ref>94</ref>.</p>
<p>Simpson, Robertor W., name of, changed, <ref>99</ref>.</p>
<p>St. Johns, Mrs. Sophia J., land scrip granted to, <ref>99</ref>.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">T</head>
<p>Taylor, C. C., for the relief of, <ref>8</ref>.</p>
<p>Taylor, James, for the relief of, <ref>15</ref>.</p>
<pb n="781" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="v" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Texana College, incorporated, <ref>20</ref>.</p>
<p>Tilley and Hewitt, for the relief of, <ref>36</ref>.</p>
<p>Tuten, William S., for the relief of the heirs of, <ref>38</ref>.</p>
<p>Tyler, Town of, incorporated, <ref>60</ref>.</p>
<p>Thompson, Joseph, for the relief of the heirs of, <ref>69</ref>.</p>
<p>Troute, Christopher, for the relief of, <ref>73</ref>.</p>
<p>Taylor, Joseph, for the relief of, <ref>80</ref>.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">U</head>
<p>Ury, James, for the relief of the heirs of, <ref>53</ref>.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">V</head>
<p>Von Ger-Mar, Albert, for the relief of, <ref>7</ref>.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">W</head>
<p>Ward, Thomas, for the relief of, <ref>6</ref>.</p>
<p>Ward, Thomas Wm, for the relief of, <ref>28</ref>.</p>
<p>Walradt, William Lipe, name changed, <ref>30</ref>.</p>
<p>Williams, Henry B., for the relief of the representatives of, <ref>56</ref>.</p>
<p>Wallace, William, for the relief of the heirs of, <ref>83</ref>.</p>
<p>Wallace, William A. A., for the relief of, <ref>84</ref>.</p>
<p>Wallace, William W., for the relief of, <ref>85</ref>.</p>
<p>Weston, Thomas, for the relief of the heirs of, <ref>92</ref>.</p>
<p>Webb, James, appropriation of land for services, <ref>93</ref>.</p>
<pb n="782" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="vi" />
</div3>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
