<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="1355" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">SPECIAL LAWS <lb/>OF <lb/>THE FOURTH LEGISLATURE <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS</head>
<byline>VOLUME IV.</byline>
<byline>PUBLISHED BY AUTHORITY.</byline>
<byline>AUSTIN. 1853</byline>
<pb n="1356" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" />
<pb n="1357" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" />
<head type="sub">SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to an act entitled &#8220;An Act to establish and incorporate the Marshall University,&#8221; and to change the name thereof to that of Van Zandt College.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the name of Marshall University be, and the same is changed to that of Van Zandt College.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the name of the Corporation of Trustees be changed to &#8220;the Trustees of Van Zandt College,&#8221; and that all do<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nations and bequests which have heretofore been made, or which may hereafter be made to said University, shall be good and bind<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, notwithstanding the change of name from Marshall Univer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ity to Van Zandt College.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 26, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the act to incorporate the Buffalo Bayou, Brazos and Colorado Railway Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That sections second, third and seventeenth, of the &#8220;act to incorporate the Buffalo Bayou, Brazos and Colorado Railway Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany,&#8221; approved February 11, 1850, be so amended as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 2. That said company be, and is hereby invested <pb n="1358" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>with the right of locating, constructing, owning and maintaining a Railway, commencing at a suitable point on Buffalo Bayou, in the county of Harris, and thence running by such course and to such point or points at or near the Brazos and Colorado rivers, or across the same as said company may deem advisable, with the privilege of making, owning and maintaining such branches to said road as they may deem expedient.</p>
<p>Sec. 3 The capital stock of said Company shall consist of all its property, real and personal, franchises and rights to property; shall be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, each share shall entitle the owner thereof to one vote in person or proxy, at all meetings of said company; said shares shall be deemed personal estate, and shall be transferable by any conveyance in writing, recorded either by the Treasurer in books kept by him at his office for that purpose, or by any other officer duly authorized by the Directors, in books kept by him in such other place as the Directors may appoint. Such transfers as are recorded at such other place, being within thirty days communicated to the Treasurer, and by him entered into his book.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. If at least twenty miles of said railway are not in run<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ning order by the 11th February, 1854, then this charter shall be null and void.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That there shall be granted to said company eight, sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions of land, of six hundred and forty acres each, for every mill of railway actually completed and ready for use, and upon the ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plication of the President of the Company, or any duly authorized Agent thereof, stating that any section of five miles or more of said railway has been completed and is ready for use, it shall be the. duty of the Comptroller of Public Accents to require the State Engineer or a Commissioner to be appointed by the Governor, to examine said railway, and upon his certificate that said section of said railway has been completed in a good and substantial manner, and is ready for use, the Comptroller shall give information of that fact to the Commissioner of the General Landoffice, whose duty it shall be to issue to said company land certificates to the amount of eight sections of land, of six hundred and forty acres each, and shall be located upon any unappropriated domain of the State of Texas, within twelve months from the issuing thereof, which date shall appear upon the face of each certificate, and upon the return of the field-notes of any survey made by virtue of any certificate thus issued, it shall be the duty of the Commissioner of the General Landoffice to issue patents to <pb n="1359" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>said company in their corporate name; one-fourth of which said lands thus patented shall be alienated by the company in six years, one-fourth in eight years, one-fourth in ten years, and the other fourth in twelve years, so that the whole of the lands thus granted shall pass from the hands of the company, within twelve years form the date of the patents thus issued. Said company shall have the same right or power that any other company have, or may here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after have, chartered by this State, to connect and contract with other railway companies, and in case of disagreement between said companies, the same shall be referred and settled as provided for in like cases, and be binding for one year.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The sixteenth section of said act incorporation is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 29, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the Benefit of the heirs of H. P. Chamberlain, De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Landoffice be, and he is hereby authorized to issue to the heirs of Horace P. Chamberlain, deceased, a certificate for his head right of one-third of a league of land, which may be located, surveyed and patented upon the public lands of Texas, as other land claims are patented, and upon the payment of the Government dues and fees of office.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. And that this act go into effect upon its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 2, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Incorporate the town of Mount Vernon in Texas, Titus County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the citizens of the town of Mount Vernon be, and <pb n="1360" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>are hereby declared a body politic and corporate, under the title of the town of Mount Vernon, and by that name may sue and be sued in all suits whatever, and by that name may purchase, hold and convey any real or personal estate, within the limits of said town, and mav have a corporate seal.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the limits of the corporation shall extend three<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quarters of a mile each way from the public square.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all persons who are qualified electors under the constitution of the State, and who are citizens of the town of Mount Vernon, shall be allowed to vote in elections held in said town.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That an election shall be held in said town on the first Monday of December of each and every year, for the purpose of electing a mayor, five aldermen, constable, secretary and treasurer; the first election shall be ordered by the first class justice of the peace of Titus county, at the beat in which said town is located, to be held as soon as practicable after the passage of this act, and that every subsequent election shall be ordered by the mayor and two aldermen, and if there be no mayor, said election shall be ordered by the three aldermen.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That all officers elected by the first order shall hold their offices until the annual election, or until their successors are qualified; and all officers elected by the mayor and aldermen or aldermen, shall hold their office for one year; and in case of elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion to fill vacancies, the officers so elected shall hold their offices until the next annual election: Provided, however, that all such officers so elected shall hold their office until their successors are qualified.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That no person shall be eligible to any of the said offices who is not a freeholder or householder, and a citizen of Mount Vernon.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the mayor shall be president of the board of alder<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men; the mayor and three aldermen shall constitute a quorum to transact business; and that the board may enact such by-laws for the government of said town, not inconsistent with the laws and constitution of the State, as may be deemed proper; and may inflict such fines, not exceeding one hundred dollars, as may be deemed necessary.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That the board of aldermen shall have control over the streets of said town, may order new streets to be laid out, and old ones to be discontinued at their discretion, by unanimous consent of the board; in such acts the board shall be governed by the laws of the State relative to the roads and highways.</p>
<pb n="1361" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 9. That all free males between the ages of twenty-one and forty-five, shall be liable to work the streets; that such persons shall not be compelled to work more than ten days in one year, and shall be exempt from working all other roads, and the board shall impose such fines against defaulters as they may deem neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That the board may levy an equal tax on all real and personal property and merchandize, or they man exempt a certain amount of household goods, and may levy a license tax on physi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cians, surgeons, boarding houses, livery stables, and may license or close all theatres or shows, all grog-shops, doggeries, or any drain<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />drinking establishment, restaurat, billiards, ten-pins, and all gambling houses, and all such like indulgencies, but shall not tax agricultural or mechanical trades; such tax to be levied at the be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ginning of each year, and shall be assessed and collected by an officer to be appointed by the board, in the same manner that the State tax is collected; said tax not to exceed one per cent. ad valorem.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That the board of Aldermen shall have power to ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />point such officers, fix their salaries and duties, and to remove them for default or violation of duty as said board shall think proper; and all such officers shall be required to give bond and security to the mayor, in such penalty as may be deemed requisite, and shall be liable to such fines as may be imposed for neglect of duty.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That the board of aldermen shall have power to regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />late it own proceedings, and to prescribe the duty of all the offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers of the corporation, and shall have the power to enact all ordinances necessary for the peace and welfare of said town, not contrary to law.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That the Mayor shall try all offences against all the laws and ordinances of the town, and be ex-officio Justice of the Peace, with civil and criminal jurisdiction; the Mayor, Constable and Aldermen shall be conservators of the peace.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That all offenses and violations against the ordinan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ces aforesaid, shall be prosecuted before the Mayor, as required in the acts organizing Justice&#8217;s Courts, and defining the powers and jurisdiction of the same; and the Constable shall execute all writs directed to him from the Mayor.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. That all elections shall be held in accordance with the law regulating elections.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. That the Constable, Secretary and Treasurer shall give bond and security, to be approved by the board of aldermen, for the faithful performance of their duty.</p>
<pb n="1362" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 17. That if any person elected or appointed to office under this charter, fail to qualify within ten days after his election or appointment, the board shall have power to declare the office va<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cant and order another election.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. That all officers before entering upon the duties of their respective offices, shall make oath faithfully to perform the duties of their respective offices.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. That elections shall be ordered to be held at least ten days before the expiration of the term of office of the officers designated by this charter.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. That all contests in elections shall be determined by the board of Aldermen; provided, however, that the election held by the order of the Magistrate for the first officers shall, if con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tested, be determined by the Magistrate ordering it.</p>
<p>Sec. 21. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 4, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V. AN ACT</head>
<opener>
<salute>Repealing the second section of an act passed on the 10th day of February, 1852, changing the names of Antionette Scott and Sidney Way, to that of Devereaux.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the second section of said act be repealed, leaving the first section in full force.</p>
<p>SeC. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 4, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the inhabitants of Presidio de San Elizario, in El Paso County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the grant to the inhabitants of the town of Presidio de San Elizario, having been destroyed by the American troops in the year eighteen hundred and forty-six; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the grant made to the people of Presidio de San <pb n="1363" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Elizario in the year seventeen hundred and ninety, to the follow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing described tract of land, to wit: commencing on the Rio Grande at a point where the established line of division between the towns of Socarro and San Elizario strikes said river for the North<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ern boundary, and following said line to the hills bordering on the eastern bank of the river Viejo; thence running south-east along with said hills down the river Viejo, to a point at which said Rio Viejo empties into the Rio Grande; thence up said Rio Grande from the mouth of the Rio Viejo to the place of beginning, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />taining four leagues more or less, is hereby fully recognized and confirmed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Commissioner of the General Landoffice be, and he is hereby authorized to issue a patent to the inhabitants of said town of Presidio de San Elizario, to the above described tract of land; provided, that there are no evidences of conflicting claims for said tract of land on record in the General Landoffice.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 5, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Incorporate and establish St. Paul&#8217;s College:</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That an Institution of learning, to be known as St. Paul&#8217;s College be, and the same is hereby established at Anderson in the county of Grimes.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That there shall be for the present, seven Trustees of said College, to take charge of its interests, a majority of whom shall contitute a quorum to do business.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the following named persons, having been duly chosen Trustees of said College, are recognized as such, viz: Geo. W. Freeman, Anson Jones, Peter W. Gray, Guy M. Bryan, E. B. Nichols, D. C. Dickson and S. G. Haynie, which board may be increased as hereinafter provided for, to any number not exceed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing fifteen.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the aforesaid Trustees and their successors in office be, and they are hereby constituted a body politic and cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate, in deed and in law, by the name of the &#8220;President and Trustees of St. Paul&#8217;s College,&#8221; and by that name they and <pb n="1364" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>their successors may and shall have perpetual succession, and be able and capable in law to receive, have and enjoy, to them and their successors, lands, tenements, hereditaments of any kind, in fee or for life, or for years, and personal property of any kind what<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />soever, and all sums of money which may be granted, given or be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />queathed to them for the purpose of promoting the interests of said College.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That there shall be a stated meeting of the Board of Trustees in each year, at the time of conferring degrees, and that the President of said Board of Trustees shall have full power to call an occasional meeting of the Board whenever it shall appear to him necessary, and a majority of said Board shall have similar power.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the Trustee&#347; of said College may and shall have a common seal for the business of themselves and their successors, with liberty to alter or change the same from time to time, as they shall think proper, and that by their aforesaid name, they and their successors may and shall be able to sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, answer and be answered, defend and be defended in all courts of law and equity in this State, and to grant, bargain, lease, sell or assign any lands, tenements, goods or chattels, now belon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ging to said College, or that may hereafter belong to the same; to construct all the necessary buildings for said Institution; to estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lish a preparatory department, and departments for the study of any or all the learned and liberal professions, at such places as may be designated by them, and any such dependent institutions as they may deem necessary in furtherance of the objects of this act; to establish fellowships and scholarships; to have the management of the finances; the privilege of electing their own officers (except as hereinafter provided;) of appointing all necessary committees, and to act and do all things whatsoever for the benefit of said Institution in as ample a manner as any body politic or corporate may and can do by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. It. That the Trustees shall have the power of prescribing the course of studies to be pursued by the students, and of framing and enacting all such ordinances and by-laws as shall appear to them necessary from time to time for the government of said Col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lege and for their own proceedings; provided, always, that the same be in accordance with the Constitution of the United States and of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That the head of said College shall be styled the President, and the instructors thereof the Professors and Tutors, and the President and Professors of the departments general<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1365" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ly; the Faculty of the respective departments of said College; which Faculty as above shall have power of enforcing the ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nances and by-laws adopted by the Trustees for the government of the students in their respective departments, by rewarding or censuring them, and finally by suspending or expeling such of them as after repeated admonitions shall continue disobedient or refractory.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That the Trustees shall have power by the President and Faculty of said College to grant and confer such degree or degrees in the arts, sciences and learned professions to the students of said College, and to other persons worthy thereof, as are usually granted and&#8217; conferred in other Colleges or Universities in the United States, and to give certificates thereof or diplomas, signed by them, and sealed with the common seal of the Trustees of the College, to authenticate and perpetuate the memory of such gradu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ations.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That whenever a vacancy shall occur, either by death, resignation, or removal by the appointing power, in the Board of Trustees, such vacancy shall be filled by the annual convention of the Protestant Episcopal Church in the diocese of the State of Texas, and said convention may at their discretion, at any time hereafter, increase the Faculty to any number not exceeding fif<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teen, and classify the same and fix their terms of office.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That the Bishop of the Protestant Episcopal Church in the diocese of Texas, for the time being, and his canonical suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessors, shall be ex-officio President of the Board of Trustees, and until some other person shall, with his approval, be appointed hv the Board, be also President of the Faculty of said College.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That the Trustees shall have the power of appointing the President of the Faculty as hereinbefore provided, and the Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fessors and other officers connected with the College, and of fixing their salaries, and also of removing them for cause, a majority of the whole number concurring in said removal.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That no misnomer of said College shall defeat or annul any gift, grant, devise or bequest to the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That this act shall be deemed a public one, and judicially taken notice of without special pleading.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. That in case any donation, devise or bequest, shall be made for particular purposes, accordant with the designs of this institution, and the Trustees shall accept the same; every such donation, devise, or bequest shall be applied in strict con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1366" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>formity with the express conditions of the donor or devisor, and the property or funds belonging, or in anywise appertaining to the Institution, shall not be diverted from the primary object for which they were donated.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. That the seal of the corporation, with the attestation of the President, or in his absence, of the usual majority of the Trustees, shall be sufficient to authenticate any act of the corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 4, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to an act to establish the La Salle and El Paso Railway Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all that portion of an act to establish the La Salle and El Paso railway company, approved the 11th day of February, 1850, contained in the fourth section, and all the subsequent sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions thereof, be, and the same are hereby repealed; and whereas, it is desirable to preserve uniformity in the several enactments establishing railway companies, by this legislature, the following provisions are hereby adopted at the instance of the Commissioner named in the said original act, for the government, formation and observance of the company thereby established.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the meeting of the Commissioners provided for by this act, and the said original act, may be held at such times and places as they may appoint, and at said meetings the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners may act in person or by proxy.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The capital stock of said company, to consist of all its property, real and personal, franchises and rights to property, shall be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each. Each share entitling the owner thereof to one vote by himself, or proxy, at all meetings of said company, that said share shall be deemed personal estate, and shall be transferable by any conveyance in writing, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corded by the treasurer, in books kept by him at his office, or in such other manner as the by-laws of said company shall provide.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The immediate government and direction of the af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fairs of said Company, shall be vested in a board of not less than six directors, who shall choose one of their own number as Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1367" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>dent of said company. No person shall be eligible to the office of Director, unless an owner or subscriber of at least five shares of the stock of said company; the Directors shall have power to fill any vacancy that may occur in said board, from non-election, death, or otherwise, and may appoint a Secretary, Treasurer, and such other officers and agents as they may consider necessary, and prescribe and require bonds for the faithful performance of their duties; they may, if not otherwise provided by the by-laws, deter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mine the manner of conducting all meetings, the number of mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers that shall constitute a quorum, and to do or cause to be done, all other lawful matters and things which they may deem neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary and proper in conducting the matters of the company; and they shall keep or cause to be kept, accurate records of all meet<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings of the Directors. and company, and accurate accounts of the receipts and expenditures of the company, which shall be open to the inspection of the stockholders; a majority of the board of Directors shall have the authority of a full board, and all con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyances and contracts in writing, executed by the President and countersigned by the Secretary or any other officer or person authorized by the Directors, under the seal of the company, and in pursuance of a vote of said Directors, shall be valid and binding.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The shares may be disposed of and books open for sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scription thereto, in such manner and on such terms as said Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners shall determine will be best for the interest of said company, and any agreement in writing by which any person shall become a subscriber to the capital stock of said company may be enforced against him according to its terms, and if any subscriber shall fail to pay any amount due upon shares subscribed by him according to the terms of his subscription, the Directors may sell at auction, and transfer to the purchaser the shares of such delin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quent, and if the proceeds of sale shall not be sufficient to pay the amount due on said subscription, with interest and charges, such delinquent shall be held liable to the company for the de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficiency, and if the proceeds shall exceed the amount so due, with interest and charges, said delinquent shall be entitled to the sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plus.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. It shall be lawful for the company to enter upon and purchase or otherwise take and hold any land necessary for the purpose of establishing and constructing said railway, with all necessary depots and other buildings, and if they shall not be able to obtain said lands by agreement with the owners there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />of, they shall pay therefor such compensation as shall be determined in the manner provided by the following section; <pb n="1368" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Provided, that the land so taken for the road bed, shall not exceed two hundred feet in width, and for depots and other buildings, only such further width as shall be needed for such purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Any person when land has been taken as aforesaid, without agreement or satisfactory compensation, may apply to the District Court of the county in which said land is situated for the appointment of, and the court shall thereupon appoint three disinterested free-holders of the county, who shall appoint a time and place to hear the applicant and the company, to whom shall be given by said free-holders, reasonable notice of said time and place, and said free-holders shall, after having sworn, and after due hear<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing of the parties, determine the amount of compensation, if any, to which the applicant is entitled, and make return of their award to the next succeeding term of said court, and said award if not re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jected by said court for sufficient cause then shown, shall be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tered up as the judgment of said court; in determining the ques<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of compensation, said free-holders shall be governed by the actual value of the land at the time it was taken, taking into con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sideration the benefit or injury done to the other lands and prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty of the owner by the establishment of said railway, and if the amount of compensation awarded by said free-holders, shall not exceed the amount offered by said owner prior to said application to the court, the applicant shall pay the cost of the proceedings, otherwise the company shall pay the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. It shall be the duty of said company whenever any State or county road, now by law established, shall be crossed by the track of said railway, to make and keep in repair good and suffic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ient causeways at such crossings, and in all cases where any person shall own lands on both sides of said railway, and there shall be no other convenient access from one part to the other, such owner shall have the right of passage free of cost, at reasonable times, across the track of said railway.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. This company is hereby required at all reasonable times and for a reasonable compensation, to draw over their road, the passengers, merchandize and cars of any other rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road corporation, which has been or may hereafter be authorized by the legislature, to enter with their railroad and connect with the railroad of this company, and if the respective companies, shall be unable to agree upon the compensation aforesaid, it shall be the duty of the President of each company, to select each one man as a commissioner, and the two commissioners <pb n="1369" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>so selected shall choose a third, in case of disagreement, neither of whom shall be a stockholder in either road or interested therein, and they shall fix the rates which shall not be changed for one year, from the time of going into effect, the said commissioners shall also fix the stated periods at which said cars are to be drawn as aforesaid, having reference to the convenience and interests of said corporation and the public, who will be accommodated there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by; the right or power is specially conferred on this said company, to connect and contract with any railroad company chartered by this State, for the performance of like transport, and in ease of disagreement between said companies, the same shall be referred and settled as aforesaid, to be binding for one year as aforesaid.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That said company may acquire real estate by gift or purchase, and that such commissioners hereinbefore mentioned shall have full authority to solicit and receive subscriptions, and conveyances of land to said company, until the time fixed for the first meeting of said commissioners, which authority may be then extended by said meeting; which land so obtained shall be alien<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated by said company in the following manner: one-fourth in six years; one-fourth in eight years; one-fourth in ten years, and the remaining one-fourth in twelve years from the time the same was acquired.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. If the track of this railway shall cross any navigable stream, it shall do it in such way as not to obstruct its navigation.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Said company shall have the right to demand and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive such rates and prices for the transportation of passengers and freight as they may think proper to establish, not to exceed five cents per mile for passengers, and fifty cents per hundred pounds for freight, each hundred miles the same may be carried.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. If any person shall wilfully injure or obstruct said railway or its property, such person may be punished when prose<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cuted by indictment for said offense in due course of law, and also liable to action by said company, or any person whatever, who may suffer in person or property from said wilful obstruction, for the amount of damages occasioned thereby.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. There shall be granted to aid company eight sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions of land, of six hundred and forty acres each, for every mile of railway actually completed by them and ready for use, and upon the application of the President of the company, or any duly authorized agent thereof, stating that any section of five miles or more of said railway has been completed and is <pb n="1370" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ready for use, it shall be the duty of the Comptroller of Public Accounts, to require the State Engineer, or a commissioner to be appointed by the Governor to examine said railway, and upon his certificate that said section of said railway has been completed in a good and substantial manner, and is ready for use, the Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller shall give information of that fact to the Commissioner of the General Landoffice, whose duty it shall be to issue to said company land certificates to the amount of eight sections of land of six hundred and forty acres each, for each and every mile of railway thus completed and ready for use, such certificates shall be for six hundred and forty acres each, and shall be located upon any unappropriated public domain of the State of Texas, within twelve, months from the issuing thereof, which date shall appear upon the face of each certificate, and upon the return of the field<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />notes of any survey made by virtue of any certificates thus issued, it shall be the duty of the Commissioner of the General Landoffice, to issue patents to said company in their corporate name. One fourth of which said lands thus patented shall be alienated by the company in six years, one-fourth in eight years, one-fourth in ten years, and the other fourth in twelve years, so that the whole of the lands thus granted, shall pass from the hands of the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany within twelve years from the date of the patent thus issued.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. Said company shall be required to have a good and sufficient brake upon the hindmost car in all trains transporting passengers or merchandize, and also permanently stationed there, a trusty and skillful brakeman, under a penalty not exceeding the sum of one hundred dollars for each offense, to be recovered in any court of competent jurisdiction, for the benefit of the State, and said company shall cause to be placed on each locomotive engine passing over their road, a bell of the weight of at least twenty-five pounds, or a steam whistle, and the said bell shall be rung or the whistle blown at the distance of at least eighty rods from the place of crossing any highway or turnpike, and kept ring<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing or blowing until the engine has passed or stopped; said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany shall be required to contract their railroad with good T or U iron rails; Provided, That no land shall be donated unless the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany shall actually commence their road within two years, and actually complete and finish at least ten miles within three years.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. Nothing in this act shall be so contrued as to confer banking privileges or powers of any kind whatever.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. If said railway shall not be commenced within five years from the passage of this act, and at least twenty <pb n="1371" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>miles thereof completed within six years, then this charter shall be null and void; and it is hereby provided and declared, that it shall be lawful for any railway hereafter to be constructed, to cross the said railway or any branch thereof or to connect at any point therewith.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. The said company shall have the right to take and hold so much of the public lands, not exceeding two hundred feet wide, as the said railway or any of its branches may pass through, for the track thereof, and such additional width as may be abso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lutely necessary for any depot, or other work for the purposes of the railway, that the company may deem proper to establish, and in all cases where such railway or branch shall pass through any pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic lands, all such lands to the depth of three miles from the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terior lines of the track on each side, thereof, shall be, and hereby are reserved for the State, from and after the time such track shall be fixed or designated by survey, reconnoisance or otherwise, and the said lands as fast as the road is constructed, shall be divided into sections fronting one mile each on the road; which sections shall be numbered, and the corners of such sections on the road plainly marked, and of these reserved lands the company shall have the right by virtue of any of their certificates issued in ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cordance with the provisions of this act, to cause to be located, surveyed and patented for their use each alternate section, such section in each instance embracing a tract of land fronting one mile on said road, and extending back three miles, preserving an equal width, and the remaining sections shall continue the prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty of the State, until disposed of by the Legislature.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 5, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of John White.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Landoffice be, and he is hereby required to issue to John White or his legal represen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tatives, patents for two leagues and two labors of land, granted to said White by act of Congress, approved January 19th 1839, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 5, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1372" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Andrew Female College.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Andrew J. Wiley, Francis A. McShan, Robert Wynne, J. Carroll Smith, C. G. Iveenan, H. Yoakum, Daniel Baker, Will<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />iamson Wynne, Anthony C. Parmer, D. J. Ransom, Andrew J. Mc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Gown, Pleasant W. Kittrell and Micajab. C. Rogers, be, and they are hereby incorporated, and with their successors, as hereinafter provided, shall be known and recognized in law, as the Trustees of Andrew Female College, and under that name shall have power to sue and be sued, to have a seal, and to do all things incident to corporations; provided, their acts as such shall not be, inconsistent with the Constitution and laws of the United States, or of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Said Trustees shall hold their offices for two years from the first day of January, 1853, at which time the four first named shall go out of office; and at the end of two years thereafter, the next four shall go out of office; and at the end of two years more the remaining four shall go out of office; provided, that nothing herein contained shall prevent the reappointment of any Trustee whose time has thus expired.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Said female College shall be located, at the town of Huntsville, and shall be under the supervision and patronage of the Texas Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church South; provided, that no religious test shall ever be required of Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fessors, Tutors or Students in said institution.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The places of those Trustees whose time shall expire as provided in the second section of this act, shall be filled by the Texas Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South, and the Trustees so appointed by said Conference shall severally hold their offices for the term of six years from the expiration of the term of their successors, and so all vacancies by expiration of terms of service shall be filled.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Said corporation shall have power to buy and sell real and personal estate, to erect buildings, enlarge and remove the same, to put in operation an institution of learning, to appoint and remove Professors, Teachers and Tutors, to confer degrees and grant diplomas to such as in their opinion shall deserve the same, to dismiss and suspend students, to make by-laws for their own government, and establish rules for the government of the College, to fix the rates of tuition, salaries of instructors, and gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erally to do all things necessary for the good conduct and manage<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of a female College.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Said Trustees shall elect one of their number Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1373" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>dent of the board, and a Secretary, when they shall be declared organized, and a majority of the entire board shall be competent to transact business.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. This corporation shall exist for fifty years under this charter.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the town of Seguin in Guadalupe county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the citizens of the town of Seguin be, and they are hereby declared a body corporate, by the name and title of the incorporation of the town of Seguin, and by that name may sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, and may hold and dispose of real and personal estate in said town.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the incorporated limits of said town of Seguin shall embrace the lower half of the branch league of land which is covered by the present town of Seguin, and the whole of the town of Guadalupe city on the upper half of said league adjoining the present town of Seguin, according to the original plot and plan of said Guadalupe city, as the same is recorded in the office of the clerk of the county court of Guadalune county.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That an election shall be held in said town on the first Monday in March, in each and every year, for a Mayor, a Consta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ble, a Treasurer and four Aldermen, the first election to be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ducted by the Chief Justice of Guadalupe county, and every sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sequent election to be conducted by the Mayor or a majority of the Aldermen acting at the time of such election, and the persons elected shall continue in office one year, or until their successors are duly qualified.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That whenever a vacancy shall occur in the office of Mayor, a majority of the Aldermen acting shall order and conduct an election to fill such vacancy, and the person so elected shall hold the office until the next regular election, or until his successor shall he duly qualified.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That no person shall be eligible to the office of Mayor or Alderman unless a citizen of said town and a householder or owner of real estate therein, and no person shall be eligible to the office of Constable or Treasurer unless such person be a citizen of the same.</p>
<pb n="1374" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 6. That the Mayor shall be President of the board of Aldermen, that three of the members of said board, including the Mayor, shall constitute a quorum to transact business, and that the board may enact such by-laws for the Government of said town not inconsistent with the Constitution and laws of this State, as may be deemed proper, and may inflict fines for disobedience of the same, not exceeding twenty dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the board of Aldermen shall have and exercise control over the public squares and streets in said town, and may compel all persons (ministers of the gospel excepted) over the age of eighteen and under forty-five years, to work on the same; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that such persons shall not be required to work more than ten days in any one year, and they shall be exempt from other road duty in said county, and the board may impose such fines on defaulters as they may deem necessary, in which the board shall be governed by the law of this State regulating roads.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That the board of Aldermen shall have power to levy a tax on all persons and property, both real and personal, in said town, subject to taxation by the laws of this State; provided, that the tax on property shall not in any one year exceed one-fifth of one per cent, ad valorem on such property, and no tax shall be levied unless by two-thirds of the members present, which shall be assessed and collected by the Constable in the same manner as the State tax is collected; and the board shall also have the power to levy and collect a license tax on all shows, places of amusement, race tracks, billiard tables, ten pin alleys, houses for retailing spirituous liquors, or for the carrying on of any business or calling within said corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That the board of Aldermen shall have power to ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />point such additional officers, with the regulation of their duties and compensation as may be necessary, and may require of them bond with security to the Mayor, in such penalty as may be deemed, requisite to compel the official discharge of such duties as may be assigned them.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That all offenses against the by-laws be prosecuted before the Major, and governed by the law organizing justices courts, and the Constable shall execute and return all writs issued by the Mayor in the same manner as is provided by law defining the duties of Constables.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That in case of the death, resignation, or removal of any Alderman, Treasurer or Constable, the Mayor shall order an election under such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the board, to fill such vacancy.</p>
<pb n="1375" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 12. That the Constable shall give bond and security as re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired of other Constables, shall have the same power and be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled to the same fees for similar services.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That the Mayor of said town shall be entitled to such fees as may be allowed Justices of the Peace for similar services, together with such other compensation as may be allowed him by two-thirds of the Aldermen present at the time of such allowance.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That the Aldermen shall be entitled to such compen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sation as may be allowed them by the board; provided, in no ease shall the same exceed two dollars per day for each day they may be required to sit as such Aldermen.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. That the Treasurer shall keep safely all the money of said corporation, shall pay out the same upon the order of the board, and shall do such other dirties as may be assigned him by the by-laws; he shall give bond with security payable to the Mayor in such sum as may be deemed proper, conditioned for the faith<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ful performance of his duties, to be approved by the board, and shall be allowed such compensation as may be allowed from time to time to county Treasurers.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. That the Mayor be, and is hereby invested with all the powers and jurisdiction of a Justice of the Peace within the limits of said town.</p>
<p>Sec. If. That the books and records of the incorporation shall at all reasonable times be open to the examination of any citizen of said town or property holder therein, desiring the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. That all free white male persons over the age of twenty-one years, who shall have resided within said corporation for one month, and shall be entitled to a vote in the general elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions of the State, shall be entitled to vote in the election of the officers of said corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XII.</head>
<p>An Act to incorporate the Indianola and Victoria Plank and Turnpike Road Company.</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of <pb n="1376" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Texas, That Charles A. Ogsbury, Chambers Etter, James Ash<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />worth, John H. Dale, H. J. Huck, John D. Logan, George F. Eodgers and their associates and successors be, and they are here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by created and established a body corporate, under the name of the Indianola and Victoria Plank and Turnpike Road Company, with capacity in said corporate name to contract, to make by-laws for the regulations of its affairs, to sue and be sued, to have succession and a common seal, and generally to do and perform all acts neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary and proper for the maintenance of its rights, ahd in accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance with the Constitution of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the said company be, and is hereby invested with the right of locating, contracting, owning and maintaining a Plank and Turnpike road, commencing within the coroorate lim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />its of the town of Indianola, thence running by such course and to such points at or near Victoria as the company shall deem most suitable, with the privilege of making such branches and extensions as thev may think expedient.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the parties named in this act, or a majority of them, with such persons as they may associate with themselves for such purpose, are hereby appointed Commissioners, and invested With the right of forming and organizing said company, and of exercising the powers of Directors until Directors are elected by the stockholders.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the capital stock of said company shall be one hundred thousand dollars, to be divided into shares of fifty dollars each, each share entitling the owner to one vote at all meetings of the company, the ownership of the several shares being deter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mined by the exhibit of the original certificate, duly assigned, if not in the hands of the first holders, or proof of their ownership, said company being authorized to increase their capital stock to such an amount as may be necessary for the purposes herein speci<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That until the stockholders shall elect a board of direc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors consisting of five persons, each one of whom shall own five shares at least, the Commissioners above named, or a majority of them, shall have the power to appoint all officers necessary and proper for such associations, and to make all contracts which may be necessary for carrying into effect the provisions of this charter, not conflicting with the constitution and laws of this State, and that when such board of Directors is elected, their powesre to be the same as are herein Conferred upon the Commissioners, and the powers of the Commissioners to cease.</p>
<pb n="1377" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 6. That the Commissioners or Directors shall have the power to dispose of the shares in said capital stock in such manner and on such terms as they may deem best for the interests of the company; any agreement in writing whereby any person shall be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />come a subscriber, may be enforced against him according to its terms, and all contracts made by the company shall be in writing, and executed in such form as the Commissioners or Directors may adopt in their by-laws.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the said corporation shall have the power to ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriate such lands on the immediate route of said road, and within one hundred feet on each side of it, as may be necessary for the construction of said road or roads, upon compensating the owner or claimants of such lands for the same at their cash valua<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, and for such further amount of damages which such owners ipay sustain in consequence of said road; which compensa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion and damages shall be ascertained in the following manner: the corporation shall present a petition to the Chief Jnstice of the county in which such land or lands may be situated, designating what lands are required for the use of said road or roads, and stat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing as near as can be ascertained who are the owners or claimants of said lands; whereupon the Chief-Justice shall appoint a day, not less than twenty days, for more than forty days from the time of filing said application, for the parties interested to appear before him, to ascertain the value of such lands, and the amount of dam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ages to which the owmer may be entitled; twenty days notice of the time and place of such hearing shall be given By notice posted up in three public places in the county, by written notice delivered to such owners or claimants as are residents of the county, and on the day so appointed by the said Chief-Justice, or on any subsequent day to which such proceedings may be adjourned, and if the parties cannot agree upon a valuation, then the Chief-Justice shall, with the assistance of the clerk of the county court, draw from the jury boxes of said county the names of six disinterested free-holders of, and residents of said county, and said Chief Justice shall issue a subpoena directed to the Sheriff or other legal officer, commanding him to summon said jurors to appear before him at his office on a day to be named in such subpoena; on the day named for the meet<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing of said jury, if the whole number do not attend, the Chief<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Justice shall in like manner draw other jurors to sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ply the places of those who fail to attend; who shall be subpeoned to attend forthwith, and when a jury of six shall be made up, the Chief-Justice shall administer to them an oath <pb n="1378" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>or affirmation, well and truly to enquire, and a true appraisement make of the cash value of the land or lands sought to be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />demned by said corporation, under the provisions of this act, and the damages which the owner or claimant may sustain in conse<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quence of said road. The said jury or any member thereof shall have power to examine on oath or affirmation, to be administered by any of said jurors, all such witnesses as may be brought before them by any party interested, and may continue their session from day to day not exeeeeding three days; a majority of said jury shall agree to the appraisement, which shall be in writing and signed by those who agree to it, and shall contain a particular description of The land or lands appraised, said appraisement shall be returned to, and recorded in the office of the county clerk of the county court in which the land is situated; upon payment of the amount of such appraisement to the owner of the land appraised, or to the county Treasurer of the county in which the land is situated, for the use of the owner or claimant, said land shall be considered as condemned and appropriated to the use and benefit of said corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion for the purposes contemplated by this act. Should the ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jority of the jury not be able to agree on an appraisement, other jurors shall be drawn and subpoened, and proceed in the like man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner as the original jury, until an appraisement is made. The said jurors shall each be allowed one dollar and fifty cents per day for their services, and they shall assess a reasonable amount for the costs of the proceedings directed by this section, including their own pay, which shall be paid by said corporation to the Chief<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Justice for the use of the parties for whom it is assessed.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That said company may acquire by purchase, donation or in payment for stock, such real estate as the Commissioners or Directors may think desirable to aid in the construction or main<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tenance of said road, and such real estate so acquired, as well as the road itself, may be mortgaged by a vote of three-fifths of the Directors, for the purpose of raising money on their bonds for the construction of said road.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That said company shall have power to borrow money on their bonds secured by mortgage as in the preceding section, at such rates of interest as the Directors may deem expedient.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That a vote of two-thirds of the stockholders shall be sufficient at any time to remove any board of Direc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors and appoint others in their stead; provided, that any meet<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />-, ing for such purpose shall only be called by a notice to that effect, <pb n="1379" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>published for four successive weeks in the nearest newspaper, and signed by one-fourth of the stockholders.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That the first election for Directors shall take place at such time as the Commissioners shall appoint within nine months from the 1st day of February, 1853, and be conducted in such manner and form as they shall adopt, adhering to the rights of the stock-holders and the general provisions of this charter, the place of said first election being the town of Indianola, and that all subsequent elections shall take place in twelve months after the first election, and any vacancy by death, resignation or otherwise shall be filled by the Directors.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That the counties and corporate towns through which the road may pass shall have power to take one-third part of the capital stock of the company, and issue their bonds to the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany for the same, bearing eight per cent interest payable semi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />annually; provided, the question of taking the same be first sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitted to the legal voters of the said towns and counties, and two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds of the votes cast be in favor of said subscription; and pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that clue notice of such meeting of the legal voters be pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished by the county Court and town council for at least four weeks before said meeting, and that the said towns and counties shall have power to levy and collect such taxes upon the real and per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonal estate of said towns and counties, not being more than twenty-five cents annually, upon every one hundred dollars of tax<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able property, as may be necessary for the punctual payment of the interest and principal of said bonds.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That said company shall also have the right, provided, no other chartered company now existing shall make a railway or commence the construction of a railway within one year from the first day of February, 1852, within twenty miles of a direct line from the town of Indianola to Victoria, to change their Plank and Turnpike road into an iron railway for the running of cars by steam, should they hereafter deem the Plank road insufficient, with such rights, privileges and guarantees, and under such restrictions, so far as the same are applicable, as are prescribed by &#8220;an act to incorporate the San Antonio Railroad company,&#8221; approved Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember 5, 1850, and the act supplementary thereto, approved Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary 14th, 1852.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That the company shall be, and are hereby author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized to charge and collect the following rates of toll, viz: for ox wagons with two or four yoke of oxen, five cents per mile; for horse wagons with four or six horses, five cents per mile; <pb n="1380" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>for ox carts one or three yoke of oxen, four cents per mile; for pleasure carriages, or two horse wagons, four cents per mile; for man and horse one cent per mile; for horses, mules, cattle, each one-half cent per mile.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. That all real estate not used by said company in actual occupation for the ordinary purposes of the road, shall be alienated within ten years from the granting of this charter, or shall become forfeited to the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. That if this road is not commenced within one year from the first day of February, 1853, and one-half thereof com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleted within two years thereafter, then this charter shall be null and void.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize Stephen P. Holingsworth and his associates to construct a Bridge across the Sabine River.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Stephen P. Hollingsworth and other persons whom he may choose to associate with him be, and they are hereby au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized to construct a bridge across the Sabine river, at any point he or they may select, in the counties of Busk and Harrison, between a ferry on said river known as APalling&#8217;s Perry, and another known as Bamsdale&#8217;s Perry; where he or they may be the owner of the lands on either side of the said river; provided, that he or they shall cause to be paid or pay to the owner or owners of said lands on the opposite side of said river, all such damages as he or they may sustain by the construction of said bridge, to be ascertained in the following manner, to wit: first, the parties shall have the right to agree upon the amount of damages; second, if they can<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />not agree as to the amount of damages, then it shall be lawful for the said Hollingsworth and his associates, or the owner or owners of the land on the opposite side of the river, or both, to apply to the county court of the county in which such lands may be situated, for the appointment of three Commissioners to assess the damages sustained by the owner or owners of said land, and it shall be the duty of said court to appoint said Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />misioners to assess the damages, and said Commissioners, or a majority of them, shall proceed to assess the damages, and in a <pb n="1381" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>reasonable time make their report to said court in writing, under oath, which report shall be recorded in the office of the clerk of the county court, and upon the payment of the amount of dam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ages assessed by the Commissioners, and all costs incurred by said appointment, to the person or persons entitled to receive the same, or in case the person or persons entitled to receive the same shall refuse to receive the amount so adjudged, then and in that case the amount of damages shall be paid or deposited with the clerk of the county court, by the said Hollingsworth or his associates, and after the payment of the amount of damages as aforesaid, in either case, then the said Hollingsworth and his associates shall have the right to construct the said bridge as aforesaid, and shall have the right of way to open a road from the same to the town of Marshall in Harrison county, and also to the town of Henderson in the county of Rusk, and also through the county of Harrison in the direction of Shreevesport, in the State of Louisiana; provided, that said bridge shall be so constructed as not to obstruct or hinder the navigation of said river.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the rates ot toll to be charged and collected by said Hollingsworth and his associates, shall be fixed by the county court of the county of Rusk, and the license tax shall be levied by the same court; provided, that said Hollingsworth and his asso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciates shall not be required to pay a license tax in but one county on said bridge.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That said Hollingsworth and his associates shall, in all respects, be governed by the laws of this State regulating roads, bridges and ferries, when the same shall not conflict with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That said Hollingsworth and his associates shall have the right to the use of a sufficient quantity of timber for the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struction of all causeways and bridges that may be necessary on the roads mentioned in section one, to be taken from the lands adjacent to said road or roads, for which they shall pay a reason<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able compensation, to be determined as before provided, by the county court, in case any party shall object to the cutting of timber for such purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That said parties shall commence the building of said bridge within one year from the passage of this act. and have the same completed within five years, and in ease of failure thereof, they shall forfeit all privileges granted by this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="1382" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Incorporate the Mount Enterprise Male and Female Academy.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That William H. Estell, David Collins, A. P. Galloway, M. D., Charles Vincent, Bird Linthicum, William Hays, John L. Salmon, Robert E. Wynn, S. W. March, M. D., G. Booker, Thomas Jones and William Horle, M. D., and their successors in office be, and they are hereby constituted a board of trustees of an institu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of learning established at Mount Enterprise in the county of Eusk, which said institution is hereby incorporated by the name of the Mount Enterprise Male and Female Academy; by which name it may sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, and buy and sell property both real and personal and mixed, hold and enjoy the same; the said institution may have a common seal for the trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />action of its business, which seal it shall have power to alter at pleasure.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That five of the trustees shall constitute a quorum to do business; they shall have power to make such by-laws and regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lations as they may think necessary for the government of the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution and its finances; provided, such by-laws and regulations are not inconsistent with the United States, and the laws and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution of this State; they shall also have power to elect their own officers; they shall also have power to elect a President of said in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution, who shall have authority to appoint or dismiss his as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sistants; it shall require a majority of the board to dismiss or re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />move the President, and in case of the death or resignation of the President, to elect a successor.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The board of trustees shall hold their offices during good behaviour, and that in case of death, resignation, permanent absence or inability to perform the duty of a trustee, they shall have power to fill the vacancy; provided, that if three of the mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers of the board be at the time of filling such vacancy members of the same denomination or sect, a fourth shall not be selected from the same denomination or sect; and be it further provided, that no member of the board shall forfeit his right as trustee in consequence of any change of his religious views or relations; and, further provided, that five of the members of said board shall be and reside within the limits of said institution.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the board of trustees shall have power to regn<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1383" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="29" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>late and fix the salaries of all officers connected with said institu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, and to regulate the price of tuition and the length of the ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sions.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the President of the Academy shall be ex-officio President of the board of trustees, and shall have power to con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vene said board whenever he may think proper, but shall have no vote except in case of a tie; and no other member of the board shall hold any office in said institution; provided, that in case the President should refuse to call the board together at any time upon the application of at least three of the members of the board, then, and in that case, they shall have the right to do so, and elect a President pro tem to preside.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That no religious test shall be required of any member of the board, officer of the institution, or student.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That all donations and bequests to said institution shall be good and binding although the corporate name of the same may not have been properly stated by the person making such bequest or donation.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That the seal of the corporation with the attestation of the Secretary and the signature of the President, or in his absence, five of the board of trustees shall be sufficient to authenticate any act of the corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That said institution shall not hold more than fifty thousand dollars worth of property, over and above the institution, buildings and ground on which they may be situated, and the funds belonging or in anywise appertaining to said Academy shall not be diverted from the object for which the same was donated, nor shall any man or person be allowed to vend any ardent spirits under the penalty of one hundred dollars for each and every such offence, within one mile of said Academy.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the heirs of L. Gilbert.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Thomas Johnson. Esq., District Attorney of the Third Judicial District, for the Republic of Texas, was em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ployed by Anson Jones. President of the Republic, to defend two certain suits brought in the District Court of said Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1384" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="30" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>trict, by Empresarios, against the President of the said Repub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic for large amounts of land, and the said Anson Jones, then President, agreed to pay said Johnson for his services the sum of five hundred dollars, each suit; and whereas, the said Johnson assigned to L. Gilbert five hundred dollars of his said fees, and received from said Gilbert, then Treasurer of Washington Coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty, the consideration therefor, and agreed to have that amount placed to the credit of said Gilbert upon his account as Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer aforesaid, who was then, and still is indebted to the State of Texas; and whereas, said Johnson and Gilbert both departed this life without having the said amount credited as aforesaid; and whereas, said Johnson did faithfully attend to said suits and defended one of them successfully, and defeated said suit; there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature or the State of Texas, That the Comptroller be, and he is hereby authorized to allow the estate of L. Gilbert, former Treasurer of Washington county, a credit of five hundred dollars, for the claim of Thomas Johnson, late District Attorney of the Third Judicial District, for his services in attending to the said Empresario&#8217;s suits against the Bepublic of Texas.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the town of Richmond.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the citizens of the town of Richmond, in Fort Bend county, be, and they are hereby declared a body corporate, by the name and style of the corporation of the town of Richmond, and by that name may sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, and may hold and dispose of real and personal estate; provided such real property is situated within the limits of said corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the limits of said corporation shall be as follows: To commence at the upper river corner of Morton&#8217;s labor, running back from the river with the upper line of said labor, and extending continuously to a point one mile from the court house; from thence across the Borden tract to a point one mile from the court house; from thence in a direct line to the <pb n="1385" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="31" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>present river corner of Mrs, L. H. Long; from thence to run with the river bank to the place of beginning.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That an election for Mayor, five Aldermen, a Treasurer, Recorder and a Constable, shall be held as soon as practicable, after the passage of this act, by the Chief Justice, or one of the Commissioners of Fort Bend county, according to the laws govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing elections generally, and annually thereafter for a similar pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose, an election shall be conducted by the Mayor, or a majority of the Aldermen acting at the time of such election, and the per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons elected shall continue in office one year, or until their suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessors are duly qualified. And the annual elections for Mayor and Aldermen shall be held at such place in the town of Richmond as may be disignated by the board, for the convenience of the peo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ple.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That whenever a vacancy shall occur in the office of Mayor, a majority of the Aldermen acting shall order and conduct an election to fill such vacancy, and the person so elected shall hold his office until the next regular election, or until his succes<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sor be duly qualified, and in case of the death, resignation or re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />moval of any Alderman, Treasurer or Constable, the Mayor shall order an election under such rules and regulations as may be pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by the board, to fill such vacancy.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That no person shall be eligible to any office under the provisions of this charter who is not a citizen of this State, and a resident within the limits of the corporation; nor shall any person have a right to vote for officers, who is not a citizen and resides within its limits.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the Mayor shall be President of the Board of Aldermen; that three of the members of said board shall constitute a quorum to transact business, and that said board shall enact such by-laws for the government of said town, not inconsistent with the constitution and laws of the State, as may be deemed proper, and may impose fines for the disobedience of the same, not exceeding one hundred dollars for each offence.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the board ot Aldermen shall have and, exer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cise control over the public squares and streets of said town, and may compel all free male citizens, ministers of the Gos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pel excepted, over the age of seventeen years, and under that of forty-five, to work on the same; provided, that such person shall not be required to work more than six days in any one year, and shall be exempt from other road duty in said county, and the board may impose such fines on defaulters as they may <pb n="1386" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="32" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>deem necessary, in which they shall be governed by the laws of this State regulating roads.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That the board of Aldermen shall have power to levy a tax on all persons and property, both real and personal, in siad town, subject to taxation by the laws of the State; provided, that the tax on the property shall not in any one year exceed one<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />half of one per cent ad valorem on such property, and no tax shall be levied unless by a vote of two-thirds of said board; which shall be assessed and collected by the Constable, in the same manner as the State tax is collected.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That all offences against the by-laws be presented before the Mayor, and governed by the law governing Justice&#8217;s Courts; and the Constable shall execute and return all writs issued by the Mayor, in the same manner as is provided by the law defining the duties of Constables.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That the Constable shall give bond and security as required by other Constables, and shall have the same powers, and be entitled to the same fees for similar services.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That the Mayor of said town shall be entitled to such fees as may be allowed Justices of the Peace for similar services, together with such other compensation as may be allowed him by said board of Aldermen.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That the Aldermen shall be entitled to one dollar for each day they may be required to sit as such Aldermen.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That the Treasurer shall keep safely all the monies of said corporation; shall pay out the same upon the order of the board, and he shall give bond until security payable to the Mayor, in such sum as may be deemed proper, conditioned for the faithful performance of his duties, to be approved by the board, and he shall be allowed such compensation as may be specified by the board of Aldermen.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That the mayor be, and he is hereby vested with all the power and jurisdiction of a Justice of the Peace within the limits of said corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. That this act take effect and be in full force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the city of Brownsville.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of <pb n="1387" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="33" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Texas, That the citizens of Cameron county, in the State of Texas, residing within the limits of that section of territory, situated and lying on the left margin of the Rio Grande, in the county of Cam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eron aforesaid, formerly a part of the town tract of four leagues of land (ejidos) of the city of Matamoras, in the Republic of Mexico, be, and they are hereby declared a body politic and corporate, by the name and title of the &#8220;City of Brownsville,&#8221; and by that name may sue and be sued, implead and be impleaded, in all courts, and in all actions and matters whatsoever, and by the same name may, by deed of gift, grant or purchase, hold and dispose of any estate, real or personal, within the limits of said city, for the use of the corporation; and may have a common seal which they may alter and change at pleasure.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That it shall be the duty of the citizens of said corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion to elect a Mayor, nine Aldermen, a Marshal, Treasurer, Secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary, and an Assessor and Collector of taxes.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The Mayor, with a majority of said Aldermen, shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute a quorum for the transaction of business; they shall form the City Council, and the Mayor shall preside at their meetings.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The Treasurer, Marshall and Assessor and Collector of taxes shall give bond to the Mayor of said city in such sum as the said Council shall determine, which bonds shall be for the faithful performance of their respective duties, as they shall be from time to time defined by said council, and if either said Treasurer, Mar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />shal or Assessor and Collector of taxes, shall refuse or neglect to give bond as required by said Council within such reasonable time as they may be required by said Council, such Treasurer, Marshal or Assessor and Collector of taxes may be removed, and his office de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clared by said Council to be vacant, and a new election ordered to supply such vacancy. It shall be the duty of the Marshal to at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tend upon the Council and execute all process to him lawfully directed by the Mayor, and generally to do and perform such duties as are performed by Constables in courts of Justice&#8217;s of the Peace.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the City Council shall have full power to make and pass such by-laws and ordinances as they shall deem neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary to maintain the cleanliness and salubrity of said city, to insure the safety and convenience of passing in the streets, squares and alleys; to establish and regulate such common schools as they may direct, to organize and regulate a fire department for the purpose of extinguishing and preventing conflagrations; to prevent the storage of powder within the <pb n="1388" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="34" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>limits of said city; to establish a system of police for the main<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tenance of public order and tranquility; to permit theatres, shows or other public amusements, under such regulations and restric<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions as they may direct; to establish one or more market places, and to regulate the same; to take charge and superintendence of all streets, roads and alleys and ways, appoint the necessary overseers for the same, and to enforce labor thereupon in the same manner and with the same effect as such authority is now authorized by the county court; to enact all ordinances to carry this act into ef<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fect, and to fix such penalties thereto as they may determine; to appoint all subordinate officers necessary; to grant licenses to all billiard tables, coffee houses, groceries, or any place of amusement in said city, and to determine the amount to be paid for such licenses; to have and exercise the power of laying, levying and col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lecting taxes upon all subjects of taxation within their corporate limits upon which a tax may be levied by the State; provided, said tax shall not exceed in any one year one-fourth of the amount of the tax levied by the State upon such subjects of taxation, and to divide said city into three wards, and after the first election, there shall be elected three Aldermen for each ward.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The Mayor shall have the power and concurrent juris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diction of a justice of the peace, over all such criminal matters as may arise within said corporate limits, and which by existing laws are cognizable before a justice of the peace. He shall have juris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diction over all penalties for violation of the ordinances of said city, and shall have the right to issue process, hear and determine suits arising from violations of city ordinances, and to enforce col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lection of judgments rendered thereupon by execution.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The Mayor shall have the right to collect fees for services rendered according to the fees established for Jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tices of the Peace, and such other fees as are by law given to him, as such Mayor ex-officio, but shall have no other salary. The Marshal shall have and receive the fees of a Constable, but no other compensation for his service. The Treasurer shall be entitled to receive, and may retain such amount as the Coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cil may in its discretion allow, not exceeding five per cent, on all moneys that may come into his hands by virtue of his office. The Assessor and Collector shall be entitled to receive and map retrain in his hands such amount as the Council may in its dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cretion allow, not exceeding five per cent, on all moneys that may come to his hands. The Secretary shall be entitled to <pb n="1389" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="35" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>charge the same fees as those allowed by law to county clerks for similar services, and the Council shall be allowed to expend any sum not exceeding two hundred dollars in one year for Attorney&#8217;s fees.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That all property together with all rights in action and claims to property, of any and all kinds, which were held, owned, occupied and enjoyed by the citizens of said city, under the act entitled &#8220;an act to incorporate the city of Brownsville,&#8221; and which act was approved January 24, 1850, are hereby vested in the citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zens of Brownsville, and all liabilities incurred by said citizens under said act of incorporation, shall stand and be against the property vested in said citizens by this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That the first election shall be held for the officers under this act, under the direction of the Chief-Justice of said county of Cameron, after having given ten days notice thereof, the returns shall be made to the Chief-Justice on the second day after the election; he shall thereupon open the returns and give cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates of election to those entitled to the same. The election for all officers shall be held annually thereafter, under the direction of the Mayor, at least twenty days before the expiration of the term of office, and in case of vacancy by death, resignation or otherwise, the vacancy or vacancies shall be filled by new elections to be directed by the Mayor, and in case the office of Mayor shall be va<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cant, then the Aldermen shall elect one of their own body to act as Mayor until the next annual election. After the division of said city into wards, the election of officers under this act shall be held in the several wards. The city council shall appoint the pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />siding officers. The election shall be conducted in conformity with the law regulating elections. The returns shall be made to the City Council within three days after such elections, the city Coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cil shall thereupon open the said returns, examine the same and give certificates of election to those found duly elected.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That no person shall be eligible to any office in this corporation, or entitled to vote for city officers, unless he be a citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zen of this State, and shall have resided in the corporation limits of the city for at least six months next preceding the election.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That all laws and parts of laws conflicting with this act, are so far repealed as not to interfere with this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That this act shall be in force from and after its pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1390" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="36" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to An Act to incorporate the Vicksburg and El Paso Railroad Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That so much of the first section of the above recited act be so changed as to read as follows, to wit: That the name of L. C. Clopton be stricken from said section, and in lieu thereof, the names of Joseph McDougal, Thomas H. Rogers, Adam Sullivan, Josiah Starr, C. D. Holbert, Mason Moselv and Jacob Fisher, be incorporated in said section.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That so much of the seventeenth section of the above recited act, be so modified as to read as follows, to wit: That the first meeting of the Commissioners or directors, appointed by this act, shall be held at such times and places as they may think proper, said Directors may act in person or by proxy.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all laws and parts of laws that conflict with the provisions of this act, be and the same is hereby repealed, and this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to the acts to establish the Galveston and Red River Railway Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the preliminary action of Ebenezer Allen and others associated with him, as Commissioners of the Galveston and Red River Railwaw Company, in commencing the survey and grade of said Rail way, at the city of Houston, is hereby confirmed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Said company is also hereby further authorized and empowered to extend said Railway to the city of Galves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton, and also to make and construct simultaneously with the main Railway, described in the original acts establishing said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, a branch thereof towards the city of Austin, under the same restrictions and stipulations, provided in said original <pb n="1391" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="37" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>acts, and subject to the rights of the State, to regulate the tolls by general laws.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act shall take effect immediately.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Certain persons therein named:</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Landoffice be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue certificates for land to John Sise, for six hundred and forty acres of land; to Thomas Jones, his heirs or assigns, for one-third of a league of land; to the heirs of Samuel McEarly, for one labor of land; to Butler Hughes, for six hundred and forty acres of land; to James Morris, one third of a league of land; to Geo. W. Parrish, three hundred and twenty acres of land; to Kussel Gorman, three hundred and twenty acres of land; to G. W. Browning, one-third of a. league of land; to Jackson J. Walker, three hundred and twenty acres of land; to Charles R. Slaughter, three hundred and twenty acres of land; to William Middleton, his heirs or assigns, six hundred and forty acres of land; to Newton Kimbro, his heirs or assigns, one league and labor of land; to Janies Wallace, his heirs or assigns, one league and labor of land; to Herschell Corzine, his heirs or assigns, one league and labor of land; to the heirs of Thomas Hamilton, one-third of a league of land;-to H. K. Hardin, his heirs or assigns, one-league and labor of land; to Jno. Hughes, three hundred and twenty acres of land; to the heirs of John C. Sullivan, three hundred and twenty acres of land; to the heirs of Lilly or Lvla Forsyth, one league and labor of land; to the heirs of Eli W. Lawler, twelve hundred and eighty acres of land; to Edward Morrison, six hundred and forty acres of land; to the heirs of Albert Jackson, six hundred and forty acres of land; to Margaret Clark, six hundred and forty acres of land; to Andrew R. Jones, three hundred and twenty acres of land; to Mary Anthony, alias Mary Collins, six hundred and forty acres of land; to the heirs of Hiram Frilev, one league and labor of land; to Matthew Cartwright, two-thirds of a league and one labor of land; to William McCoy, six hundred and forty acres of land; to Carl Dorr, three hundred and twenty acres of land; that the certificate issued to Silas M. <pb n="1392" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="38" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Grace by the Board of Land Commissioners in and for the county of Harrison, on the fifth day of June, 1843, for twelve hundred and eighty acres of land be, and the same is hereby confirmed and made good, and that the Commissioner of the General Landoffice is hereby directed to issue a patent to said Grace on any location which has been or may be made by virtue of said certificate, on vacant and unappropriated lands; to Elizabeth Berry, widow of William Landrum, one league and labor of land; to James W. Man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ning, one-third of a league of land; to the heirs of Norman Aus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tin, one-third of a league of land; to Jno. T. Davidson, one-third of a league of land; to William B. Willis, one league and labor of land; to William Forbes, three hundred and twenty acres of land; to the heirs of Edward Little, eight hundred and thirty-six acres of land; to John Stryker, one league and labor of land; to Levin S. Largent, six hundred and forty acres of land; to Patrick May, one-quarter league of land; to the heirs of George Creath, one<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />third of a league of land; to E. S. C. Robertson, administrator of Sterling C. Robertson, deceased, one league and labos of land, headright of deceased; to Robert Tippett, three hundred and twen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty acres of land; to the heirs of Archibald Swords, one-third of a league of land: to John H. Bostick, one-third of a league of land; to G. C. Blackburn, three hundred and twenty acres of land; to Cyrus W. Egery, one-third of a league of land; to Thomas Dean, one-third of a league of land; to Francis Moore, Jr., two-thirds of a league and one laber of land; to Robert English, three hundred and twenty acres of land; to George Joy, six hundred and forty acres of land; to Omy Weir his heirs, or assigns, certificate for three hundred and twenty acres of land, amount of conflict of Omy Weir&#8217;s survey with W. Prissick&#8217;s survey; to Maria Jesusa Trevinio, one league and labor of land; to the heirs of T. Benson, one-third of a league of land, confirmation of six hundred and forty acres of land, certificate number two hundred and twenty-four, is<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sued in Fayette county to Isaac Mullens in consequence of clerical error in its issue; to Joseph Bays, one league and labor of land; to the heirs of Richard Hall, one-third of a league of land: to the heirs of Shadrach Goody, deceased, six hundred and forty acres of laird; to David Andrews, his heirs or assigns, one league and labor of land: to Warren Lyons, three hundred and twenty acres of land: to the heirs of Guadalupe Martinez, formerly a resident of Nacogdoches, one league and labor of land; to Daniel Par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ker. one-third of a league of land to which he is entitled as an <pb n="1393" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="39" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>augmentation to the heirs of Samuel P. Williams, one-third of a league of land; to Janies Crossland, six hundred and forty acres of land; to the heirs of Wesley Fisher, deceased, one league of land; to the heirs of John Norman, deceased, one league and labor of land; to the heirs Walker Reid, twelve hundred and eighty acres of land, for headright and military services; to the heirs or assigns of Christopher Yandevere, deceased, for two-thirds of a league and labor of land, by virtue of certificate No. 117, Second Class, issued to him by the Board of Land Commissioners of Montgomery coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty; to William H. Kennedy, eight hundred and thirty-six acres of land; to the heirs of Daniel W. Cloud, six hundred and forty acres of land; to the heirs of Joseph Bayless, six hundred and forty acres of land; to the heirs of Peter J. Bailey, six hundred and forty acres of land.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That no certificate which may be issued under the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act to the heirs of persons deceased, shall be sold by any Administrator or otherwise, until the same shall have been located, surveyed and patented.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That no certificate shall be issued under the provisions of this act, when a certificate for a like quantity of land, or in satisfaction of a claim to land has been previously issued or granted by any authority of the Republic or State of Texas, in the name of, or upon the rights or claims of any person named herein, and any certificate which may be issued contrary to the provisions of this section shall be null and void.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved; <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the town of San Patricio, in the connty of San Patricio.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the citizens of the town of San Patricio be, and they are hereby declared a body politic and corporate, and by that name and style of the corporation of the town of San Patricio, and by that name may sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, and may have a common seal and change the same at pleasure, and may hold and dispose of real and per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1394" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="40" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>sonal property; provided, the same is within the limits of the cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the boundary and limits of said town, and within which the said corporation shall exercise lawful jurisdiction, shall include and comprehend all that tract of land heretofore originally granted to, and composing said town, by whatever name it may have been designated.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the first election under this charter shall be held by the Chief:-Justice of the county of San Patricio, (after giving ten days notice under the laws now regulating elections) for one Mayor and four Aldermen, and annually thereafter by the Mayor and two Aldermen, or by three Aldermen in case of the absence of the Mayor, or vacancy in that office, and the persons so elected shall continue in office for one year, or until their succes<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sors are duly qualified, and in case a vacancy shall occur in the office of Mayor, any three Aldermen shall order and conduct an election to fill such vacancy, to serve until the next succeeding an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nual election, or until his successor shall be duly qualified, and that if the office of Alderman shall become vacant from death or otherwise, the board shall have power to appoint a successor to fill the unexpired term of such Alderman.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. No person shall be eligible to the office of Mayor or Al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dermen, who is not a citizen and a free-holder, householder, or re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sider in said town, and has not resided six months immediately pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeding the election within the limits of said town.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The Mayor shall be President of the board, and three Aldermen shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness, and said board may enact such by-laws for the government of said town, not inconsistent with the laws of the State, as may be deemed proper, and may inflict such fines not exceeding one hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars, as may be considered necessary.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the board shall have entire control over the streets of said town, may order new streets to be laid out at their discre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, and shall be governed in such cases by the laws of the State relative to roads and highways. That all free males between the ages of eighteen and forty-five years, shall be liable to work on the streets; provided, no person shall be compelled to work more than ten days in any one year, and the board may impose such fines on said defaulters as they may deem necessary, not inconsistent with the laws of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the board shall have power to levy a tax on <pb n="1395" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="41" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>all persons and property real and personal, within the limits of said town subject to taxation by the laws of the State; provided, said tax shall not in any one year exceed one per centum advalorem, on such property, and it shall be assessed and collected (by an offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cer to be appointed by the board,) in the same manner as the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty tax, and the board shall also have power to levy a tax on all taverns, tippling houses, billiard tables, and ten pin alleys in said town.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That all the public property within the limits of said town shall belong to said corporation, and the board may dispose of it in such manner as they may deem to the best interests of said town.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. The board shall have power to constitute and appoint such officers as may be necessary, and to regulate their duties and compensation, and the officers so appointed may be removed at the pleasure of the board, and may be required to give bond with security, payable to the Mayor and his successors in office, in such sum as may be deemed requisite for the faithful performance of their several duties of said offices to which they may be appointed.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That if from any cause the annual election should not be held at the regular time, the Mayor shall call another election immediately, giving at least five days notice, and all elections for Mayor and Aldermen shall commence at ten o&#8217;clock A. M., and shall close at 2 o&#8217;clock P. M., and all persons qualified to vote for members of the Legislature, who shall have resided six months im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mediately preceding an election in the said town, shall be entitled to vote for Mayor and Aldermen.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That the Mayor be, and he is hereby invested with all the powers of a Justice of the Peace within the limits of said town, and that all offences against the by-laws shall be prosecuted before the Mayor in such manner as is provided by law in the act or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganizing Justice&#8217;s courts, and defining the powers and jurisdiction of the same, and the Sheriff or any Constable within the Limits of the town shall execute all writs directed to him by the Mayor.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That the Treasurer shall keep safely all the money of said corporation, and shall pay it out to the order of the board, and shall do such other duties as may be assigned him by the board; he shall give bond and security payable to the Mayor, in such sum as the board may deem proper, conditioned for the faithful performance of the duties of his office, to be <pb n="1396" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="42" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>approved by the Mayor, and shall receive such compensation as may be allowed him by the board.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. That so much of an act entitled an &#8220;act to incorporate the city of San Antonio, and other towns therein named,&#8221; together with the amendments and supplements thereto, so far as the same relates to the town of San Patricio, and all laws and parts of laws conflicting with this act be, and the same are hereby repealed, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXII</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Jim Shaw, a Delaware Indian.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Auditor and Comptroller be, and they are hereby required to audit and allow the claim of Jim Shaw, a Delaware In<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dian, for six hundred dollars, expended by him in the years 1840 and 1841, in the purchase from the Comanche Indians of Mrs. Tidwell and her three children, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the heirs of Stacy Dailey.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Landoffice be, and he is hereby required to issue to the heirs of Stacy Dailey, a cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate for one league and labor of land, which may be surveyed and patented as other first class head right certificates, and that this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1397" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="43" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the city of Indianola.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the citizens of Indianola, in the county of Calhoun, be a body corporate by the name and style of &#8220;the City of In<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dianola,&#8221; and by that name may sue and be sued, plead and be im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleaded, in all courts and in matters and actions whatsoever, and by that name may purchase, hold and dispose of any estate, real or personal, and may have a common seal, which they may alter or change at their pleasure.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the boundaries of said city and the limits within which said corporation shall exercise jurisdiction, shall begin on the north at the mouth of White&#8217;s Bayou; thence down Matagorda Bay, so as to include the harbor in front of Powder Horn Bayou; thence with said Bayou and lake to a point one mile in a straight line south west from the said Bay of Matagorda; thence in a straight line to a point one mile due south-west from the mouth of White&#8217;s Bayou; thence to the said place of beginning; provided, that whenever the proper courts of law shall decide that the titles of Benito Morales and Juan Cano are valid ones, all the lands within their original grants which by this act are placed or de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed within the limits of said corporation, shall be considered as stricken out therefrom and altogether exempted from all the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this charter.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That there shall be elected by the citizens in said cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate limits, annually, by ballot, on the first Monday of January, in each and every year, one Mayor, one Recorder and eight Aider<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men, to serve one year, or until their successors are qualified, who shall constitute the city Council; which election shall be held by the Mayor and two Aldermen, except the first, which shall be held by the Chief-Justice of the county, as early as practicable after the passage of this act, by giving ten days public notice. The city Council, immediately after being qualified, shall appoint one Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer, one Assessor and tax Collector, one Marshal, and such other officers as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this charter. The Treasurer and Assessor and Collector shall each give bond and security for the faithful discharge of their duties, in such an amount and form as the Council may determine. At the first election for Mayor, Recorder and Aldermen, every resident of the city shall be entitled to vote who has resided six months therein, previous to the election, and has paid a State and county tax.</p>
<pb n="1398" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="44" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 4. That any resident of the city who has resided therein for six months preceding the election, and has paid a tax on real estate or on any business upon which a tax has been leyied by the Council, shall be entitled to vote for the Mayor, Recorder and Al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dermen, and shall be eligible to hold office. No person shall hold the office of Mayor or Recorder unless he be a qualified voter for members of the Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That before entering upon the discharge of the duties of their respective offices, the Mayor, Eecorder and Aldermen and other city officers shall take and subscribe an oath to perform the duties thereof to the best of their abilities, which oath the Mayor shall take before the Chief-Justice of the county or a Justice of the Peace, and each of the other officers before the Mayor or Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corder.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the Mayor and Recorder shall have all the au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thority and power of Justices of the Peace, and concurrent juris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diction, civil and criminal, and the Marshal all the authority of a Constable in the county.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the Council shall have full power and authority to make and pass such ordinances and by-laws as they shall deem necessary to maintain the cleanliness of the city, to secure the safe and convenient passage of the streets, sidewalks and public ways, to prevent encroachments on the public grounds, works or city property, order and determine the construction of the side<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />walks at the cost of the proprietors of the lots in front of which the improvements are to be made, to establish an active inspec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion over the conduct of slaves, to determine in what part of the city wooden buildings and wooden chimneys may be erected; to regulate the keeping and sale of gunpowder within the city; to determine the means to be resorted to in order to prevent and extin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />guish conflagration; to establish one or more market places, and to determine the mode of inspection of all comestibles sold publicly; to regulate every thing relating to bakers, butchers, tavern keep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers, oyster houses, restaurats, eating houses and grog shops, except the prices of the articles vended; and to control all public wharves, landing places and bridges within the city limits; to fix a uni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />form rate of drayage, taxes on carriages, omnibuses, hacks and other vehicles; to regulate the rate of fare on the same, and to regulate the price of wharfage and harbor dues; to appoint a city guard or watch, and make such regulations regulating the discipline and management thereof, as may be necessary; to fix uniform prices for license to pedlars and hawkers; to erect all public buildings, and to make all other regulations which <pb n="1399" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="45" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>may contribute to the better administration of the affairs of said corporation, as well as for the maintenance of the tranquility and safety of the same; provided, that no ordinance of said corporation shall be enforced that is contrary to the laws of this State or of the United States. And all official acts of said corporation shall be sanctioned by a majority of all the members present and voting, except the levying of taxes, which shall require the votes of two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds of all the members of said corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That no ordinances shall take effect or be in force until the same has been published for five days in the corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That the city Council shall have power to levy and col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lect a tax not to exceed one per centum ad valorem, on all lots and lands, and an ad valorem tax not to exceed one-fifth of one per centum upon improvements annually, and one-fourth of one per centum on all the slaves within the corporation, for municipal pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poses, also a poll tax of one dollar each on all the males of the age of twenty-one years, who do not pay a tax on property.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That the Council shall have power to levy and collect a tax not to exceed one-fourth of one per centum annually, upon all real estate within the limits of the corporation, for the express purpose of raising a school fund, and the proceeds of said tax shall be applied to no other purpose than that of advancing the cause of education in the town of Indianola.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That a majority of the Aldermen shall constitute a quorum to do business. The Mayor shall preside at all the meet<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings of the Council, (except when prevented by sickness or other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise, when the Aldermen present shall appoint one of their body to preside,) and shall convene the board whenever requested so to do by three of the Aldermen, in writing.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That whenever any order, resolution, by-law or ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nance may be passed by the Council, and is disagreed to by the Mayor, it shall be inoperative, unless the same shall be passed by a majority of the whole number of Aldermen, taken by yeas and nays and recorded upon the journal of proceedings.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That the city Council shall have power to appropriate so much of the revenue of the city to the improvement of the pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic roads within or without the corporation limits, leading into the city, as they in their wisdom may think proper and expedient.</p>
<pb n="1400" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="46" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 14. That all process emanating from the Mayor or Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corder may be executed by the Sheriff, any Constable of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty, or the city Marshal, in the same manner that similar process from the Justices of the Peace are executed.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. That after the expiration of the time prescribed by law for the payment of city taxes, the city Marshal or such officer as the Council may charge therewith, may proceed to seize upon any property, real or personal, the tax on which has not been paid, or that belongs to a delinquent tax payer, and after making publica<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion in some newspaper in the city, or by posting at three public places in said city, if there be no paper, for twenty days, specifying the time and place of sale, with a description of the property, may sell to the highest bidder so much of said property as will pay the taxes thereon, or may be due from such delinquents, as the case may be, together with all costs, and the officer selling shall give the purchaser a certificate, stating the amount of tax and costs paid, and describing the property sold, which shall entitle the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chaser to a deed for said property at the expiration of twelve months, from the Mayor of the city; but such certificate may be redeemed in one year from the day of sale, by the owner of the property sold, or some person for them, by payment of double the amount of tax and costs paid by the holder, which payment may be made either to the city Treasurer for the use of the holder of said certificate, or to the holder thereof in person; but if the cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate of purchase be not redeemed in the time specified, then the holder may demand, and it shall be the duty of the Mayor to give a deed to such holder, conveying all the rights and interests of the person in whose name the property was assessed and sold, which deed shall be signed by the Mayor in his official capacity and coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tersigned by the Recorder under the city seal; provided, that none of such assessments or sales, or other action of said corporation shall ever be made to affect in any manner whatever the rights or titles of those persons who may hold lots or lands within the said corporation limits, under mesne Conveyances from Juan Cano or Benito Morales, made in virtue of grants respectively issued to the said Cano and Morales by the State of Coahuila and Texas, and that nothing contained herein shall be so construed as a recogni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of title in said Cano or Morales or their assigns.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. That whenever it may be deemed necessary the Coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cil shall divide the city into a convenient number of wards, each ward to be represented by at least one Alderman.</p>
<pb n="1401" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="47" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 17. That the Council shall have power to assess and collect for the use of the city, an annual license tax upon all persons pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />suing any trade, occupation or profession, upon which a license tax may be imposed by law, and shall have power to assess and collect a tax upon all public shows, circuses, or other exhibitions for money.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. That the city council shall have power to create a loan and negotiate her bonds to any amount not to exceed forty thousand dollars, for the benefit of the city; provided, that the purpose for which said loan is to be effected shall be made public, and a propo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sition distinctly submitted to the legal voters of the city and sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained by a vote of two-thirds thereof.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to establish the Texas Orphan Asylum.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That there shall be established an Institution to be known and designated the &#8220;Texas Orphan Asylum.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the said Asylum shall have for its object the educa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of orphan children.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the students of said Asylum shall be taught some branch or branches of industry, to be regulated by the Trustees.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the following named persons are here by appointed Trustees of said Asylum: J. Randolph Weir, James S. Hanna, R. J. Swearingen, H. H. Calvert, N. W. Bush, James W. McDade, W. S. Day, Thomas B. White, Miller Francis, D. C. Dickson and A. M. Lewis, who shall hold their office for four years from the passage of this act, and their successors shall be elected by the donors of said Asylum.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the said Trustees shall have power to locate said In<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution, and transact all business connected with said Asylum.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the said Trustees shall elect one of their own body as President, and one to serve as Treasurer, who shall give bond for the faithful performance of his duty; and that the Trustees shall have power to appoint such Clerks, Agents or Professors, to serve as such, as they may deem proper.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the said Trustees shall have power to enact such by-laws as they shall desire; provided, said by-lawt shall not <pb n="1402" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="48" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>conflict with this act, or the Constitution of the State of Texas or of the United States.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That when a vacancy shall occur in the board of Trustees in any way, such vacancy shall be filled by the Board, who shall serve until the regular election shall take place by the donors.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That the President of said Board shall have full power to call an extra meeting whenever he shall deem such meeting ne<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessary, and in the absence of said President, any three members of the Board shall have power to convene said Board; provided, said three members think such meeting requisite.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. A majority of said Board shall constitute a quorum.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That the said board of trustees shall have a seal, such as a majority of the board shall select.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That the Faculty and Trustees of said Asylum shall have full power to grant and confer any degree or degrees in the Arts and Sciences to any of the students of said Asylum, or any person or persons by them deemed worthy, as are generally granted and conferred in any college, and give diplomas or memorials thereof, signed by the Faculty of said Institution, and by the President and Secretary of said Board of Trustees, and sealed by the seal of the Asylum.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That the Texas Orphan Asylum shall be entirely free from the control of any religious sect.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That the names of those who contribute to said Institu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion be inscribed in a book, and that said names be preserved in the archives of the Institution.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. All donations and bequests made to said Asylum shall be good and binding, notwithstanding the misnomer of said Insti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tution by the party making said bequest or donation.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of John Conner, Delaware Chief.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Landoffice be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to John Conner, Delaware Chief, a certificate for one league of land, <pb n="1403" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="49" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>which, said certificate, when issued, may be located, surveyed and patented upon any of the vacant and unappropriated public domain of the State of Texas, upon the same terms and conditions as other certificates or land warrants, under the provisions of the general land law, which certificate shall not be sold or transferred by said Conner, but the land located by virtue thereof, shall be solely for the use of himself and family; provided, that such location or survey shall not be made within the limits of the Colony of the German Emigration company, hertofore Fisher and Miller&#8217;s grant; and pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that he shall not be required to pay dues or office fees there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />on, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Cold Spring Female Academy.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That John B. Johnson, Westley Ross, Arnett Harold, John W. Saunders, Henry Jallet&#8212;&#8212;Carnes, James Davis,&#8212;&#8212;Slade, William Vance, James McCardle, &#8212;&#8212; Lisle, John Manor, Wm. McCormick and their successors in office, be, and they are hereby constituted a board of Trustees of a Collegiate Institute near Cold Spring, in the county of Polk, to be known as the Cold Spring Fe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />male Institute, by which name they may sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, buy, sell and hold property, real and personal and mixed, and the said Trustees may have and use a common seal for the transaction of their business.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. A majority of the Trustees shall constitute a quorum to transact all ordinary business of the said Institute. They shall have power to elect their own officers and to make their own by-laws; provided, such by-laws are not inconsistent with the provisions of this charter, or the laws or constitution of the State of Texas; and further provided, that it shall require the concurrence of two-thirds of said Trustees to elect or remove the president or any one of the professors.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The Institute shall have power to confer the usual de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />grees upon females distinguished in science and literature, and upon deserving students, and to grant diplomas for the same; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that such diplomas shall be first signed by a majority of the faculty of said Institute.</p>
<pb n="1404" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="50" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 4. That said Trustees shall have the power of fixing the salaries of all officers connected with the Institute, and of filling all vacancies which may occur in their body.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. No religious test shall ever be required of any president, professor or tutor in said Institute.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. All donations and bequests made to said Institute, shall be good and binding, notwithstanding the misnomer of said Insti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tute, on the party making the bequest or donation.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The said Institute shall not hold real estate exceeding one hundred thousand dollars in value, and it shall never be under the control of any particular denomination of Christians or religious sect.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Antonio Menchaca.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Landoffice be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Antonio Menchaca a certificate for one league of land, to be located upon any vacant and unappropriated domain of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Upon, the return of said certificate with legal field-notes of the survey of the same to the General Landoffice, it shall be the duty of the Commissioner to issue to the said Antonio Menchaca, if alive, or to his heirs, a patent for the same upon the payment of the usual fees.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Marshall Railroad Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That William Evans, William T. Scott, H. L. Berry, P. Murrah, M. J. Hall, T. A. Patillo, Joseph Taylor, and their asso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciates be, and are hereby created and established a body corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rate and politic, under the name and title of the Marshall Bailroad Company, with the capacity, in said corporate name, <pb n="1405" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="51" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>to make contracts, to have succession and a common seal, to make laws for its governient and the regulation of its affairs, to sue and be sued, to plead and be impleaded, and to grant and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive, and generally to do and perform all such acts and things as may be necessary or proper for or incident to the fulfilment of its obligations, or the maintenance of its rights under this act, and consistent with the constitution of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said company is hereby invested with the right to locate, construct, own and maintain a railing company, commenc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing at a suitable point and connecting with the New Orleans, Texas and Pacific Bailway, and thence running by such course as said company shall decree and determine to be most suitable, to Mar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />shall in Harrison county, with the right of owning and maintain<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing such branches of said railway as they may deem expedient.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the parties thus named in this act are hereby ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed commissioners, and invested with the right of forming and organizing said company, and generally of exercising the powers of directors until directors are chosen or appointed by such persons as may subscribe to the stock of said company, when the powers of the commissioners shall cease.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the capital stock of said company, to consist of all its property, real and personal, franchises and rights of property, shall be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, each share entitling the owner thereof to one vote by himself or proxy, at all meetings of said company; said shares shall be deemed personal estate, and shall be transferable by any convey<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance in writing, recorded by the Treasurer in books kept by him at his office, or in such manner as the by-laws of said company shall provide.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the immediate government and direction of the af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fairs of said company shall be vested in a board of not less than six directors, who shall elect one of their own number as President of said company; no person shall be eligible to the office of director unless an owner of at least five shares of the stock of said company; the directors shall have power to fill any vacancy that may occur in saidboard from non-election, death or otherwise, and may appoint a secretary, treasurer and such other officers and agents as they may consider necessary, and prescribe and require bonds for the faithful performance of their duties; they may, if not otherwise provided for by the by-laws, determine the manner of conducting all meet<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings, the number of members that shall constitute a quorum to do business, and do or cause to be done all other lawful matters and <pb n="1406" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="52" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>things which they may deem necessary and proper in conducting the affairs of the company; they shall keep or cause to be kept, accurate records of all meetings of the directors and company, and accurate books of accounts of the company, and all ther books neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary and proper to be kept by such company, which shall be opened to the inspection of the stockholders; a majority of the bord of di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rectors shall have the authority of a full board, and all conveyances and contracts in writing, executed by the President and counter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />signed by the Secretary, or any other officer or person authorized by the directors under the seal of the company, and in pursuance of a vote of said directors, shall be valid and binding.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the shares may be disposed of and books opened for subscriptions thereto, in such manner and on such terms as said commissioners shall determine will be for the best interests of said company, and any agreement in writing by which any per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son shall become a subscriber to the capital stock of said company, may be enforced against him according to its terms; and if any subscriber shall fail to pay any amount due upon shares subscribed by him according to the terms of his subscription, the directors may sell at auction and transfer to the purchaser the shares of such delinquent; and if the proceeds of sale shall not be sufficient to pay the amount due on said subscription, with interest and charges, such delinquent shall be held liable to the company for the de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficiency, and if the proceeds shall exceed the amount so due, with interest and charges, said delinquent shall be entitled to the sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plus.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That it shall be lawful for the company to enter upon and purchase, or otherwise take and hold any land necessary for the purpose of establishing and constructing said railway, with all necessary depots and other buildings; and if they shall not be able to obtain said lands by agreement with the owner thereof, they shall pay therefor such compensation as shall be determined in the manner provided by the following section: Provided, that the lands so taken for the road bed shall not exceed two hundred feet in width, and for depots and other buildings only such further amount as shall be needed for such purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That any person, where land has been taken as aforesaid without agreement or satisfactory compensation, may apply to the District Court of the county in which said land is situated, for the appointment of, and said Court shall thereupon appoint three disinterested freeholders of the county, who shall appoint <pb n="1407" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="53" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>a time and place to hear the applicant and the company, to whom shall be given by said freeholders reasonable notice of said time and place; and said freeholders shall, after being sworn and after due hearing of the parties, determine the amount of compensation, if any, to which the applicant may be entitled, and make return of their award to the next succeeding term of said Court; and said award, if not rejected by said Court for sufficient cause there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />shown, shall be entered up as the judgment of said Court. In determining the question of compensation, said freeholders shall be governed by the actual value of the land at the time it was taken, taking into consideration the benefit or injury done to other lands and property of the owner by the establishment of said rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />way; and if the amount of compensation awarded by said freehold<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers shall not exceed the amount offered by said company prior to said application to the Court, the applicant shall pay the costs of the proceedings, otherwise the company shall pay the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That it shall be the duty of said company, whenever any State or county road now by law established, shall be crossed by the tract of said railway, to make and keep in repair good and sufficient causeways at such crossings; and in all cases where any persons shall own lands on both sides of said railway, and there shall be no other convenient access from one part to the other, such owner shall have the right of passage, free of cost, at all rea<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonable times, across the track of said railway.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That this company is hereby required, at all reasonable times and for a reasonable compensation, to draw over the road the passengers, merchandize and cars of any other railroad corpor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ation which has been or may hereafter be authorized by the legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature to enter with their railroad and connect with the railroad of this company; and if the respective companies shall be unable to agree upon the compensation aforesaid, it shall be the duty of the president of each company to select each one man as a commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner, and the two commissioners so selected shall choose a third, in case of disagreement, neither of whom shall be a stockholder in either road or interested therein, and they shall fix the rates, which shall not be changed for one year from the time of going into ef<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fect. The said commissioners shall also fix the stated periods at which said cars shall be drawn as aforesaid, having reference to the convenience and interests of said corporations and the public who shall be accommodated thereby. The right and power is <pb n="1408" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="54" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>specially conferred on said company to contract with any railroad company chartered by this State, for the performance of like trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />port; and in case of disagreement between said companies, the same shall be referred and settled as aforesaid, and be binding for one year as aforesaid.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That said company may acquire real estate by gift or purchase, and that such commissioners hereinbefore mentioned shall have full authority to solicit and receive subscriptions and conveyances of land to said company until the time fixed for the first meeting of such commissioners, which authority may be then extended by said meeting, which said land so obtained shall be alienated in the following manner: one-fourth in six years, one<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fourth in eight years, one-fourth in ten years and one-fourth in twelve years from the time the same was acquired.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That if the tract of this railway shall cross any naviga<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ble stream, it shall do it in such a way as not to obstruct its naviga<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That said company shall have the right to demand and receive such, rates and prices for the transportation of passengers and freight, as they may thing proper to establish, not to exceed five cents per mile for passengers, and fifty cents per hundred pounds for freight for every hundred miles the same may be car<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ried.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That if any person shall wilfully injure or obstruct said railway or its property, such person may be punished when prose<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cuted by indictment for said offence, in due course of law, and also liable to action by said company or any person whatever who may suffer in person or property from said wilful obstruction, for the amount of damages occasioned thereby.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. That there shall be granted to said company eight sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions of land of six hundred and forty acres each for every mile of railway actually completed by them and ready for use; and upon the application of the president of the company or any duly author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />izedagent thereof, stating that any section of five miles or more has been completed and ready for use, it shall be the duty of the Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller to give information of that fact to the Commissioner of the General Landoffice, whose duty it shall be to issue to said company land certificates to the amount of eight sections of land, of six hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and forty acres each, for each and every mile of railway thus completed and ready for use; such certificates shall be for six hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and forty acres each, and shall be located upon any unappro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated public domain of the State of Texas within twelve <pb n="1409" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="55" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>months from the issuing thereof, which date shall appear on the face of each certificate; and upon the return of the fieldnotes of any survey made by virtue of any certificate thus issued, it shall be the duty of the Commissioner of the General Landoffice to is<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sue patents to said company in their corporate name, one-fourth of which said lands thus patented shall be alienated by the compa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ny in six years, one-fourth in eight years, one-fourth in ten years and one-fourth in twelve years, so that the whole of the land thus granted shall pass from the hands of the company within twelve years from the date of the patents.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. That said company shall be required to have a good and sufficient brake upon the hindmost car in all trains transporting passengers and merchandise, and also permanently stationed there a trusty and skilful brakeman, under a penalty not exceeding one hundred dollars for each offense, to be recovered in any court of competent jurisdiction, for the benefit of the State; and said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany shall cause to be placed on each locomotive engine passing on their road, a bell of the weight of at least thirty-five pounds, or a steam-whistle, and the said bell shall be rung, or whistle blown, at the distance of at least eighty rods from the place of crossing any highway or turnpike, and kept ringing or blowing until the engine has passed or stopped. Said company shall be required to con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struct their railroad with good T or U iron rails; Provided, that no land shall be donated unless the company shall actually commence their road within four years, and actually complete and finish at least ten miles within five years.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. That the first meeting of the commissioners or direc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors appointed by this act, shall be held in the town of Marshall, Harrison county, on the first Monday in August, 1853, in which and all subsequent meetings which may be held, at such times and places as the directors may think best, said directors or com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners may act in person or by proxy.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. That nothing in this act shall be construed so as to con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fer banking privileges or powers of any kind whatever.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. That if said railway shall not be commenced within five years from the passage of this act, and at least twenty miles thereof completed within six years, then this charter shall be null and void; and it is hereby provided and declared, that it shall be lawful for any other railway hereafter to be constructed, to cross the said railway or any branch thereof, or to connect at any point therewith.</p>
<pb n="1410" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="56" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 20. That the said company shall have the right to take and hold so much of the public land, not exceeding two hundred feet wide, as the said railway or any of its branches may pass through, for the track thereof, and such additional width as may be absolutely necessessary for any depot or other work for the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose of said railroad, that the company may deem proper to estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lish; and in all cases where such railroad or any branch shall pass through any public lands, all such lands, to the depth of three miles from the extension line of the track on each side thereof, shall be reserved for the State from and after the time such track shall be fixed or designated by survey, recognition or otherwise; and the said lands, as the road is constructed, shall be divided into sections fronting one mile each on the road, plainly marked, and of these reserved lands the company shall have, by virtue of any of the certificates issued in accordance with the provisions of this act to cause to be located, surveyed, and patented for their use, each alternate section, such section, in each instance, embracing a tract of land fronting one mile, pursuing an equal width, and the remaining sections shall continue the property of the State until disposed of by the Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 21. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Galveston, Houston and Henderson Railroad Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That William C. Lacy, T. P. Anderson, R. A. Harris and William M. Tuck, and their associates and successors, be, and they are hereby created and established a body corporate and politic, under the name of the Galveston, Houston and Henderson Railroad Company, with capacity in said corporate name to make contracts, to have succession and a common seal, to make bye-laws for the government and regulation of the said company, to sue and be sued, to plead and be impleaded, to grant and receive and generally to do and perform all such acts as may be necessary and proper for, or incident to the ful<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />filment of its obligations, for the maintenance of its rights un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1411" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="57" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>der this act, and in accordance with the constitution of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said company be, and is hereby invested with the rights of locating, contracting, owning and maintaining a railway, commencing at the city of Galveston, crossing Galveston bay so as not to obstruct or unreasonably impede the navigation of the same, and thence running by such course and such point at the city of Houston as said company shall deem most suitable; thence by the most suitable and direct line to Henderson, in Rusk county, and with the further privilege of making, owning and maintaining such branches of said railway as they may deem most expedient.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the parties named in this act, or a majority of them, with such persons as they may associate with themselves for this purpose, are hereby appointed commissioners, and invested with the right of forming and organizing said company, and of exercis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the powers of directors until directors are chosen, when the powers of the commissioners shall cease.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the capital stock of said company shall be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, each share entiting the owner thereof to one vote, in person or by proxy, at all meetings of the company, and the shares shall be deemed personal estate, and shall be transferable by any conveyance in writing, recorded either by the Treasurer, in books kept by him for that purpose at his office, or by any other officer duly authorized by the directors, in books kept by him at such other place as the directors may appoint, such transfers as are recorded in any other place, being within ninety days communicated to the Treasurer, and by him entered on his books.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The immediate control and direction of the affairs of the company, shall be vested in a board of not less than five directors. Said directors shall elect one of their own number to he President of the company; the first hoard of directors shall be chosen by the persons named in this act, and such persons as they may associate with themselves for that purpose; said election shall be held in the city of Galveston, and at such times as the persons named in this act. or a majority of them with their associates shall have determin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed. No person shall be eligible to the office of director unless he be a subscriber or owner of at least three shares of the capital stock; the directors shall have power to fill any vacancy in their body, arising from non-election or other cause; they shall have power to appoint a clerk, treasurer, or any other officers or agents as they may deem necessary, and prescribe and require bonds for the faithful perfor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1412" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="58" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>mance of their duties; they may make all necessary rules and reg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ulations for the holding of meetings, and all other things they may deem proper for the carrying out the provisions of this charter, and business of the company; they shall keep, or cause to be kept, correct records of all meetings of the directors and company, and aceuratebooks and accounts of the receipts and expenditures of the company, and all other books and accounts necessary and proper to be kept by such company; which hooks shall be open to the inspec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the stockholders; a majority of the board of directors shall have the power of a full board, and all conveyances and contracts executed in writing, signed by the president and countersigned by the treasurer, or any other officer duly authorized by the direc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors, under seal of the Company, and in pursuance of a vote of the directors, shall be valid and binding.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the directors shall have power to dispose of the shares in said capital stock, in such manner and on such, terms as they may deem best for the interest of the company, and any agreement in writing,whereby any person shall become a subscriber to the capital stock of said company, may be enforced against him according to its terms. If any subscriber shall fail to pay any amount due upon shares subscribed for by him, according to the terms, of his subscription, the directors may, after twenty days public notice, sell at public auction the shares subscribed for by said delinquent, and transfer to the purchaser such shares; if the proceeds of sale shall not be sufficient to pay the amount due, with interest and charges, such delinquent shall be held liable to the company for the deficit, and if the proceeds shall exceed the amount so due with interest and charges, he shall he entitled to the surplus.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. It shall be lawful for the company to purchase and hold any land that may be necessary for the purpose of locating, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structing and maintaining said railway, with all necessary depots and other buildings, and by their engineers or agents, enter upon and take possession of all such lands as may be necessary for the locating, constructing and maintaining said railway, and if they shall not be able to obtain such lands by agreement with the owner, they shall pay for the same such amount as shall be determined in the manner provided for in the following section; the land so aken for the railroad shall not exceed fifty yards in width, and for depots and buildings only such further width as may be necessary.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That any person from whom lands have been taken for the purposes set forth in the preceding section, may apply <pb n="1413" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="59" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>to the District Court of the county wherein said lands are situat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed, for the appointment of appraisers, and said Court, after proof that the President or other officer of the company has been served with a notice describing the land, ten days before the holding of the Court, the Court shall thereupon appoint three disinterested free<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holders, citizens of the county, who shall appoint a time and place to hear the application, and the company, to whose agent or Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent a reasonable notice shall be given by the Court of said time and place, and said freeholders being sworn, shall after hearing the parties, determine the amount of compensation as aforesaid, and make return of their award to said Court at its next term, and said award may be confirmed, or for any sufficient reason, rejected by said Court, in the same manner as awards by arbitra<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors under a rule of Court, and if confirmed by the Court, judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment shall be rendered thereon as in other cases. In determining the amount of compensation to be paid as aforesaid, said free<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holders shall be governed by the actual value of the land at the time it was taken, taking into consideration the benefit or injury done to other neighboring lands of the owner, by the establishment of said railway; if in any case the amount found by the arbitra<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors shall not exceed the sum proved to have been offered by the company to the owner prior to his application to the Court, the owner shall pay the costs of proceedings; otherwise, the company shall pay the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That said company may acquire by purchase, donation, or in payment of stock, such real estate as the directors shall think desirable for the purpose of aiding in the construction or mainten<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance of said road, and such real estate acquired by the company, may be alienated or mortgaged by a vote of the majority of the di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rectors, for the constructing or maintaining said railway; said alienation or mortgage shall be signed in the name of the Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent and countersigned by the Treasurer.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That the said company shall have power to borrow money on their bonds, or notes, at such rates as the directors deem expedient; Provided, however, that nothing in this act shall be construed to confer banking privileges of any kind.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That upon the written request of one-fourth of the stockholders, the President of the company shall call a special meeting of the directors, and upon the written demand of three<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fourths of the stockholders, the President shall remove any one, or the whole of the directors, and order a new election within thirty days, which directors so elected shall hold their offices until the time prescribed for the next regular election.</p>
<pb n="1414" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="60" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 12. That if said railway is not commenced within twelve months from the first day of March, 1853, and at least forty miles are not in running order within three years after its commence<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, then this charter shall be null and void.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That the company is hereby required at all reasonable times and for a reasonable compensation, to draw over their road the passengers, merchandize, and cars of any other railroad cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration, which has been or may hereafter be authorized by the legislature to enter with their railroad and connect with the rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road of this company; and if the respective companies shall be unable to agree upon the compensation aforesaid, it shall be the duty of the President of each company to select each one man as a commissioner, and the two commissioners so selected, shall choose a third in case of disagreement, neither of whom shall be a stockholder in either road, or interested therein, and they shall fix the rates, which shall not be changed for one year from the time of going into effect. The said commissioners shall also fix the stated periods at which said cars are to be drawn as aforesaid, having reference to the convenience and interests of said corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, and the public who shall be accommodated thereby; the right or power is specially conferred on this company to connect and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tract with any railroad company heretofore or hereafter chartered by this State, for the performance of like transport, and in ease of disagreement between companies, the same shall be referred and settled as aforesaid, to be binding for one year as aforesaid.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That this act of incorporation shall expire in ninety years unless it shall be renewed or extended.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. That this company shall be subject to the provisions of any general laws not inconsistent with the terms of its charter, which may be enacted by this State, regulating railroad companies.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. That this act shall take effect from its passage. [Approved, 7th February, 1853.]</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Bastrop Academy.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That S. W. Sims, Thomas B. J. Hill, A. W. Moore, C. K. Hall, James H. Gillespie, Josiah W. Whipple and Thomas C. Moore and their successors in office be, and they are hereby <pb n="1415" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="61" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>constituted a board of Trustees of the Academy heretofore erected and established in the town of Bastrop, in the county of Bastrop, which is by this act incorporated, by the name of &#8220;Bastrop Aca<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />demy,&#8221; by which name it may sue and be sued, plead and be im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleaded, and buy and sell property, real, personal and mixed, and hold the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the lot of ground situated in the town of Bastrop, known as the south west lot, in farm lot No. 2, west of main street, which is particularly described in a deed of conveyance drawn in favor of Samuel W. Sims, Samuel B. Morris, Thomas B. J. Hill, Josiah W. Whipple, Constance K. Hall, Charles L. McGehee and Abraham W. Hill, as Trustees for the Bastrop Educational Asso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciation, bearing date the tenth day of December, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and fifty-one, executed by John D. Hogan and Hortentia G. Hogan, being the same ground upon which the Academy buildings have been erected, together with the said Academy buildings and all books, apparatus and every species of property of the Bastrop Educational Association, and of the Bastrop Educational Society, and of Bastrop Academy, is hereby placed, and shall be hereafter under the control and di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rection of the before named Trustees and their successors in office, who shall hold the same as Trustees, in trust for the Texas An<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nual Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church South.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That each of the individuals before named as Trustees shall hold their office until the first Monday of February next, (1854,) and at the next session of the Texas Annual Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church South, the said Trustees shall be divided by said conference into three classes, the term of the first class shall expire on the first Monday in February, 1854; and that of the second class, on the first Monday in February, 1855; and that of the third class on the first Monday in February 1856; provided, that any Trustee shall be eligible to re-election; and pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided further, that any Trustee may be removed by the Texas An<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nual Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church South, for abusing his trust or for neglect of duty.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That it shall be the duty of the Texas Annual Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ference of the Methodist Episcopal Church South, at each of its sessions hereafter, to elect such number of Trustees as may be necessary to fill all vacancies which may have occured in said board or which may occur by the expiration of the term of any of its members, before the next session of said annual <pb n="1416" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="62" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>conference; provided, that every Trustee who shall hereafter be elected (except such as may be elected to fill vacancies occasioned by the death, resignation or removal of any member of the board) shall enter upon the duties of his office on the first Monday in Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary next, after his election, and shall continue in office three years, and when such Trustee shall be elected to fill a vacancy occasioned by the death, resignation or removal of a member of said board, he shall hold his office until the term of his predecessor would have expired.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the said hoard of Trustees shall elect one of their own number chairman of the board. They shall also elect one Treasurer and one Secretary. The chairman shall preside atremeetings of said board, but in his absence a chairman pro tem. may he appointed by said board. The Treasurer shall he elected for one year, he shall keep a fair record of all moneys, notes and papers of value received and paid out by him, paying out the same by order of the hoard of Trustees, signed by the President of the board; he may at any time be removed for a dereliction of duty, by a two-third vote of the hoard of Trustees. The Secretary shall be elected for three years, he shall attend the meetings of the board of Trustees, and shall keep a fair record of all its of proceedings and resolutions, and also of such by-laws and regulations as may he passed by said board for the government of the school.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. No money shall be paid out of the Treasury of the Aca<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />demy except by the order of the board of Trustees, signed by the chairman of the board. The said board shall have power to employ one President and as many Professors and Teachers in theAcademy as the educational interests of the school may require, and they shall assign to all persons so employed their duties respectively, and fix their salaries. They shall have power to appropriate any money in the Treasury to the payment of the salary of any nerson employed in the school; and it shall be their duty to appoint an agent to at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tend to the collection of tuition fees and of all monies due to the academy. The said board shall have power to enact such by<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />laws as they may deem necessary for the government of the Academy; provided, the same be not in contravention to the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution or laws of this State. The said board of Trustees shall have power, by a two-third vote of its members, to sell and dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose of any property of the said Academy, (except the ground and buildings, books and apparatus, occupied and used by the school,) which the said conference may direct; provided, that the proceeds of all such sales shall be applied to advance the <pb n="1417" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="63" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>educational interests of the Academy. It shall be the duty of said board of Trustees to submit perfect reports of all their pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceedings and of the financial condition of the academy to the Tex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />as Annual Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church South, at each of its sessions.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the said board shall, by and with the advice and consent of the said annual conference, have power to erect and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pair all necessary buildings and improvements upon the ground belonging to the said academy, and to purchase such books and apparatus as they may deem necessary for its use.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That the faculty of &#8220;Bastrop Academy&#8221; shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sist of the President, Professors and Teachers; the faculty shall have power to enforce all laws adopted by the board of Trustees for the government of the school, by such measures as may be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sidered reasonable, and shall have power to suspend any student who may knowingly violate the laws, which suspension shall last until the board of Trustees can be convened, who conjointly with the faculty shall have power to continue or remit the suspen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion; they shall also have power to expel disorderlv students, but no student shall be suspended or expelled who has not knowingly violated some law of the board of Trustees.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That the board of Trustees, conjointly with the faculty, shall have power to confer such degrees in the arts and sciences upon any student of Bastrop Academy, or person thought worthy, as are usually conferred by other academies and institutions of similar grade, and to grant certificates thereof, signed by the fac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ulty and Trustees, and sealed with the seal of said academy, to authenticate and perpetuate their acts.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That &#8220;Bastrop Academy&#8221; shall be competent to receive and hold contributions, gifts, donations and bequests of real estate, and of property of every kind, and all donations and bequests to said Academy shall be good and binding, although the corporate name of said Academy may not have been properly stat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed by the person making such donation or bequest; provided, how<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever, that said Academy shall not hold property beyond the value of two hundred thousand dollars, (the Academy buildings and lot of ground on which they stand, excepted.)</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That four members of the board of Trustees shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, the said board may have and use a seal to authenticate and perpetuate all certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cates of scholarship.</p>
<pb n="1418" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="64" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 12. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Aet to incorporate the Virginia Point and Austin Railroad</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Samuel W. Sims, Pleasant H. Jones, A. W. Moore, E. M. Smith and Thomas G. Moore, and their associates and suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessors be and they are hereby created and established a body cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate and politic, under the name and style of &#8220;The Virginia Point and Austin Railroad Company,&#8221; with capacity in said corporate name to make contracts; to have succession and a common seal; to make by-laws for its government and the regulation of its af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fairs; to sue and be sued; to plead and be impleaded; to grant and receive, and generally to do and perform all such acts and things as may be necessary or proper for, or incident to the fulfilment of its obligations or the maintenance of its rights under this act and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sistent with the constitution of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said company be, and is hereby invested with the right of locating, constructing, owning and maintaining a railway, commencing at Virginia point on Galveston Bay, or at any suit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able place within five miles of Virginia Point, and thence running as near a direct route as may be thought advisable by said company, to the city of Austin in the county of Travis, with the privilege of making, owning and maintaining such branches of said railway as they may deem expedient.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the parties named in this act, or a majority of them, with such persons as they may associate with themselves for this purpose, are hereby appointed Commissioners and invested with the right of forming and organizing said company, and gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erally of exercising the powers of Directors, until Directors are chosen, when the powers of the Commissioners shall cease.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the capital stock of said company shall not exceed fifteen hundred thousand dollars. The amount to be determined by the Commissioners or Directors and by them divided into shares, of such equal per value as they shall think <pb n="1419" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="65" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>fit, each share entitling the owner thereof to one vote in person or by proxy at all meetings of the company, and the shares shall be deemed personal estate, and shall be transferable by any convey<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance in writing, recorded either by the Treasurer of the company, in books to be kept by him at his office for that purpose, or by any officer duly authorized by the Directors, in books kept by him at such other place as the Directors may appoint, such transfers as may be recorded in such other place being within thirty days com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />municated to the Treasurer, and by him entered into his books.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the immediate direction and government of the af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fairs of the company shall be vested in a hoard of not less than five Directors; said Directors shall elect one of their own body to be President of the company. The first Directors shall be chosen by said Commissioners, and such persons as they may associate with themselves for the purpose, and at such time and place as they shall appoint, and they shall hold their offices until others are duly elected in their places by the members of the company. No person shall be eligible as Director unless a subscriber or owner of at least five shares of the capital stock. The Directors shall have power to fill any vacancy in their board, arising from non-election, death, resignation or other cause; to appoint a Clerk, Treasurer and such other officers and agents as they may consider necessary, and pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribe and require bonds for the faithful performance of their du<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties. They may, if the same is not fixed by the by-laws, determine the manner of calling and conducting all meetings; the number of members that shall constitute a quorum, and do or cause to be done all other lawful matters or things they may deem necessary or proper in conducting the business of the company; they shall keep or cause to be kept accurate books of accounts of the receipts and expeditures of the company. A majority of the board of Directors shall have the power of a full board, and all conveyances and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tracts in writing executed by the President and countersigned by the Treasurer, or any other officer duly authorized by the Directors under the seal of the company, and in pursuance of a vote of the Directors, shall be valid and binding.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the shares in said capital stock may be disposed of by the Directors in such manner and on such terms as they shall think best for the interest of the company; and any agreement in writing whereby any person may become a sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scriber to the capital stock, may be enforced against him according to its terms; and if any subscriber shall fail to pay <pb n="1420" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="66" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>any amount due upon shares subscribed for by him according to the terms of his subscription, the Directors may sell at auction and transfer to the purchaser the shares of such delinquent, and if the proceeds of sale shall not be sufficient to pay the amount so due, with interest and charges, such delinquent shall be held liable to the company for the deficiency, and if the proceeds shall exceed the amount so due, with interests and charges, he shall be entitled to the surplus.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That it shall be lawful for the company to enter upon and purchase, or otherwise take and hold any land necessary for the purpose of locating, constructing and maintaining said rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />way, with all necessary depots and other business, and if they shall not be able to obtain such lands by agreement with the owners thereof, they shall pay such compensation as shall be determined in the manner provided for in the following section: the land so taken for the road bed shall not exceed fifty yards in width, and for depots and buildings only such further width as shall be nec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />essary.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That any person when land has been taken as aforesaid, may apply to the District Court of the county where the land is situated, for the appointment of, and said court shall thereupon appoint three disinterested free-holders of the county who shall appoint a time and place to hear the applicant and the company, to whom shall be given reasonable notice by the court of said time and place, and said free-holders shall, after being sworn, and after hearing the parties, determine the amount of compensation as aforesaid, and make return of their award to said court at its next regular term, and said award may be confirmed, or for any suffic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ient reason rejected by said court, in the same manner as awards of arbitrators, under a rule of court, and if confirmed by the court, judgment shall be rendered thereon as in other cases. In deter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mining the amount of compensation to be paid as aforesaid, said free-holders shall be governed by the actual value of the land at the time it was taken, taking into consideration the benefit or injury done to other neighboring lands of the owner, by the establish<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of said railway. If in any case the amount found by the ar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bitrators shall not exceed the amount proven to have been offered by said company to the owner prior to his application to the court, the owner shall pay the cost of the proceedings, otherwise the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany shall pay the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That said company shall have the right to charge such amount for transportation of all produce, merchandize and bulky freight as the Directors may establish, not to exceed one <pb n="1421" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="67" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>half one cent on each and every hundred pounds of freight for every mile the same may be transported over said railway, and for all passengers over said railway said company may charge such sum not to exceed five cents per mile for each passenger, as said Di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rectors may establish. And said company shall have the right to cross all public highways that may be necessary in establishing and maintaining said railway, but shall be compelled to make causeways over all public highways so crossed for the convenient passage of the public.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That said company shall commence the construction of said railway within one year from the passage of this act, and com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plete the construction of the same to the city of Austin within five years from the passage of this act, and should said company fail to commence said railway within one year from the passage hereof, they shall forfeit and loose all rights under this act; and in the event said company shall fail to complete the final construc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of said railway within said time of five years, said company shall forfeit all right to such portion of said Railway as may not be so completed.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That said company shall be entitled to have and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive all the rights and privileges not herein specially named, which is or may be granted or conceded to other railroad com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />panies.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. This company is hereby required at all reasonable times and for a reasonable compensation, to draw over their road the passengers, merchandize and cars of any other railroad corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration which has been or may hereafter be authorized by the Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature, to enter with their railroad and connect with the railroad of this company, and if the respective companies shall be unable to agree upon the compensation aforesaid, it shall be the duty of the President of each company to select each one naan as a Commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />er, and the two Commissioners so elected shall choose a third in case of disagreement, neither of whom shall be a stockholder in either road, or interested therein, and they shall fix the rates, which shall not be changed for one year from the time of going into effect; the said Commissioners shall also fix the stated periods at which said cars are to be drawn as aforesaid, having reference to the convenience and interests of said corporation and the public who will he accomodated thereby; the right or power is specially con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred on this said company to connect and contract with any railroad company chartered by this State for the performance of like transportation, and in case of disagreement between <pb n="1422" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="68" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>said companies, the same shall be referred and settled as afore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />said, and he binding for one year as aforesaid.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Brownsville and Rio Grande Railroad Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Patrick C. Shannon, Charles Stillman, J. R. Thompson, H. N. Caldwell, William Evans, Jno. E. Gary, Wm. P. Converse, A. J. Walker, Jno. P. Shannon, Daniel Wolf, Samuel A. Belden, E. Delmas and J. R. Butler, their associate and successors be, and are hereby created and established a body corporate and politic, under the name and title of The Brownsville and Rio Grande Railroad Company, with the capacity in said corporate name to make contracts, to have succession and a common seal, to make by-laws for its government and the regulation of its af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fairs, to sue and be sued, to plead and be impleaded, to grant and receive, and generally to do and perform all such acts and things<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />as may be necessary or proper, for or incident to the fulfilment of its obligations or the maintenance of its rights under this act, and consistent with the Constitution of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said company be, and is hereby invested with the right to locate, construct, own and maintain a railway, commenc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing at a suitable point on the Laguna Madra, Brazos Santiago, Brazos or Clark&#8217;s Islands, and thence running by such course and to such points on the Rio Grande, and up and down said river, and by the way of the Sal del Rey as said company shall deem and determine to be most suitable, with the right of making, owning and maintaining such branches of said railway as they may deem expedient.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the parties named in this act are hereby appointed comissioners, and invested with the right of forming and organiz<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing said company, and generally of exercising the powers of di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rectors until directors are chosen or appointed by such persons as may subscribe to the stock of said company, when the powers of said commissioners shall cease.</p>
<p>Sec. 4 That the capital stock of said company, to consist <pb n="1423" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="69" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>of all its property real and personal, franchises and rights to prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty, shall be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, each share entitling the owner thereof to one vote, by himself or proxy, at all meetings of said company; that said shares shall be deemed personal estate, and shall be transferable by any conveyance in writing, recorded by the treasurer in books kept by him at his of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fice, or in such manner as the by-laws of said company shall pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vide.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the immediate government and direction of the affairs of said company shall be vested in a board of not less than six directors, who shall elect one of their own number president of said company. No person shall be eligible to the office of direc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tor, unless an owner or subscriber of at least five shares of the stock of said company; the directors shall have the power to fill any vacancy that may occur in said board from non-election, death or otherwise, and may appoint a secretary, treasurer and such other officers and agents as they may consider necessary, and prescribe and require bonds for the faithful performance of their duties; they may, if not otherwise provided by the by-laws, determine the manner of conducting all meetings, the number of members that shall constitute a quorum, and to do or cause to be done all other lawful matters and things which they may deem necessary and proper in conducting the matters of the company; they shall keep or cause to be kept, accurate records of all meetings of the directors and company, and accurate books of the accounts of the receipts and expenditures of the company, and all other books necessary and proper to be kept by such company, which shall be open to the inspection of the stockholders; a majority of the board of directors shall have the authority of a full board, and all conveyances and contracts in writing, executed by the president and countersigned by the secretary or any other officer or person authorized by the di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rectors, under the seal of the company, and in pursuance of a vote of said directors, shall be valid and binding.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the shares may be disposed of and books opened for subscription thereto, in such manner and on such terms as said commissioners shall determine will be best for the interest of said company; and any agreement in writing by which any person shall become a subscriber to the capital stock of said company, may be enforced against him according to its terms; and if any subscriber shall fail to pay any amount due upon shares subscribed by him according to the terms of his subscription, the directors may sell at auction and transfer <pb n="1424" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="70" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>to the purchaser the shares of such delinquent, and if the proceeds of the sale shall not he sufficient to pay the amount due on said subscription, with interest and charges, such delinquent shall be held liable to the company for the deficiency; and if the proceeds shall exceed the amount so due, with interest and charges, said de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />linquent shall be entitled to the surplus.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That it shall be lawful for the company to enter upon and purchase, or otherwise take and hold any land necessary for the purpose of constructing and establishing said railway, with all necessary depots and other buildings; and if they shall not be able to obtain said lands by the agreement with the owner thereof, they shall pay therefor such compensation as shall be determined in the manner provided by the following section; provided, that the land so taken for the road bed shall not exceed two hundred feet in width, and for depots and other buildings only such further width as shall be needed for such purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That any person, where land has been taken as afore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />said without agreement or satisfactory compensation, may apply to the District Court of the county in which said land is situated, for the appointment of, and said court shall thereupon appoint three disinterested freeholders of the county, who shall appoint a time and place to hear the applicant and the company, to whom shall be given by said freeholders a reasonable notice of said time and place, and said freeholders shall, after being sworn, and after due hearing of the parties, determine the amount of compensation, if any, to which the applicant may be entitled, and make return of their award to the next succeeding court; and said award, if not rejected by said Court for sufficient cause then shown, shall be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tered up as the judgment of said Court. In determining the ques<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of compensation, said freeholders shall be governed by the actual value of said land at the time it was taken, taking into con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sideration the benefit or injury done to the other lands and proper<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty of the owner by the establishment of said railway, and if the amount of compensation awarded by said freeholders shall not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed the amount offered by Said company to the owner, prior to said application to the Court, the applicant shall pay the costs of the proceedings, otherwise the company shall pay the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That it shall be the duty of said company, when<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever any State or county road now by law established shall be crossed by the track of said railway, to make and keep in re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pair good and sufficient causeways at such crossings; and in <pb n="1425" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="71" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>all cases where any person shall own lands on both sides of said rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />way, and there shall be no other access convenient from one part to the other, such owner shall have the right of passage free of costs, at all reasonable times, across the track of said railway.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. This company is hereby required, at all reasonable times and for a reasonable compensation, to draw over their road the passengers, merchandize and cars of any other railroad corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration which has been or may hereafter be authorized by the legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature, to enter with their railroad and connect with the railroad of this company; and if the respective companies shall be unable to agree upon the compensation aforesaid, it shall be the duty of the president of each company to select each one man as a commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />er, and the two commissioners so selected shall choose a third,in case of disagreement, neither of whom shall be a stockholder in either road or interested therein, and they shall fix the rates, which shall not be changed for one year from the time of going into effect; the said commissioners shall also fix the stated periods at which said cars are to be drawn as aforesaid, having reference to the conven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ience and interests of said corporations and the public, who will be accommodated thereby. The right or power is specially conferred on this said company to connect and contract with any railroad company chartered by this State, for the performance of like trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />port, and in case of disagreement between said companies, the same shall be referred and settled as aforesaid, and be binding for one vear as aforesaid.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That said company may acquire real estate by gift or purchase, and that such commissioners hereinbefore mentioned shall have full authority to solicit and receive subscriptions and conveyances of land to said company until the time fixed for the first meeting of said commissioners, which authority may be then extended by said meeting, which said land so obtained shall be alienated by said company in the following manner: one-fourth in six years, the one-fourth in eight years, one-fourth in ten years, and the other fourth in twelve years from the same was acquired.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That if the track of this railway shall cross any navi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gable stream, it shall do it in such way as not to obstruct its navi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gation.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That said company shall have the right to demand and receive such rates and prices for the transportation of pas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sengers and freight as they may think proper to establish, not to exceed five cents per mile for passengers, and fifty cents per <pb n="1426" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="72" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>hundred pounds for freight for every hundred miles the same may be carried.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That if any person shall wilfully injure or obstruct said railway or its property, such person may be punished when prosecuted by indictment for said offense in due course of law, and also liable to action by said company or any person whatever who may suffer in person or property from said wilful obstruction, for the amount of damages occasioned thereby.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. There shall be granted to said company eight sections of land of six hundred and forty acres each, for every mile of rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />way actually completed by them and ready for use; and upon the application of the president of the company, or any duly author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized agent thereof, stating that any section of five miles or more of said railway has been completed and is ready for use, it shall be the duty of the Comptroller of Public Accounts to require the State engineer, or a commissioner to be appointed by the Governor, to examine said railway, and upon his certificate that said section of said railway has been completed in a good and substantial man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner, and is ready for use, the Comptroller shall give information of that fact to the Commissioner of the General Landoffice, whose duty it shall be to issue to said company land certificates to the amount of eight sections of land, of six hundred and forty acres each, for each and every mile of railway thus completed and ready for use; such certificates shall be for six hundred and forty acres each, and shall be located upon any unappropriated public domain of the State of Texas, within twelve months from the issuing thereof, which date shall appear upon the face of each certificate; and upon the return of field-notes of any survey made by virtue of any certificate thus issued, it shall be the duty of the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner of the General Land office to issue patents to said company in their corporate name, one-fourth of which said lands patented shall be alienated by the company in six years, one-fourth in eight years, one-fourth in ten years, and the other fourth in twelve years, so that the whole of the lands thus granted shall pass from the hands of the company within twelve years from the date of the patents thus issued.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. Said company shall he required to have a good and sufficient brake upon the hindmost car in all trains trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porting passengers or merchandize, and also permanently sta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned there a trusty and skilful brakeman, under a penalty of not exceeding the sum of one hundred dollars for each offence, to be recovered in any court of competent jurisdiction, for the benefit of the State; and said company shall cause to be placed <pb n="1427" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="73" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>on each locomotive engine passing over their road, a bell of the weight of thirty-five pounds, or a steam whistle, and the said bell shall be rung or the whistle blown, at the distance of at least eighty rods from the place of crossing any highway or turnpike, and keep ringing or blowing until the engine has passed or stopped. Said company shall be required to construct their railroad with good T or U iron rails; provided, that no land shall be donated unless the company shall actually commence their road within three years, and actually complete and finish at least ten miles within four years; and provided, also, that the alternate sections belong<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing to the State, named in this section, shall not be subject to entry or location, but shall be sold under such laws as may hereafter be passed, and the money paid into the State Treasury.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. The first meeting of the commissioners or directors appointed by this act, shall be held at Brownsville, on the first Monday in June next, in which and all subsequent meetings said directors may act in person or by proxy.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. That nothing in this act shall be so construed as to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />confer banking privileges or powers of any kind whatever.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. That if said railway shall not be commenced within five years from the passage of this act, and at least twenty miles thereof are not completed within six years, then this charter shall be null and void. And it is hereby provided and declared that it shall be lawful for any other railway hereafter to be constructed, to cross the said railway or any branch thereof, or to connect at any point therewith.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Colorado Valley Railroad Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That John Duncan, William L. Sartevell, John C. Perry and their associates and successors be, and are hereby created a body corporate and politic, under the name and style of the &#8220;Colorado Valley Railway company,&#8221; with the capacity in said corporate name to mate contracts; to have succession and a common seal; to make by-laws for its govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, and the regulation of its affairs; to sue and be sued; to plead and be impleaded; to grant and receive, and generally <pb n="1428" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="74" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>to do and perform all such acts and things as may be necessary or proper for, or incident to the fulfilment of its obligations, or the maintenance of its rights under this act, and consistent with the Constitution of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said company be, and is hereby invested with the right to locate, construct, own and maintain a railway, commenc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing at any suitable point to be selected by a majority vote of the stockholders, on the bay of Matagorda or Trespalacios Bay, be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween the half moon reef and Carancuaha Bay, thence running by such course as may be deemed most suitable, to the city of Austin, or to such intermediate point on the Colorado river as may hereafter be determined by said company, with the right of ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tending said railroad to the town of Fredericksburg, and of mak<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing and owning such branches of said railroad as they may deem ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pedient.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The parties named in this act are hereby appointed Commissioners, and invested with the right of forming and organ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />izing said company, and generally to exercise the powers of Di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rectors until Directors are chosen or appointed by such persons who may subscribe to the stock of said company, when the powers of said Commissioners shall cease.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The capital stock of said company, to consist of all its property, real and personal, franchises and rights to property, shall be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, each share enti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tling the owner thereof to one vote by himself or proxy, at all meet<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings of said company. That said shares shall be deemed personal estate, and shall be transferable by any conveyance in writing, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corded by the Treasurer in books kept by him at his office, or in such other manner as the by-laws of said company shall provide.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The immediate government and direction of the af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fairs of said company, shall be vested in a board of not less than ten Directors, who shall elect one of their own number as Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent of said company; no person shall be eligible to the office of Director unless an owner or subscriber of at least five shares of the stock of said company; the Directors shall have the power to fill any vacancy that may occur in said board from non-election, death or otherwise, and may appoint a Secretary, Treasurer and such other officers and agents as they may consider necessary, and pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribe and require bonds for the faithful performance of their du<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties; they may, if not otherwise provided by the by-laws, determine the manner of conducting all meetings, the number of members that shall constitute a quorum, and to do, or cause to be done, all other <pb n="1429" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="75" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>lawful matters or things which they may deem necessary and proper, in conducting the matters of the company; they shall keep or cause to be kept, accurate records of all meetings of the Direc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors and company, and accurate books of accounts of the receipts and expenditures of the company, and all other books necessary and proper to be kept by such company, which shall be open to the inspection of the stockholders. A majority of the board of Direct<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ors shall have the authority of a full board, and all conveyances and contracts in writing, executed by the President and countersigned by the Secretary, or any other officer or person authorized by the Directors, under the seal of the company and in pursuance of a vote of said Directors, shall be valid and binding.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The shares may be disposed of and books opened for subscription thereto, in such manner or on such terms as said Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners shall determine will be best for the interests of said company, and any agreement in writing by which any person shall become a subscriber to the capital stock of said company, may be enforced against him according to its terms, and if any subscriber shall fail to pay any amount due upon shares subscribed by him according to the terms of his subscription, the Directors may sell at auction, and transfer to the purchaser the shares of such delin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quent, and if the proceeds of sale shall not be sufficient to pay the amount due on said subscription, with interest and charges, such delinquent shall be held liable to the company for the deficiency, and if the proceeds shall exceed the amount so due with in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terest and charges, said delinquent shall be entitled to the surplus.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. It shall be lawful for the company to enter upon and purchase, or otherwise take and hold, any land necessary for the purpose of establishing and constructing said railway, with all necessary depots and other buildings, and if they shall not be able to obtain such lands by agreement with the owners thereof, they shall pay therefor such compensation as shall be determined in the manner provided by the following section: provided, that the land so taken for the road bed shall not exceed two hundred feet in width, and for depots and other buildings only such fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ther width as shall be needed for such purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. And any person, when land has been taken as afore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />said, without agreement or satisfactory compensation, may apply to the District Court of the county in which said land is situ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated for the appointment of, and said court shall thereupon appoint three disinterested tree-holders of the county, who shall <pb n="1430" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="76" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>appoint a time and place to hear the applicant and the company, to whom shall be given by said free-holders reasonable notice of said time and place, and said free-holders shall, after being sworn and after due hearing of the parties, determine the amount of compensation, if any, to which the applicant may be entitled, and make return of their award to the next succeeding term of said court, and said award, if not rejected by said court, for sufficient cause then shown, shall be entered up as the judgment of said court. In determining the question of compensation, said free-holders shall be governed by the actual value of the land at the time it was taken, taking into consideration the benefit or injury done to the other lands and property of the owner by the establishment of said railway, and if the amount of compensation awarded by said free<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holders shall not exceed the amount offered by said company to the owner, prior to said application to the court, the applicant shall pay the costs of the proceedings, otherwise the company shall pay the same.</p>
<p>Sec 9. It shall be the duty of said company, whenever any State or county road, now by law established, shall be crossed by the track of said railway, to make and keep in repair good and suffic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ient causeways, at such crossings, and in all cases where any per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son shall own lands on both sides of said railway, and there shall be no other sufficient access from one part to the other, such owner shall have the right of passage free of cost at all reasonable times, across the track of said railway.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. This company is hereby required at all reasonable times, and for a reasonable compensation, to draw over their road the passengers, merchandize and cars of any other railroad corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration which has been or may hereafter be authoried by the Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature, to enter with their railroad and connect with the railroad of this company, and if the respective companies shall be unable to agree upon the compensation aforesaid, it shall be the duty of the President of each company to select each one man, as a Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner, and the two Commissioners so selected shall choose a third, in case of disagreement, neither of whom shall be a stockholder in either road, or interested therein, and they shall fix the rates, which shall not be changed for one year from the time of going into effect; the said Commissioners shall also fix the stated periods at which said cars are to be drawn as aforesaid, haying reference to the convenience and interests of said corporations and the public who will be accomodated thereby. The right or power is <pb n="1431" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="77" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>specially conferred on the said company to connect and contract with any railroad company chartered by this State, for the per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formance of like transport, and in case of disagreement between said companies, the same shall be referred and settled as aforesaid, and be binding for one year as aforesaid.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. Said company may acquire real estate by gift or pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chase, and that such Commissioners hereinbefore mentioned shall have full authority to solicit and receive subscriptions and convey<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ances of land to said company, until the time fixed for the first meeting of said Commissioners, which authority may be then ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tended by said meeting, which said land thus obtained shall be alienated by said company in the following manner: one-fourth in six years, the one-fourth in eight years, the one-fourth in ten years, and the other fourth in twelve years from the time the same was acquired.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. If the track of this railway shall cross any navigable stream, it shall do it in such way as not to obstruct its navigation.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. Said company shall have the right to demand and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive such rates and prices for the transportation of passengers and freight as they may think proper to establish, not to exceed five cents per mile for passengers, and fifty cents per hundred pounds for freight, for every hundred miles the same may be carried.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. If any person shall wilfully injure or obstruct said rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />way or its property, such person may be punished when prosecuted by indictment for said offence in due course of law, and also liable te action by said company, or any person whatever who may suffer in person or property from said wilful obstruction, for the amount of damages occasioned thereby.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. There shall be granted to said company eight sections of land, of six hundred and forty acres each, for every mile of rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />way actually completed by them and ready for use, and upon the application of the President of the company or any duly authorized agent thereof, stating that any section of five miles or more of said railway has been completed and is ready for use, it shall be the duty of the Comptroller of Public Accounts to require the State Engineer, or a Commissioner to be appointed by the Governor, to examine said railway at the expense of said company, and upon his certificate that said section of said railway has been completed in a good and substantial manner and is ready for use, the Comptroller shall give information of that fact to the Commissioner of the General Landoffice, <pb n="1432" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="78" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>whose duty it shall be to issue to said company land certificates to the amount of eight sections of land of six hundred and forty acres each, for each and every mile of railway thus completed and ready for use, such certificates shall be for six hundred and forty acres each, and shall be located upon any unappropriated public do<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />main of the State of Texas, within twelve months from the issuing thereof, which date shall appear upon the face of each certificate, and upon the return of the field notes of any survey, made by virtue of any certificate thus issued, it shall be the duty of the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner of the General Landoffice to issue patents to said company in their corporate name, one-fourth of which said land thus patented shall be alienated by the company in six years, one-fourth in eight years, one-fourth in ten years and the other fourth in twelve years, so that the whole of the land thus granted shall pass from the hands of the company within twelve years from the date of the pat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ents thus issued.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. Said company shall be required to have a good and suf<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficient brake upon the hindmost car, in all trains transporting passengers or merchandize and also permanently stationed there a trus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty and skillful brakeman, under a penalty not exceeding the sum of one hundred dollars for each offence, to be recovered in any court of competent jurisdiction, for the benefit of the State; said company shall cause to be placed on each locomotive engine passing over their road, a bell of the weight of at least thirty-five pounds, or a steam whistle, and the said bell shall be rung or the whistle blown at the distance of at least eighty rods from the place of cros<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sing any highway or turnpike, and kept ringing or blowing until the engine has passed or stopped; said company shall be required to eonsriuct their railroad with good T or U iron rails; provided, that no land shall be donated unless the company shall actually commence their road within two years, and construct twenty-five miles every year thereafter, until the road be entirely finished.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. The first meeting of the Commissioners or Directors appointed by this act, shall be held at Columns on the first Monday in August next, in which and all subsequent meetings said Direc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors may act in person or by proxy.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. Nothing in this act shall be so construed as to confer banking privileges or powers of any kind whatever.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. If said railway shall not be commenced within five years from the pasage of this act, and at least twenty miles thereof are not completed within ten years, then this charter shall be null and void; and it is hereby provided and <pb n="1433" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="79" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>declared, that it shall be lawful fox any other railway hereafter to be constructed to cross the said railway or any branch thereof, or to connect at any point therewith.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. This charter shall in no event, unless renewed by the Legislature, continue for a longer term than ninety years from the passage of this act, but the same shall expire and cease to exist at the expiration of that term. This act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Memphis and El Paso and Pacific Rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That James Bourland, William C. Young, A. M. Alexander, Geo. W. Wright, G. W. Barnett, G. A. Foote, Martin D. Hart, Jno. G. Chambers, Howell W. Runnels, Jno. Holford, Edward Sweat, Eldridge Hopkins, M. T. Johnson, and such other persons as they may associate with them for the purposes, and their successors be, and they are hereby constituted and created a body corporate and politic, under the name and style of the &#8220;Memphis and El Paso and Pacific Railroad Company,&#8221; with the capacity in said corporate name to make contracts, to have succession and a common seal; to make by-laws for its government and the regulation of its affairs, to sue and be sued, to plead and be impleaded, to grant and receive, and generally to do and perform all such acts and things as may be proper or necessary for the fulfillment of its contracts and obli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gations, and for the maintenance of its rights under this act, and consistent with the constitution and laws of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Said company is hereby invested with the right to locate, to construct, own and maintain a railway, commencing on Red River, at a suitable point opposite the terminus on that stream of the Memphis and Arkansas road, or at a point near the white oak shoals, as said company may choose, and thence running in a westwardly direction up the valley of the Red River, crossing the extreme source of the headwaters of the Trinity river; thence on to the main or salt fork of the Brazos river, crossing the same at or near the United States post, &#8220;Fort Belknap;&#8221; thence to the Rio Grande, striking the same <pb n="1434" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="80" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>at or near El Paso, said road running such course and to such points as said company shall deem and determine to be most suit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ale, with the right of making, owning and maintaining such branches of said railway as they may deem expedient.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Said James Bourland and William C. Young and their associates, are hereby appointed Commissioners, and invested with the right of forming and organizing said company, and generally of exercising the powers of directors, until directors are chosen or appointed by such persons as may subscribe to the stock of said company, when the powers of said Commissioners shall cease.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The capital stock of said company, to consist of all its property, real and personal, franchises and rights to property, shall be divided into shares of fifty dollars each, one share entitling the owner thereof to one vote by himself or proxy, at all meetings of said company; said shares shall be deemed personal estate, and shall be transferable by any conveyance in writing, recorded by the Treasurer in books kept by him at his office, or in such other man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner as the by-laws of said company shall provide.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The immediate government and direction of the affairs of said company shall be vested in a board of not less than six di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rectors, who shall elect one of their own members as President of said company. No person shall be eligible to the office of director, unless an owner of at least ten shares of the stock of said company. The directors shall have the power to fill any vacancy that may oc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cur in said board from non-election, death or otherwise, and may appoint a Secretary, Treasurer and such other officers and Agents as they may consider necessary, and prescribe and require bonds for the faithful performance of their duties; they may, if not other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise provided by the laws, determine the manner of conducting all meetings, the number of members that shall constitute a quorum, and to do or cause to be done all things Which they may deem ne$$cessary and proper in the management of, and conducting the mat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ters of said company. They shall keep or cause to be kept an accu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rate record of all meetings of the directors and company, and correct books of all accounts of the receipts and expenditures of the company, and all other books necessary and proper to be kept by said company, which shall be open at all times to the inspection of the stockholders; a majority of the board of directors shall have the authority of a full board, and all conveyances and contracts in writ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing executed by the President and countersigned by the Secretary, <pb n="1435" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="81" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>or any other person or officer authorized by the directors under the seal of the Company, and in pursuance of a vote of said direc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors, shall be valid and binding.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The shares may be disposed of, and books opened for subscription thereto, in such manner and on such terms as said Commissioners shall determine will be best for the interests of said company, and any agreemnt in writing by which any person shall become a subscriber to the capital stock of said company, may be enforced against him acocrding to its terms, and if any per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son fail to pay the amount due by him to said company, for shares in said stock according to the terms of his subscription, the direc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors may sell at auction, and transfer to the purchaser the shares of such delinquent, and if the proceeds of the sale shall not be suf<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficient to pay the amount due on said subscription with interest and charges, such delinquent shall be held liable to the company for the deficiency, and if the proceeds of any such sale should ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed the amount so due, with interest and charges, said delinquent shall be entitled to the surplus.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. It shall be lawful for the company to enter upon and purchase or otherwise take, and hold any land necessary for the purpose of establishing and constructing said railway, with all ne<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessary depots and other buildings, and if they shall not be able to obtain said lands by agreement with the owner thereof, they shall pay therefor such compensation as shall be determined in the man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner provided by the following; provided, that the land so taken for the road bed, shall not exceed two hundred feet in width, and for depots and other buildings, such further width as shall be need<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed for such purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That any person, when land has been taken as aforesaid, without agreement or satisfactory compensation, may apply to the District Court of the county in which said land is situated, for the appointment of and said court shall thereupon appoint three dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />interested free-holders of the county, who shall appoint a time and place to hear the applicant and the company, to whom shall be given by said free-holders reasonable notice of said time and place, and said free-holders shall, after being sworn, and after due hearing of the parties, determine the amount of compensation, if any, to which the applicant may be entitled, and make a return of their award to the next succeding term of said court, and said award, if not rejected by said court for sufficient cause then shown, shall be entered up as the judgment of said court. In deter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mining the question of compensation, said free-holders shall be <pb n="1436" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="82" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>governed by the actual value of the land at the time it was taken, taking into consideration the benefit or injury done to the other lands and property of the owner, by the establishment of said rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />way, and if the amount of compensation awarded by said free<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holders shall not exceed the amount offered by said company to the owner prior to said application to the court, the applicant shall pay the costs of the proceedings, otherwise the company shall pay the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. It shall be the duty of said company, whenever any State or county road now by law established, or may hereafter be established, shall be crossed by the track of said railway, to make and keep in repair good and sufficient causeways at such crossings, and in all cases where any person shall own lands on both sides of said railway, and there shall be no other convenient access from one part to the other, such ower shall have the right, free of cost, at all reasonable times to cross the track of said railway.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. This company is hereby required at all reasonable times, and for a reasonable compensation, to draw over their road the passengers, merchandise and cars of any other railroad corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion which has been or may hereafter be granted by the Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture, to enter with their railroad and connect with the railroad of this company, and if the respective companies shall be unable to agree upon the compensation aforesaid, it shall be the duty of the President of each company to select each one man as a Commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />er, and the two Commissioners shall choose a third in case of dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />agreement, neither of whom shall be stockholders in either road, or interested therein, and they shall fix the rates, which shall not be changed for one year from the time of going into effect. The said Commissioners shall also fix the stated periods at which cars are to be drawn as aforesaid, having reference to the convenience and interest of said corporations and the public who will be accommo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dated thereby. The right or power shall be specially conferred on said company to connect and contract with any railroad com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany chartered by this State for the performance of like transport, and in case of disagreement between said companies, the same shall be referred and settled as aforesaid, and be binding for one year as before contemplated.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That said company may acquire real estate by gift or purchase,, and such Commissioners hereinbefore mentioned shall have full authority to solicit and receive subscriptions and conveyances of land to said company, until the time fixed for the first meeting by said Commissioners, which authority <pb n="1437" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="83" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>may be then extended by said meeting; which said land so obtain<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed by said company shall be alienated by them in the following manner: one-fourth in six years, one-fourth in eight years, one<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fourth in ten years, and one fourth in twelve years from the time the same was acquired by said company.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. If said railroad track should cross any navigable stream, it shall be in such manenr as not to obstruct the navigation of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. Said company shall have the right to demand and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive such rates of prices for transportation of freight and passen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gers as they may think proper to establish, not to exceed five cents per mile for passengers, and fifty cents for one hundred pounds of freight, for every one hundred miles the same may be carried.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. If any person shall wilfully obstruct or injure said rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />way or its property, such person or persons may be punished when prosecuted by indictment for such offences in due course of law, and shall be liable to action by said company, or any person what<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever, who may suffer in person or property from such wilful ob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struction, for the amount of damage occasioned thereby.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. There shall be granted to said company eight sections of land, of six hundred and forty acres each, for every mile of said railway completed by said company and ready for use, and upon ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plication by the President of said company or any duly authorized agent thereof, stating that any section of five miles of said road has been completed and ready for use, it shall be the duty of the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor of the State to require the State Engineer, or other Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner that may be appointed for that purpose, to examine said railway, and if found to be completed in a good and substantial manner and ready for use, such person so appointed shall give infor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mation of the fact to the Commissioner of the General Landoffice, whose duty it shall be to issue to said company land certificates, to the amount of eight sections of land of six hundred and forty acres each, for every mile of road completed by said company and reported by the Engineer or person appointed for that purpose, as being built in a good and sufficient manner; after the first five miles, said company shall receive eight sections of land of six hundred and forty acres each, to be located upon any vacant and unappropriated lands belonging to the State, within twelve months from the time such certificates have been issued, and upon return of field-notes of surveys made by virtue of any such certificates so issued, it shall be the duty of the <pb n="1438" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="84" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Commissioner of the General Land office to issue patents to said company in their corporate name, one fourth of which land shall be alienated by said company within six years, and one-fourth with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />in eight years, and one-fourth within ten years, and one-fourth within twelve years, so that all lands thus acquired by said compa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ny shall pass out of their hands within twelve years from date of the patents thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. Said company shall be required to have a good and sufficient brake upon the hindmost car, in all trains carrying pas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sengers or freight, and also permanently stationed there, a trusty and skilful brakeman, under a penalty not exceeding one hundred dollars for each offence, to be recovered in any court of competent jurisdiction for the benefit of the State, and on each locomotive en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gine passing over said road shall be placed a bell of the weight of at least thirty-five pounds, or a steam whistle, and the said bell shall be rung or the whistle blown at the distance of at least eighty rods from the place of crossing any highway or turnpike, and kept ringing or blowing until the engine has passed or stoned, and said company shall construct their road of the best T or U iron rails; provided, no lands shall be granted by the State unless the road be commenced in three years, and twenty-five miles of the road actual<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ly completed within three years after the granting this charter.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. The first meeting of the Commissioners or Directors appointed by this act, shall be held in the town of Paris on the first Monday in May next, in which, as well as all after meetings, said Directors may act in person or by proxy.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. Nothing in this act shall be so construed as to confer banking privileges of any kind whatever.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. If this company shall not commence the construction of the road within two years from the passage of this act, and com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plete twenty-five miles thereof, from year to year for every year thereafter, until the same shall be entirly completed, this act shall be null and void.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. That should the State Legislature at any time adopt a general system of Internal Improvements by which other priv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ileges than such as are enumerated by this charter, shall be grant<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed to railroad companies, then in that case &#8220;the Memphis and El Paso and Pacific railroad company,&#8221; shall be entitled to all such privileges and immunities and be subject to such general laws as may hereafter be enacted regulating railroad companies.</p>
<p>Sec. 21. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1439" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="85" />
<pb n="1440" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="86" /><fw type="header" place="top">Certificate.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">STATE OE TEXAS.</head>
<p>I, THOMAS H. DUVAL, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, certify that the second session of the fourth legislature of said State commenced its session at the City of Austin, on Monday, the tenth day of January, in the year one thousand eight hundred and fifty-three, and adjourned on Monday, the seventh day of Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary in the year one thousand eight hundred and fifty-three.</p>
<p>And I further certify, that the Acts and Joint Resolutions con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained in this Volume are true copies, taken from the original rolls deposited in the Department of State, with which they have been carefully compared.</p>
<p>Given under my hand and Official Seal, at the City <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[Seal.]</p></body></floatingText>of Austin, the seventeenth day of March, in the year one thousand eight hundred and fifty-three.</p>
<closer>
<signed>THOMAS H. DUVAL.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1441" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="i" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX TO SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">A</head>
<p>Page.</p>
<p>Andrew Female College incor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porated..................... <ref>18</ref></p>
<p>Andrews David, heirs of, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lief of..................... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Anthony Mary, alias Collins Mary, relief of............... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Austin Norman, heirs of, relief of.......................... <ref>37</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">B</head>
<p>Bastrop Academy, incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rated.................. <ref>60</ref></p>
<p>Bailey Peter J., heirs of, relief of........................ <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Bayless Joseph, heirs of, relief of.................... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Bays Joseph, relief of........ <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Benson T., heirs of, relief of.......... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Berry Llizabeth, widow of Wm. Landrum, relief of.......... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Blackburn G. C., relief of.... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Bostick John H., relief of.... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Browning, G. W., relief of... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Brownsville, city of, incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rated................. <ref>32</ref></p>
<p>Brownsville and Rio Grande Railroad Company, incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rated................... <ref>68</ref></p>
<p>Buffalo Bayou, Brazos and Col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />orado Railway Company, act incorporating amended.. <ref>3</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">C</head>
<p>Cartwright Matthew, relief of, <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Chamberlain H. P., heirs of, relief of................. <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>Clark Marsraret, relief of.... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Cloud Daniel W., heirs of, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lief of.................. <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Cold Springs Female Acad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />emy, incomorated......... <ref>49</ref></p>
<p>Collins Mary, alias Anthony Mary, relief of............ <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Colorado Valley Railroad Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, incorporated........ <ref>73</ref></p>
<p>Conner John, Delaware chief, relief of............ <ref>48</ref></p>
<p>Coody Shadrack, heirs of, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lief of...................... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Corzine Herschell, heirs of, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lief of.................. <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Creath George, heirs of, relief of........................... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Crossland James, relief of.... <ref>37</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">D</head>
<p>Dailey Stacy, heirs of, relief of..................... <ref>42</ref></p>
<p>Davidson John T., relief of... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Dean Thomas, relief of........ <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Dorr Carl, relief of........... <ref>37</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">E</head>
<p>Egery Cyrus W., relief of.... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>English Robert, relief of..... <ref>37</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">F</head>
<p>Fisher Wesley, heirs of, relief of......... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Forbes William, relief of..... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Forsythe Lilly, or Lyla, heirs of, relief of............... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Friley Hiram, heirs of, relief of............................. <ref>37</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">G</head>
<p>Galveston and Red River Rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />way Company, supplement<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary to acts relating to.. <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>Galveston, Houston and Hen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />derson Railroad Company, incorporated.............. <ref>56</ref></p>
<p>Gilbert L., heirs of, relief of.. <ref>29</ref></p>
<p>Gorman Russell, relief of.... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Grace Silas M., relief of...... <ref>37</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H</head>
<p>Hall Richard, heirs of, relief of <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Hamilton Thomas, heirs of, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lief of..................... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Hardin H. K., his heirs or as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />signs, relief of.............. <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Hollingsworth Stephen P., and his associates, authorized to construct a bridge across the Sabine river............... <ref>26</ref></p>
<p>Hughs Butler, relief of....... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Hughs John, relief of........ <ref>37</ref></p>
</div3>
<pb n="1442" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="ii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">I</head>
<p>Indianola and Victoria Plank and Turnpike Road Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, incorporated....... <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Indianola, city of, incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rated................. <ref>43</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">J</head>
<p>Jackson Albert, heirs of, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lief of............... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Jones Andrew R., relief of............ <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Jones Thomas, Heirs or as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />signs, relief of......... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Joy George, relief of....... <ref>37</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">K</head>
<p>Kennedy William H., relief of, 37 Kimbro Newton, heirs or as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />signs, relief of........... <ref>37</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">L</head>
<p>Lararent Levin S., relief of... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>La Salle and El Paso Rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />way Company, supplement<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary to an act establishing the..................... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Lawler Eli W., relief of..... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Little Edward, heirs of, relief of.................... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Lyons Warren, relief of..... <ref>37</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">M</head>
<p>McCoy William, relief of..... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>McEarly Samuel, heirs of, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lief of............... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Manning James W., relief of, <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Marshall University, supple<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mentary to an act establish<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the, and changing the name thereof to that of Van Zandt College................ <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>Marshall Railroad Company, incorporated............. <ref>50</ref></p>
<p>Martinez Guadalupe, heirs of, relief of................... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>May Patrick, relief of........ <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Memphis and El Paso and Pa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cific Railroad Company, in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corporated.................. <ref>79</ref></p>
<p>Menchaca Antonio, relief of.. <ref>50</ref></p>
<p>Middleton William, heirs or assigns, relief of........... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Morrison Edward, relief of... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Morris James, relief of....... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Moore Francis Jr., relief of <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Mount Vernon, in Titus county, incorporated........... <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>Mount Enterprise Male and Fe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />male Academy, incorporated, <ref>28</ref></p>
<p>Mullens Isaac, relief of........ <ref>37</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">N</head>
<p>Norman John, heirs of, relief of................. <ref>37</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">P</head>
<p>Parker Daniel, relief of....... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Parrish George W., relief of.. <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Presidio de San Elizario, in El Paso county, the inhabit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ants of, relief of.......... <ref>8</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">R</head>
<p>Reid Walker, heirs of, relief of.................. <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Richmond, town of, incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rated.................... <ref>30</ref></p>
<p>Robertson Sterling C., E. S. C. Robertson, administrator of, relief of................... <ref>37</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S</head>
<p>Saint Paul&#8217;s College, incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rated and established.... <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>San Patricio, town of, in San Patricio county, incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rated.................. <ref>39</ref></p>
<p>Seguin, in Guadalupe county, incornorated......................... <ref>19</ref></p>
<p>Scott Antoinette, repealing the second section of an act changing the name of, to that of Devereux............ <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Shaw Jim, a Delaware Indian, relief of.................. <ref>42</ref></p>
<p>Sise John, relief of........ <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Slaughter Charles R., relief of..................... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Stryker John, relief of.................. <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Sullivan John C., heirs of, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lief of..................... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Swords Archibald, heirs of, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lief of...................... <ref>37</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">T</head>
<p>Texas Orphan Asylum, estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished.................... <ref>47</ref></p>
<p>Tippett Robert, relief of........ <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Trerinio Maria Jesusa, relief of......................... <ref>37</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">V</head>
<p>Vandevere Christopher, heirs or assigns, relief of........... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Vicksburg and El Paso Rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road Company, supplement<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary to an act incorporating, <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>Virginia Point and Austin railroad company, incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rated............. <ref>64</ref></p>
</div3>
<pb n="1443" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">W</head>
<p>Wallace James, heirs or as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />signs, relief of........ <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Walker Jackson J., relief of.. <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Way Sydney, repealing thesec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ond section of an act chang<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the name of, to that of</p>
<p>Devereux................ <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Weir Omy, relief of......... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>White John, relief of........ <ref>17</ref></p>
<p>Williams Samuel P., heirs of, relief of...................... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Willis, William R., relief of.. <ref>37</ref></p>
<pb n="1444" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iv" />
</div3>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
